<bill session="119" type="h" number="310" updated="2026-05-12T14:29:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Energy Market Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Energy Market Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal certain credits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2025-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-12T14:28:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Energy Market Freedom Act

This bill repeals multiple business tax credits related to the production and sale of energy.

Specifically, the bill repeals the

renewable electricity production tax credit (for electricity using wind, solar, or other specific types of renewable energy produced by a qualified facility for which construction began before 2025);clean electricity production tax credit (for electricity produced&#160;using a qualified facility that has no greenhouse gas emissions and was&#160;placed into service in 2025 or after);advanced nuclear production tax credit (for electricity produced and sold by a qualified nuclear power facility placed into service before 2021);zero-emission nuclear power production tax credit (for electricity produced and sold by a qualified nuclear power facility between 2024 and 2032);carbon sequestration tax credit (for the capture and sequestration of carbon oxide);clean hydrogen production tax credit (for clean hydrogen produced at a qualified clean production facility);advanced manufacturing production tax credit (for the production and sale of qualified&#160;components, including solar and wind energy components);energy investment tax credit (for investments in certain qualified energy property placed into service before 2025);clean electricity investment credit (for investments in qualified energy property placed into service in 2025 or after);qualifying advance coal project tax credit (for investments in qualifying advanced coal projects),clean coal investment tax credit (for investments in qualifying gasification projects);advanced energy project tax credit (for investments in qualifying advanced energy projects); andadvanced manufacturing investment tax credit (for investments in semiconductor or semiconductor manufacturing equipment).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
