<bill session="119" type="h" number="6329" updated="2026-02-25T16:03:49Z">
  <state datetime="2026-02-24T13:57:49-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-02-24T13:57:49-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Information Quality Assurance Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Information Quality Assurance Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that Federal agencies rely on the best reasonably available scientific, technical, demographic, economic, and statistical information and evidence to develop, issue or inform the public of the nature and bases of Federal agency rules and guidance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001231" joined="2026-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 43 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-23T16:26:21-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Timmons moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-23T16:26:42-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2245-2247" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2245-2246" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-23T16:26:43-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6329.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-23T16:33:57-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-24T13:31:51-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2276-2277" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="71" datetime="2026-02-24T13:57:49-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 362 - 1 (Roll no. 71).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 2/23/2026 H2245-2246" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-02-24T13:57:50-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-20T14:41:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Information Quality Assurance Act of 2025

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget to revise the guidelines for federal agencies with respect to the dissemination or use of influential information or evidence, which&#160;means information or evidence&#160;about which an agency can reasonably determine that reliance on or dissemination of has, or will have, a clear and&#160;substantial impact on important public actions, policies or statements, or on important private sector decisions.

The guidelines must ensure that federal agencies rely on the best reasonably available influential&#160;information and evidence that is appropriate for the purpose when developing, issuing, or informing the public about the rules and guidance of the agency.

An agency also must publish&#160;(1) the critical factual material relied on as part of the rulemaking or guidance development process, and (2) a citation to any other source used to inform the rulemaking or guidance development process.

The guidelines must also require an agency to provide certain opportunities for the public to comment on the critical factual material upon which the agency relied.</summary>
</bill>
