<bill session="119" type="s" number="926" updated="2026-06-12T13:40:20Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Saving Our Veterans Lives Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Our Veterans Lives Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a program to furnish to certain veterans items used for the secure storage of firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2026-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2025-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2025-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2026-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1987" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-12T13:38:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Saving Our Veterans Lives Act of 2025

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement a program to provide, upon request, a firearm lockbox (or voucher for such item) to eligible individuals. Currently, there is a pilot program under which certain veterans may be prescribed a lockbox by a VA clinician.

The VA must also provide information with respect to the benefits of and options for secure firearm storage.

The VA must develop an informational video on the secure storage of firearms as a suicide prevention strategy and publish the video on its website. Additionally, the VA must publish information to inform individuals who participate in the lockbox program that such lockboxes are not for resale. The VA must also implement a public education campaign to educate eligible individuals about the availability of lockboxes under the program and that participation in the program does not affect the rights of an individual with respect to the lawful ownership of a firearm.</summary>
</bill>
