<bill session="119" type="s" number="1420" updated="2026-03-17T14:32:46Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Care Nutrition Enhancement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Care Nutrition Enhancement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to increase the amount of reimbursements under the child and adult care food program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2025-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2859" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-17T14:30:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Child Care Nutrition Enhancement Act of 2025

This bill increases and modifies reimbursements for meals and snacks served under the Child and Adult Care Food Program (CACFP).

CACFP is a Food and Nutrition Service program that provides federal reimbursements for meals and snacks provided to eligible children and adults who are enrolled at participating child care centers, day care homes (i.e., private homes that provide nonresidential child care services), and adult day care centers.

Specifically, the bill eliminates the two-tiered system for&#160;CACFP reimbursement rates for day care homes and generally makes all day care homes eligible for the same reimbursement rates.&#160;Under current law, day care homes located in a low-income area or with a low-income provider receive higher reimbursement rates (i.e., Tier I rates). Day care homes that do not qualify for Tier I rates receive Tier II rates, which are lower.

Further, the bill provides an additional 10-cent reimbursement for each eligible meal and snack served in the CACFP.

The bill also allows the provider of a family or group day care home to serve reimbursable meals and snacks to their own children&#160;when serving meals and snacks to children in their care. Specifically, the bill eliminates the current requirement that the child of a day care home provider meet the program's income eligibility requirement in order for the day care provider to receive reimbursement for the meals and snacks served to their child.</summary>
</bill>
