<bill session="119" type="s" number="1516" updated="2026-03-24T12:48:03Z">
  <state datetime="2026-02-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the Cahokia Mounds, Emerald Mounds, and Pulcher Mounds in the State of Illinois, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2025-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2668" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-10T17:47:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture Study Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of an area made up of (1) Cahokia Mounds State Historic Site in Collinsville, IL; (2) the Emerald Mounds in St.&#160;Clair County, Illinois; and (3) the Pulcher Mounds in Monroe and St. Clair Counties, Illinois. (The National Park Service uses special resource studies when determining whether to designate sites as National Historical Sites.)

The study must

evaluate the national significance of the study area;determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the study area as a unit of the National Park System;consider other alternatives for preservation, protection, and interpretation of the study area by other governmental entities or nonprofit organizations; andidentify cost estimates for any federal acquisition, development, interpretation, operation, and maintenance associated with such alternatives.Interior must report on the results of the study and make recommendations to specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
