<bill session="119" type="h" number="1501" updated="2026-05-21T17:54:22Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Domestic Mining Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Domestic Mining Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the FAST Act to include certain mineral production activities as a covered project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001229"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000568" joined="2026-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001213" joined="2025-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 16.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-21T17:46:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Domestic Mining Act of 2025

This bill provides statutory authority for federal agencies to expedite the environmental review of certain mining infrastructure projects.

Specifically, the bill permanently makes certain mining infrastructure projects eligible for expedited environmental review under the Fixing America's Surface Transportation Act (FAST Act).&#160;This provides statutory authority for similar authorities that were included in&#160;the rule titled Adding Mining as a Sector of Projects Eligible for Coverage Under Title 41 of the Fixing America's Surface Transportation Act&#160;and issued by the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council (Permitting Council) on January 8, 2021.

The bill also prohibits the Permitting Council from finalizing its proposed rule titled&#160;Revising Scope of the Mining Sector of Projects That Are Eligible for Coverage Under Title 41 of the Fixing America&#8217;s Surface Transportation Act and issued on September 22, 2023. Among other modifications, the rule proposes to limit the types of mining projects that are eligible for the expedited environmental review process. Specifically, the proposed rule limits the expedited process to critical minerals mining projects.</summary>
</bill>
