<bill session="119" type="s" number="2614" updated="2026-06-03T20:54:29Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make improvements in the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2025-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2025-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4968" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-03T20:54:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act

This bill eliminates the cap on income subject to Social Security taxes and revises methods for calculating various aspects of Social Security benefits.

Under current law, Social Security has a taxable maximum, which refers to the maximum amount of a worker's earnings that are subject to Social Security payroll taxes (set at $176,100 in 2025). The taxable maximum also serves as the maximum amount of earnings used to calculate a worker's Social Security benefits.

This bill phases out the taxable maximum so as to apply payroll taxes to all earnings after 2031, and revises the method used to calculate a worker&#8217;s Social Security benefits to account for earnings in excess of the taxable maximum.

The bill also revises the method of calculating cost-of-living adjustments to Social Security benefits to reflect the spending habits of individuals over the age of 62. An increase in Social Security benefits resulting from this change may not be treated as income for purposes of determining eligibility for, or the amount of assistance provided under, the Medicaid or Supplemental Security Income programs.</summary>
</bill>
