<bill session="119" type="s" number="3398" updated="2026-03-10T11:03:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Sextortion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Sextortion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to criminalize intentional threats to distribute child sexual abuse material, and to provide appropriate penalties for the use of child sexual abuse material to extort or coerce victims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2026-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2026-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2026-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2026-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2026-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2026-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2026-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001244" joined="2025-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2025-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="6719" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-02T17:14:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Sextortion Act

This bill criminalizes threats to distribute child sexual abuse material to intimidate, coerce, extort, or cause substantial emotional distress. This practice is commonly referred to as sextortion. The bill also increases criminal penalties for related offenses that involve the use of child sexual abuse material to intimidate, coerce, extort, or cause substantial emotional distress.

Specifically, the bill establishes new federal criminal offenses for threatening to distribute child pornography or a visual depiction of a minor engaging in sexually explicit conduct with intent to intimidate, coerce, extort, or cause substantial emotional distress. An offense, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit the offense, is subject to criminal penalties.

Additionally, the bill increases the maximum prison term for various offenses involving the sexual exploitation of children if those offenses involve the use of child pornography or a visual depiction of a minor engaged in sexually explicit conduct with intent to intimidate, coerce, extort, or cause substantial emotional distress.</summary>
</bill>
