<bill session="119" type="s" number="1284" updated="2026-06-15T15:01:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Driving Forward Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Driving Forward Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permanently extend the exemption from the engine compartment portion of the pre-trip vehicle inspection skills testing requirement for school bus drivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2026-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001244" joined="2025-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2025-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2360" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-15T15:01:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Driving Forward Act

This bill directs the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to permanently allow states to exempt school bus drivers from the &#8220;under-the-hood&#8221; testing requirement for a commercial driver's license (CDL).

As background, on December 2, 2024, the&#160;FMCSA renewed an exemption through November 28, 2026, that allows states to exempt all school bus driver applicants for a CDL from the engine compartment portion of the pre-trip vehicle inspection skills testing requirement, commonly referred to as the under-the-hood testing requirement. States must meet certain terms and conditions for the exemption.

Under the bill, the FMCSA must make permanent the December 2, 2024, exemption, thus permanently allowing states to exempt school bus drivers from the under-the-hood testing requirement.&#160;States must meet the additional terms and conditions for an exemption, which include (1) restricting school bus drivers who are issued a CDL based on the exemption to the intrastate&#160;operation of school buses, and (2) requiring states to conduct the remaining pre-trip vehicle inspection components of the skills test.

Further,&#160;the FMCSA must require any state participating in the exemption to submit an annual report describing the number of drivers that obtain a CDL under the exemption.</summary>
</bill>
