<bill session="119" type="s" number="2063" updated="2026-04-06T16:23:49Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ESTUARIES Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Science, Treatment, and Upkeep of America&#8217;s Resilient and Important Estuarine Systems Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ESTUARIES Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to reauthorize the National Estuary Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3962" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-06T16:23:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhancing Science, Treatment, and Upkeep of America&#8217;s Resilient and Important Estuarine Systems Act of 2025 or the ESTUARIES Act&#160;of 2025

This bill reauthorizes through FY2031 grants provided under the National Estuary&#160;Program to protect and restore estuaries of national significance.&#160;Estuaries are coastal waterbodies where freshwater from rivers and streams mixes with the ocean&#8217;s saltwater. Under the existing program, the Environmental Protection Agency provides grants for (1) developing and implementing comprehensive conservation and management plans for estuaries of national significance, and (2) addressing issues that threaten the ecological and economic well-being of such estuaries. The existing program provides grants to states, regional water pollution control agencies and entities, state coastal zone management agencies, interstate agencies, other public or nonprofit private agencies, institutions, organizations, and individuals.</summary>
</bill>
