<bill session="119" type="h" number="365" updated="2026-04-27T15:45:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Territorial Tax Parity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Territorial Tax Parity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the residence and source rules to provide for economic recovery in the possessions of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000610"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-27T15:44:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Territorial Tax Equity Parity Act of 2025

This bill modifies the income sourcing rules related to taxation of income from U.S. territories.

Under the bill, income is U.S.-sourced income or effectively connected to a U.S. trade or business only if attributable to an office or fixed place of business in the United States. (Currently, income is sourced to a U.S. territory and, thus, may be excluded from the gross income of a bona fide resident of a U.S. territory in calculating U.S. federal income tax&#160;if it is not U.S.-sourced income or effectively connected with a U.S. trade or business.)

Further, the bill authorizes the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to limit the income tax payment to the Virgin Islands required to treat income from the sale of certain personal property as foreign-sourced income for federal tax purposes. (Currently, income from certain personal property sales from a fixed place of business in a U.S. territory by a U.S. resident may be U.S.-sourced income unless an income tax of at least&#160;10% is paid to&#160;the U.S. territory. The Internal Revenue Service (IRS) may limit the 10% tax payment requirement related to income from personal property sales in Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and Puerto Rico.)</summary>
</bill>
