<bill session="119" type="h" number="6956" updated="2026-02-21T04:53:23Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Barcode Automation for Revenue Collection to Organize Disbursement and Enhance Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BARCODE Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Barcode Automation for Revenue Collection to Organize Disbursement and Enhance Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">BARCODE Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="display">BARCODE Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require electronically prepared tax returns to include scannable code when submitted on paper, and to require the use of optical character recognition technology for paper documents received by the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2026-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 42 - 0.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="452" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-01-14T20:13:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Barcode Automation for Revenue Collection to Organize Disbursement and Enhance Efficiency Act or the BARCODE Efficiency Act

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to use barcodes, barcode scanning technology, and optical character recognition (or similar) technology to digitize certain federal tax return information and correspondence, unless the technology is&#160;slower or less reliable than other IRS processes (subject to conditions).&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires a scannable barcode on electronically-prepared federal tax returns that are printed and filed in paper format with the IRS. The bill also requires the IRS to use barcode scanning technology to convert data included on such returns into an electronic format.

Further, the bill requires the IRS to use optical character recognition (or similar) technology to transcribe federal tax returns and correspondence received by the IRS that are not prepared electronically and are received in paper format.

However, under the bill, the use of barcodes, barcode scanning technology, and optical character recognition (or similar) technology is not required if (1) such technology is slower or less reliable than manual transcription or any other IRS process, and (2) the IRS provides a report to Congress regarding the determination to not use such technology.</summary>
</bill>
