<bill session="119" type="s" number="2988" updated="2026-03-10T11:03:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VITAL Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Infrastructure and Transformation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VITAL Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to bolster upgrades and infrastructure for lasting development at the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2026-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-23T15:04:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans' Infrastructure and Transformation Act of 2025 or the VITAL Act of 2025

This bill addresses various policies and procedures related to Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) infrastructure and facilities, including those related to construction projects.

The bill modifies the VA&#8217;s authority to share health care resources, including by providing for a simplified agreement process to share physical space (e.g., a building or parking facility) or common services (e.g., electricity).

The bill also modifies the VA&#8217;s authority to lease its real property (enhanced-use leases). Specifically, the bill allows for the exchange of real property that is assessed to be of similar value and removes the cap on the length of an enhanced-use lease. The bill&#160;requires the VA to implement a seven-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of entering into enhanced-use leases for noncash consideration.

Among other elements, the bill also

authorizes the VA to use commercial codes and standards instead of or in addition to federal codes and standards in constructing or altering VA facilities,authorizes the VA to contract with private entities for comprehensive construction project management services,expands and extends the pilot program under which the VA may accept donations of real property and facilities,modifies the authority and responsibilities of the VA&#8217;s Director of Construction and Facilities Management, andrequires the VA to consolidate certain employees and functions relating to facilities and infrastructure as well as acquisition and procurement.</summary>
</bill>
