<bill session="119" type="h" number="4336" updated="2026-06-11T19:44:49Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CBP SPACE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CBP SPACE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to provide authority to adjust the rate of merchandise processing fees to offset the capital costs incurred by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2025-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2025-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2025-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2025-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000317" joined="2025-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2025-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2025-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-11T19:43:44Z" status="Introduced in House">CBP SPACE Act

This bill expands the&#160;authorities for adjusting the rate for merchandise processing fees and the requirements for using certain&#160;customs user fees. It also prohibits U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) from requiring sea ports of entry to provide or maintain certain facilities for CBP inspection services.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Department of the Treasury to adjust the ad valorem rate for merchandise processing and the related limits on the amount of the fees to offset&#160;CBP's capital costs&#160;for&#160;processing entries and releases of merchandise. (Currently, Treasury may only adjust the rate and limits&#160;to offset CBP's related salaries and expenses.) The bill also requires Treasury to use certain customs user fees to reimburse CBP for paying capital costs associated with passenger inspection services.

Additionally, the bill (1) prohibits CBP from requesting or requiring a sea port of entry to provide or maintain administrative, training, or recreational facilities at the port for purposes of facilitating CBP's inspection services; and (2) requires CBP to submit an annual report to appropriate congressional committees on the amount and use of proceeds from merchandise processing fees.</summary>
</bill>
