<bill session="119" type="s" number="416" updated="2026-03-24T12:48:03Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park Establishment Act Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park Establishment Act Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park Establishment Act to expand the boundary of the Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park in the State of Vermont, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2025-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="986" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-01-22T17:09:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park Establishment Act Amendments Act of 2025

This bill expands the boundaries of the Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park in Woodstock, Vermont, allows the National Park Service (NPS) to acquire land within the boundaries through a variety of means, and provides statutory authority for the National Park Service Stewardship Institute, which is a program of the park.

Specifically, the bill expands the boundary of the park to include the King Farm.&#160;

The bill also allows the&#160;NPS to acquire lands within the park by purchasing, transferring, or exchanging land in addition to the current authorization to acquire land by donation.

The acquired King Farm land must include&#160;rights of access between the acquired land and the park. The&#160;acquired King Farm land may be used for certain agricultural, forestry, conservation, and educational purposes.

The bill also outlines the purposes of the National Park Service Stewardship Institute.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
