<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1439</number>
    <updateDate>2026-03-18T17:23:22Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2026-03-18T17:23:22Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2025-04-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>119</congress>
    <legislationUrl>https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/senate-bill/1439</legislationUrl>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
        <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2025-04-10T17:44:33Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2025-04-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
            <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2025-04-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001113</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cortez Masto, Catherine [D-NV]</fullName>
        <firstName>Catherine</firstName>
        <lastName>Cortez Masto</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NV</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
        <updateDate>2025-05-20T13:16:31Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2025-04-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2026-03-18T17:20:56Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Home Loan Banks' Mission Activities Act</strong></p><p>This bill expands the Federal Home Loan Bank (FHLB) program that supports affordable housing, allows additional financial institutions to qualify for FHLB membership, and establishes compensation guidelines for FHLB executive officers. The 11 regional FHLBs serve as government-sponsored enterprises to support mortgage lending and related community investment through advances to member financial institutions.</p><p>First, each FHLB must increase the annual amount contributed to the affordable housing program or other community development programs.&nbsp;</p><p>The bill also allows small credit unions and community development financial institutions to&nbsp;(1) qualify for FHLB membership by meeting reduced requirements, and (2)&nbsp;use advances for purposes other than mortgages, such as for small business activities.</p><p>Finally, the compensation for&nbsp;FHLB executive officers must be reasonable and comparable to compensation for similar positions at similar institutions. In determining such compensation, the FHLB must consider the level of investment in affordable housing and community programs.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Federal Home Loan Banks' Mission Activities Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Federal Home Loan Banks' Mission Activities Act</title>
        <updateDate>2025-05-03T03:53:24Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Federal Home Loan Banks' Mission Activities Act</title>
        <updateDate>2025-05-03T03:53:21Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to reaffirm and improve the participation of members of the Federal Home Loan Bank System to meet the short- and long-term housing, including affordable housing, agricultural and small business lending, and community economic development financing needs of the communities they serve, including rural, urban, low-income, and Tribal communities, improve the ability of community development financial institutions and credit unions to meet community economic development financing needs for their communities, and aligning executive compensation to mission achievements, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2025-05-03T03:48:33Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2025-04-10T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-119s1439is/xml/BILLS-119s1439is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2025-04-10</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
