<bill session="119" type="sc" number="33" updated="2026-04-22T19:15:43Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2026 and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2027 through 2035.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2026 and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2027 through 2035.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Submitted in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Budget discharged pursuant to Section 300 of the Congressional Budget Act.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="376">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 376.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 52 - 46. Record Vote Number: 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4793"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2026-04-22T19:14:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This concurrent resolution establishes the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2026, sets forth budgetary levels for FY2027-FY2035, and provides reconciliation instructions for legislation that increases the deficit.&#160;

The resolution recommends levels and amounts for FY2026-FY2035 for

federal revenues,new budget authority,budget outlays,deficits,public debt,debt held by the public, andthe major functional categories of spending.It also recommends levels and amounts for Social Security and Postal Service discretionary administrative expenses for the purpose of budget enforcement in the Senate.

The resolution includes reconciliation instructions that direct the House Homeland Security Committee, the House Judiciary Committee, the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee, and the Senate Judiciary Committee to submit recommendations for legislation that will increase the deficit over FY2026-FY2035 by not more than $70 billion. Each committee must submit the recommendations to the House or Senate Budget Committee by May 15, 2026.&#160;

(Under current law, reconciliation bills are considered by Congress using expedited legislative procedures that prevent a filibuster and restrict amendments in the Senate.)

In addition, the resolution establishes reserve funds that allow certain adjustments to committee allocations and other budgetary levels to accommodate (1) reconciliation legislation, and (2) legislation that would not increase the deficit over FY2026-FY2035 and supports changes to immigration enforcement and border security policy undertaken by the President.

Finally, the resolution sets forth budget enforcement procedures that address issues such as&#160;budget points of order in the Senate and emergency spending requirements in the House.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
