<bill session="119" type="s" number="651" updated="2026-03-16T14:06:13Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unplug the Electric Vehicle Charging Stations Programs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unplug the Electric Vehicle Charging Stations Programs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal programs relating to funding for electric vehicle charging infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-02-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1513" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-16T14:01:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Unplug the Electric Vehicle Charging Stations Programs Act

This bill repeals grant programs that provide funding for electric vehicle charging infrastructure and alternative fueling infrastructure.

Specifically, the bill repeals the&#160;Charging and Fueling Infrastructure Grant Program under which the Department of Transportation provides grants for acquiring and installing publicly accessible electric vehicle charging infrastructure, hydrogen fueling infrastructure, propane fueling infrastructure, or natural gas fueling infrastructure that is directly related to the charging or fueling of a vehicle.

It also repeals the National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Formula Program under which the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) provides grants for deploying electric vehicle charging infrastructure and establishing a network to facilitate data collection, access, and reliability. In addition, the bill rescinds unobligated funds&#160;that were provided to the FHWA for the program and prohibits funds from being used to carry out the program.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
