<bill session="119" type="s" number="1125" updated="2026-06-02T16:49:04Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cultural Trade Promotion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cultural Trade Promotion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote exports by creative industries and occupations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-02T16:47:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cultural Trade Promotion Act

This bill expands certain trade activities by the Department of Commerce and its related trade agencies to promote goods and services from&#160;microenterprises, creative industries and occupations (e.g., businesses focused on arts or culture), and Native Hawaiian businesses.

Specifically, the bill expands the activities that must be carried out by the U.S. Commercial Service to include the promotion of U.S. goods and services that are exported by microentrepreneurs.

Additionally, the bill expands the activities that must be carried out by Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee to include in its annual strategic plan (1) recommendations to better assist microenterprises, and (2) a consideration of how to promote exports of goods and services from creative industries and occupations.

The bill authorizes Commerce to provide assistance to eligible entities (e.g., Native Hawaiian tribes and Native Hawaiian-owned businesses) for the development of foreign markets for authentic Native Hawaiian arts and crafts.&#160;

The bill also requires the International Trade Administration, the U.S. Commercial Service, and the U.S. Postal Service to consult and collaborate to connect&#160;microenterprises and small businesses to fast and reliable international shipping services.

The bill directs the U.S. Trade and Development Agency to place special emphasis on the creative industries and occupations sectors when promoting U.S. private sector participation in development projects in developing and middle-income countries.&#160;

Finally, Commerce must appoint a representative of creative industries and occupations to serve as a permanent member of the U.S. Travel and Tourism Advisory Board.</summary>
</bill>
