<bill session="119" type="h" number="2070" updated="2026-04-03T15:57:24Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Our Military Families&#8217; 2nd Amendment Rights Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Our Military Families&#8217; 2nd Amendment Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to provide that a member of the Armed Forces and the spouse of that member shall have the same rights regarding the receipt of firearms at the location of any duty station of the member.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2025-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000482" joined="2026-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001098" joined="2025-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="961" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-03T15:57:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Our Military Families' 2nd Amendment Rights Act

This bill broadens the scope of allowable firearms transactions involving active-duty service members and their spouses.

Specifically, the bill allows a licensed gun dealer, importer, or manufacturer to sell or ship a firearm or ammunition to the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces on active duty outside the United States. Current law already allows a licensed dealer, importer, or manufacturer to sell or ship a firearm or ammunition to a member of the Armed Forces on active duty outside the United States.

The bill also specifies that, for purposes of federal firearms laws, a member of the Armed Forces on active duty, or his or her spouse, is a resident of the state in which (1) the member or spouse maintains legal residence, (2) the permanent duty station of the member is located, and (3) the member maintains a home from which he or she commutes to the permanent duty station.</summary>
</bill>
