<bill session="119" type="h" number="6719" updated="2026-04-02T16:01:47Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-12T16:08:10-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-01-12T16:08:10-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Online Predators Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Combating Online Predators Act</title>
    <title type="short">Combating Online Predators Act</title>
    <title type="short">COP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">James T. Woods Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Stop Sextortion Act</title>
    <title type="display">James T. Woods Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit threats to a minor, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official">To prohibit threats to a minor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000602" joined="2026-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001228" joined="2026-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-12T15:55:10-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Lee (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-12T15:55:14-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H628-630" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-12T15:55:15-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6719.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-01-12T16:08:10-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H628" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-01-12T16:08:12-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-26">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-02">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="346">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 346.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3704" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3397" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3398" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3394" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-02T16:00:19Z" status="Reported to Senate">James T. Woods Act

This bill expands the federal framework for combating the online exploitation of children. Among its provisions, the bill establishes new criminal offenses, expands reporting requirements, and facilitates the prosecution and sentencing of offenders.&#160;&#160;

TITLE I&#8212;SAFE ACT

Sentencing Accountability For Exploitation Act or the SAFE Act

This title directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend its guidelines and policy statements applicable to federal criminal offenses involving the production, receipt, transport, shipment, or distribution of child sexual abuse material to (1) account for the actual and potential harm from the offense and changes since the last amendments with respect to the typical offense behavior and modern technologies, and (2) better reflect the spectrum of offender culpability.

TITLE II&#8212;ENDING COERCION OF CHILDREN AND HARM ONLINE

Ending Coercion of Children and Harm Online Act or the ECCHO Act

This title establishes a federal framework to combat the online coercion of minors to commit harm. The title creates new criminal offenses, expands reporting of instances involving the online coercion of minors, facilitates the prosecution of offenders, and expands protections for minors who testify in court.&#160;TITLE III&#8212;STOP SEXTORTION

Stop Sextortion Act

This title criminalizes threats to distribute child sexual abuse material to intimidate, coerce, extort, or cause substantial emotional distress. This practice is commonly referred to as sextortion. The title also increases criminal penalties for related offenses that involve the use of child sexual abuse material to intimidate, coerce, extort, or cause substantial emotional distress.</summary>
</bill>
