<bill session="119" type="h" number="1850" updated="2026-05-08T12:54:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CRUDE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuing Robust and Uninhibited Drilling and Exporting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CRUDE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To revise the authority provided to the President to impose export licensing requirements or other restrictions on the export of crude oil from the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000246" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2025-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-08T12:51:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Continuing Robust and Uninhibited Drilling and Exporting Act or the CRUDE Act

This bill limits the President's authority to restrict the export of crude oil from the United States.

Currently, the President may restrict the export of oil for up to a year if

the President declares a national emergency;the restrictions are sanctions or trade restrictions that apply to countries, persons, or organizations for national security reasons; orthe Department of Commerce, in consultation with the Department of Energy (DOE), finds and reports to the President that the export of U.S. crude oil has caused sustained material oil supply shortages or sustained oil prices significantly above world market levels that have caused or are likely to cause sustained material adverse employment effects.However, this bill only allows the President to impose such restrictions if

the President declares a national emergency based on findings&#160;that are jointly issued by Department of Defense, DOE, and Commerce and include the conclusions described above&#160;about oil supply shortages or increased oil prices; or&#160;the restrictions are sanctions or trade restrictions&#160;that apply to countries, persons, or organization for national security reasons.</summary>
</bill>
