<bill session="119" type="s" number="4062" updated="2026-04-13T13:11:13Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Next Generation 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to provide for further deployment and coordination of Next Generation 9-1-1, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2026-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2026-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="6505" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-13T13:09:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Next Generation 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 Act

This bill establishes a grant program to support implementation of next generation 9-1-1 (NG9-1-1) systems by state, territorial, and tribal governments and requires other related activities. NG9-1-1 means a secure, interoperable, Internet Protocol-based (IP-based) system for receiving 9-1-1 requests for emergency assistance. (IP-based 9-1-1 systems have capabilities that legacy telephone systems do not, including enhanced location-finding and the ability to receive text and multimedia messages.)

Under the bill, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) must provide grants to state, territorial, and tribal governments (and entities established by those governments) to support the implementation and maintenance of NG9-1-1 systems. Grant funds may also be used for public outreach on NG9-1-1, implementation of cybersecurity measures, and, subject to certain limits, training and administrative costs.

Entities applying for grants must submit a plan for NG9-1-1 coordination and implementation that ensures interoperability and reliability, incorporates cybersecurity tools, and meets other requirements related to technology and procurement. Applicants must also certify that they have established, or will establish within a specified time frame, a sustainable funding mechanism to support NG9-1-1 and effective cybersecurity resources.

The NTIA must advise applicants on the preparation of implementation plans and provide technical assistance to grant recipients.

Further, the NTIA must establish (1) an advisory board to provide recommendations with respect to the grant program and other topics related to NG9-1-1; and (2) a cybersecurity center to coordinate with state, local, and regional governments on the sharing of cybersecurity information related to NG9-1-1.</summary>
</bill>
