<bill session="119" type="s" number="369" updated="2026-05-15T12:45:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NO GOTION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NO GOTION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Official Giveaways Of Taxpayers&#8217; Income to Oppressive Nations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to deny certain green energy tax benefits to companies associated with foreign adversaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-15T12:43:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Official Giveaways Of Taxpayers&#8217; Income to Oppressive Nations Act or the NO GOTION Act

This bill prohibits certain entities associated with China, Cuba, Iran, North Korea, Russia, or the Maduro regime of Venezuela from claiming various energy-related federal tax incentives.

Specifically,&#160;certain energy-related federal tax incentives may not be claimed by

the government, a government instrumentality, or an agency of China, Cuba, Iran, North Korea, Russia, or&#160;the regime of Nicolas&#160;Maduro in Venezuela;any entity that is organized under the laws of or is headquartered in one of these countries; orany entity that is owned, controlled, directed, or influenced by&#160;or that has certain financial or contractual connections with any such government, government instrumentality, agency, or entity.Such entities may not claim the federal tax credits for

alternative fuel vehicle refueling property,second-generation&#160;biofuel,biodiesel fuel,sustainable aviation fuel,renewable electricity production,carbon sequestration,zero-emission nuclear power production,clean hydrogen production,clean commercial vehicles,advanced manufacturing production,clean electricity production,clean fuel production,investments in energy property,advanced energy projects,clean electricity investment,biodiesel mixtures,alternative fuel, andalternative fuel mixtures.Further, such entities are prohibited from claiming the federal tax deduction for energy efficient improvements to commercial buildings.

Finally, such entities are not entitled to a credit or refund of federal excise taxes paid&#160;on biodiesel, alternative fuel, or sustainable aviation fuel mixtures produced by the entities.</summary>
</bill>
