<bill session="119" type="h" number="8884" updated="2026-07-01T08:08:51Z">
  <state datetime="2026-05-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Removing Barriers to Work for Disabled Americans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Removing Barriers to Work for Disabled Americans Act</title>
    <title type="display">Removing Barriers to Work for Disabled Americans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to reauthorize demonstration authority for the disability insurance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2026-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 119-714.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-06-25" calendar="Union" number="620">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 620.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-30T09:16:41-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1398 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8800, H.R. 8595, H.R. 8884 and H. Res. 1383. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8800 and H.R. 8595 under a structured rule, and H.R. 8884 and H. Res. 1383 under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on each measure and one motion to recommit on H.R. 8800, H.R. 8595, and H.R. 8884.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1398" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-26T17:06:48Z" status="Reported to House">Removing Barriers to Work for Disabled Americans Act

This bill reauthorizes through 2031 the Social Security Administration&#8217;s (SSA&#8217;s) authority to carry out demonstration projects within the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) program. The bill also imposes requirements related to beneficiary income, project funding, and SSA reporting.

SSDI demonstration projects&#160;must be designed to promote attachment to the workforce&#160;and generally involve temporary changes to SSDI policies tested on a subset of beneficiaries. Participation in a demonstration project must be voluntary.&#160;SSA&#8217;s authority to carry out these projects expired on December 31, 2022.

Under the bill, SSA must ensure that an individual&#8217;s participation in a demonstration project does not reduce their total income. Further, the bill specifies that administrative expenses related to demonstration projects must be paid from funds appropriated for administration.

Finally, the bill requires SSA to report to Congress 120 days before initiating a demonstration project. This is an increase from 90 days under current law. This advance notification must include evaluation metrics for the relevant project.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-714</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
