<bill session="119" type="h" number="7567" updated="2026-05-13T15:26:25Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-30T11:14:59-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-04-30T11:14:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm, Food, and National Security Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">CFTC Whistleblower Office Account Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Farm, Food, and National Security Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="display">Farm, Food, and National Security Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2031, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000467"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 34 - 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Agriculture. H. Rept. 119-620.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-21" calendar="Union" number="537">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 537.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T08:12:07-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1224 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7567, H.R. 2616, S. Con. Res. 33, S. 1318 and H.R. 1346. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 7567 under a structured rule and H.R. 2616, S. Con. Res. 33, S. 1318, and H.R. 1346 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on H.R. 7567, H.R. 2616, and H.R. 1346, and one motion to commit on S. 1318.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T22:41:14-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1224.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3169-3290" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3176-3259" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T22:41:19-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7567, H.R. 2616, S. Con. Res. 33, S. 1318 and H.R. 1346. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 7567 under a structured rule and H.R. 2616, S. Con. Res. 33, S. 1318, and H.R. 1346 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on H.R. 7567, H.R. 2616, and H.R. 1346, and one motion to commit on S. 1318.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T22:41:33-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1224 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T22:41:34-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Michael K. Simpson to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T22:42:17-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 7567.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T23:41:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thompson (PA) amendment en bloc No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T23:51:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Baumgartner amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T23:59:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bentz amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:05:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bentz amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Brown demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:06:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:09:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carbajal amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:14:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hayes amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:17:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crawford amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:20:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crawford amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:24:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crawford amendment No. 8, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Thompson (PA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:25:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perez amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:35:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:39:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:44:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:50:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:58:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Grothman demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T00:59:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:04:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:11:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 22, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grothman demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:12:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Craig amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:15:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Latta amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:19:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Luna amendment No. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:30:18-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Luna amendment No. 28, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Luna demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:30:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:37:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 30.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:43:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 31.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:47:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore (WV) amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:58:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moore (WV) amendment No. 36, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Carbajal demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T01:59:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scholten amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:02:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scholten amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:06:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Scholten amendment No. 39, as modified, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Scholten demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:08:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moylan amendment No. 42.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:09:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scholten amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:12:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schrier amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:17:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Self amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:24:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Self amendment No. 47, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Self demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:25:27-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thompson (PA) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:25:44-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T02:25:56-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 7567 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T09:17:20-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3299-3311" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T09:17:56-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T09:19:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Spartz amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T09:30:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Spartz amendment No. 49, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Craig demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T09:31:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T09:42:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1224, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 51.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:00:32-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 7567.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:01:30-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:01:44-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gros as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:02:22-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Craig moved to recommit to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3310" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:02:37-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:08:33-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 211 - 214 (Roll no. 153).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="154" datetime="2026-04-30T11:14:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 200 (Roll no. 154).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:15:01-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:15:02-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 7567.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="6779" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5562" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2897" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1224" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="8472" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5866" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1246" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="598" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1230" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="387" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1713" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1213" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="517" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1576" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2811" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2268" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2307" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1648" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7426" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7264" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="6385" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3112" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5471" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4782" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1613" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4673" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1725" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3349" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3125" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7464" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="388" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="295" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4400" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2282" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="581" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="291" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1262" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1999" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3991" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7469" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4134" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2558" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4155" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2518" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2812" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2326" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5620" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1302" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7475" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5037" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1952" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2839" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1592" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="289" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural equipment and machinery"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Argentina"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Data collection, sharing, protection"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Farm Credit Administration"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Supply chain"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h209"/>
    <amendment number="h208"/>
    <amendment number="h207"/>
    <amendment number="h206"/>
    <amendment number="h205"/>
    <amendment number="h204"/>
    <amendment number="h203"/>
    <amendment number="h202"/>
    <amendment number="h201"/>
    <amendment number="h200"/>
    <amendment number="h199"/>
    <amendment number="h198"/>
    <amendment number="h197"/>
    <amendment number="h196"/>
    <amendment number="h195"/>
    <amendment number="h194"/>
    <amendment number="h193"/>
    <amendment number="h192"/>
    <amendment number="h191"/>
    <amendment number="h190"/>
    <amendment number="h189"/>
    <amendment number="h188"/>
    <amendment number="h187"/>
    <amendment number="h186"/>
    <amendment number="h185"/>
    <amendment number="h184"/>
    <amendment number="h183"/>
    <amendment number="h182"/>
    <amendment number="h181"/>
    <amendment number="h180"/>
    <amendment number="h179"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2026-03-03T15:47:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Farm, Food, and National Security Act of 2026

This bill (commonly known as the farm bill) reauthorizes through FY2031 and modifies Department of Agriculture programs that address

commodity support,conservation,trade and international food aid,nutrition assistance,farm credit,rural development,research and extension activities,forestry,energy,horticulture,crop insurance,livestock and other animals, andforeign investments in U.S. agricultural land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-620,Book 1</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-620,Book 2</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
