<bill session="119" type="s" number="3608" updated="2026-05-27T18:01:57Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trade Transparency Unit Strategy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Transparency Unit Strategy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a strategy for the expanded use of Trade Transparency Units.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001232"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="6988" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-27T18:00:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Trade Transparency Unit Strategy Act

This bill requires a strategy and report related to the expansion of trade transparency units. Trade transparency units examine trade anomalies and financial irregularities associated with trade-based money laundering, customs fraud, contraband smuggling, and tax evasion.

Specifically, the Department of Homeland Security must coordinate with the Departments of State, Commerce, and the Treasury to submit a strategy to Congress. This strategy must (1) expand information sharing between U.S. Customs and Border Protection, Homeland Security Investigations of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, appropriate elements of the Department of Commerce, the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network of the Department of the Treasury, and appropriate counterparts of foreign customs agencies through trade transparency units; and (2) improve&#160;intra-agency, interagency, and other multilateral information sharing with respect to these units.

The Government Accountability Office must submit a report to Congress that includes an assessment of the strategy.</summary>
</bill>
