<bill session="119" type="h" number="1328" updated="2026-05-01T16:19:26Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supply Chain Security and Growth Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supply Chain Security and Growth Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish the critical supply chains reshoring investment tax credit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001103" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000617" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-01T16:18:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Supply Chain Security and Growth Act of 2025

This bill establishes a tax credit for qualified investments made in certain facilities that are located in a U.S. possession and manufacture drugs, pharmaceuticals, semiconductors, or certain other items, subject to limitations. The bill also increases the deemed-paid foreign tax credit for taxes paid to a U.S. possession.

Specifically, under the bill, a taxpayer (other than a prohibited foreign entity) is allowed a tax credit for 40% of an investment in certain property that is

placed into service during the tax year;integral to the operation of a critical supply chain facility; andconstructed, reconstructed, or erected by the taxpayer, or property acquired for original used by the taxpayer.The bill defines critical supply chain facility as a facility that (1) manufactures active pharmaceutical ingredients, drugs, biologic products, medical countermeasures, medical diagnostic devices, semiconductors, semiconductor manufacturing equipment, aerospace equipment, or artificial nanomaterials; and (2) is located in Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands.

Under the bill, the tax credit is transferable and may be claimed as a direct cash payment (i.e., elective payment). (Limitations apply.)

Finally, the bill increases to 100% (from 80%) the deemed-paid foreign tax credit for income taxes paid or accrued by a controlled foreign corporation (CFC) to a U.S. possession. (Under current law, a U.S. shareholder of a CFC is allowed a tax credit for income taxes paid by a CFC on certain income attributable to the U.S. shareholder.)</summary>
</bill>
