<bill session="119" type="h" number="3685" updated="2026-03-16T18:07:52Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">JUST Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JUST Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Just USDA Standards and Transparency Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance civil rights accountability and enforcement in the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2025-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-16T18:05:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Just USDA Standards and Transparency Act of 2025 or the JUST Act of 2025

This bill increases Department of Agriculture (USDA) oversight and enforcement of civil rights-related violations and actions.

USDA must take appropriate corrective action regarding any USDA official or employee who engages in certain discriminatory actions, retaliatory actions, harassment, or civil rights violations (e.g., failure to provide appropriate information regarding relevant USDA programs and services).&#160;A corrective action (1) is any action that would enhance civil rights at USDA, including policy or programmatic changes; and (2) may include disciplinary actions (e.g., removal from federal service or a letter of reprimand).

The bill shifts the burden of proof from a farmer or rancher to USDA in an appeal to the USDA National Appeals Division. Specifically, USDA must prove by substantial evidence the validity of a USDA adverse decision.

Further, a farmer or rancher who fails to comply fully with the requirements to receive a loan may be eligible for equitable relief if the USDA determines the individual made a good faith effort to comply with the loan requirements.

The bill also

directs USDA to establish an Office of the Legal Advisor for Civil Rights and Office of the Civil Rights Ombudsperson;creates the required position of Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil Rights (currently an optional USDA&#160;position); andallows the Assistant Secretary to grant relief, without prior approval, to farmers or ranchers who file certain civil rights complaints, including complaints&#160;regarding direct farm ownership, operating, or emergency loans.</summary>
</bill>
