<bill session="119" type="h" number="3031" updated="2026-04-24T22:14:28Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gold Star and Surviving Spouse Career Services Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gold Star and Surviving Spouse Career Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain spouses eligible for services under the disabled veterans' outreach program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2025-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1204" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-24T22:14:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Gold Star and Surviving Spouse Career Services Act

This bill expands eligibility for the Disabled Veterans&#8217; Outreach Program to the spouses of certain veterans and members of the Armed Forces. Such program is administered by the Department of Labor and generally provides career and employment services to disabled veterans.

The bill expands eligibility for the program to spouses of

persons who died while members of the Armed Forces;persons who died of a service-connected disability;members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty who, for more than 90 days, are listed as missing in action, captured by a hostile force, or forcibly detained or interned in the line of duty by a foreign government power;persons who have a total permanent disability resulting from a service-connected disability; andpersons who died while an evaluated total disability was in existence.</summary>
</bill>
