<bill session="119" type="s" number="1388" updated="2026-06-10T20:32:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Rigorous Oversight Through Evaluation of Concerning Transactions Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the review by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States of greenfield and brownfield investments by foreign countries of concern.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2025-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-10T20:32:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Providing Rigorous Oversight Through Evaluation of Concerning Transactions Act of 2025 or the PROTECT Act of 2025

This bill requires the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) to review certain real estate investments made by a foreign country of concern&#160;in the United States. The bill defines&#160;foreign country of concern as China, North Korea, Russia, Iran, or any other country determined to be a country of concern by the Department of State.

Specifically, CFIUS must review any investment by a foreign person that (1) involves the acquisition of real estate in the United States and the establishment of a U.S. business on such real estate, and (2) could result in direct or indirect control of that U.S. business by a foreign country of concern. A party to any such investment must submit to CFIUS a declaration containing basic information regarding the transaction.</summary>
</bill>
