<bill session="119" type="s" number="3119" updated="2026-06-02T14:57:49Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fisher House Availability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fisher House Availability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make temporary lodging facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs available for members of the Armed Forces, other individuals on active duty, and family members of such individuals on a space-available basis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-02T14:57:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fisher House Availability Act of 2025

This bill expands eligibility for temporary lodging at a Fisher House to additional individuals receiving medical care or treatment at a Department of Veteran Affairs (VA) or non-VA facility or those accompanying individuals receiving such treatment. (Fisher Houses are where the VA furnishes no-cost lodging to veterans and others when receiving treatment or accompanying an individual receiving treatment.)

Specifically, the bill authorizes the VA to provide lodging at a Fisher House on a space-available basis to

members of the Armed Forces, regardless of duty status, or any individual on active duty (i.e., eligible individuals) who must travel a significant distance to receive care or services;family members and others accompanying such eligible individuals to receive care or services;veterans, members of a veteran's family, and others who must travel a significant distance for a member of a veteran's family to receive care or services; andeligible individuals, members of an eligible individual&#8217;s family, and others who must travel a significant distance for a member of an eligible individual&#8217;s family to receive care or services.</summary>
</bill>
