<bill session="119" type="h" number="548" updated="2026-06-01T15:38:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HSA Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HSA Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modernize health savings accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2026-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2026-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="444" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2745" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-01T15:36:25Z" status="Introduced in House">HSA Modernization Act

This bill increases health savings account (HSA) contribution limits, expands HSA eligibility, and makes other changes to HSAs and high-deductible health plans (HDHP).

The bill increases HSA contribution limits to equal the limits on out-of-pocket expenses under an&#160;HDHP (adjusted annually). Under the bill, the maximum annual HSA contribution for 2025 is $8,300 for self-only coverage and $16,600 for family coverage. (Under current law, the maximum annual HSA contribution for 2025 is $4,300 for self-only coverage and $8,550 for family coverage.)

The bill expands eligibility to make tax-deductible HSA contributions to include individuals who

receive hospital care or medical services from the Department of Veterans Affairs and do not have a service-connected disability,receive hospital care or medical services provided by the Indian Health Service or a tribal organization,are at least 65 years old and enrolled in Medicare Part A, orhave a bronze-level or catastrophic health insurance plan through a health insurance exchange.The bill also allows eligible married individuals to make catch-up contributions to the same HSA.

Under the bill, HSA distributions may be used to pay for qualified medical expenses incurred before the HSA is established if the HSA is established within 60 days from the first day of coverage under an HDHP.

Further, the bill specifies that HSA distributions may be used to pay for expenses for qualified long-term care services.

Finally, the bill allows an HDHP to provide up to $500 of mental health benefits before the annual deductible is met.</summary>
</bill>
