<bill session="119" type="h" number="1426" updated="2026-05-06T13:21:38Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the amount allowed as a credit under the expenses for household and dependent care services credit and the employer-provided child care credit.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the amount allowed as a credit under the expenses for household and dependent care services credit and the employer-provided child care credit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001230"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-06T13:19:02Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill doubles the maximum amount that an individual may claim as a federal tax credit for qualified child and dependent care expenses and increases the maximum amount an employer may claim as a federal business tax credit for providing certain child care services to employees.

Under the bill, the annual maximum amount allowed for the child and dependent care tax credit is increased to $6,000 (from $3,000) for individuals with one qualifying child or dependent, or to $12,000 (from $6,000) for individuals with two or more qualifying children or dependents. (Under current law, an individual may claim a nonrefundable tax credit for a portion&#160;of qualified child and dependent care expenses paid so that the individual or the individual&#8217;s spouse can work or look for work.)

Further, the bill increases to $400,000 (from $150,000) the annual maximum amount that an employer may claim as a tax credit for providing certain child care services to employees. (Under current law, an employer may claim a nonrefundable business tax credit for a percentage of qualified child care facility expenses and child care referral and resource expenses.)</summary>
</bill>
