<bill session="119" type="hj" number="139" updated="2026-02-26T16:02:40Z">
  <state datetime="2026-02-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States requiring a balanced budget for the Federal Government.</title>
    <title type="display">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States requiring a balanced budget for the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001317" joined="2026-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001116" joined="2026-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-25">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 119-520.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-02-25" calendar="House" number="63">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 63.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-26T16:02:11Z" status="Introduced in House">This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment prohibiting total federal expenditures for a year from exceeding the average annual federal receipts collected in the three prior years, adjusted for changes in the population of U.S. citizens and inflation. Expenditures for payment of debt and receipts derived from borrowing are excluded.

Under the amendment, Congress may authorize specific expenditures in excess of the limit with (1) a roll call vote of two-thirds of each chamber, or (2) a roll call vote for any year in which a declaration of war is in effect.

The amendment also prohibits any bill to levy a new tax or increase the rate of any tax from becoming law unless it has been approved by a roll call vote of two-thirds of the whole number of each chamber of Congress.

The requirements take effect in the fifth year beginning after ratification of the amendment.</summary>
</bill>
