<bill session="119" type="h" number="4774" updated="2026-03-03T15:51:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fix Our Flooded Basements Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fix Our Flooded Basements Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that certain assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act is available for flood-damaged basements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000481"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001318" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000110" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000481" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2025-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001103" joined="2025-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000607" joined="2025-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001229" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001217" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000617" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3625"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-03T15:51:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Fix Our Flooded Basements Act of 2025

This bill expands the disaster assistance provided to individuals and households for repairs to and property in flood-damaged basements. It also expands eligibility and coverage for certain group flood insurance.

Under current law, the Individual Assistance (IA) program of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) limits home repair assistance for flood-damaged basements to damage affecting the safety, sanitation, or functionality of the home (e.g., structural damage, hazardous conditions). The bill allows home repair assistance for disaster-caused mold, mildew, and moisture damage in basements regardless of whether the damage affects safety, sanitation, or functionality. Additionally, flood-damaged basements are eligible for home repair assistance even when the basement is not required for occupying the dwelling.

Also, currently, IA assistance for flood-damaged personal property in basements is limited to washers, dryers, and property essential for occupying the dwelling. The bill expands IA personal property assistance to more broadly cover property damaged by disaster-caused flooding in basements. The scope of such assistance must at least equal the coverage for such damage by a standard policy under the National Flood Insurance Program (e.g., covering air conditioning units and freezers in basements).&#160;

Additionally, FEMA must expand the eligibility and coverage of the group flood insurance it provides to IA recipients, including increasing the maximum coverage and expanding coverage for basements.

The bill also excludes from the maximum for IA housing assistance expenses for (1) hazard mitigation measures in flood-damaged basements, and (2) premiums for group flood insurance policies.</summary>
</bill>
