<bill session="119" type="s" number="1815" updated="2026-03-26T20:25:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End Diaper Need Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Diaper Need Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide targeted funding for States and other eligible entities through the Social Services Block Grant program to address the increased burden that maintaining the health and hygiene of infants and toddlers, medically complex children, and low-income adults or adults with disabilities who rely on adult incontinence materials and supplies place on families in need, the resultant adverse health effects on children and families, and the limited child care options available for infants and toddlers who lack sufficient diapers and diapering supplies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2025-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3508" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-26T20:20:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">End Diaper Need Act of 2025

This bill establishes and expands programs to provide low-income families and other vulnerable groups with access to diapers and related supplies.

Specifically, it provides additional funding for FY2026-FY2029 to meet the diapering needs of certain low-income families and adults through the Social Services Block Grant Program. This grant program provides a flexible funding stream to states and territories to support social services for vulnerable children, adults, and families.

The bill exempts these funds for diapering needs from sequestration. Sequestration is a process of automatic, across-the-board reductions under which budgetary resources are permanently cancelled to enforce specific budget policy goals.

The bill requires these funds to be used to meet the diapering needs of

low-income families with one or more infants, toddlers, or medically complex children (i.e., children who are age three or older and diagnosed with a serious condition such as bowel or bladder incontinence); andlow-income families with adults, or children or adults with disabilities, who rely on diapers and other adult incontinence materials.The bill also allows individuals to buy medically necessary diapers and related supplies with funds from health savings accounts and other tax-advantaged accounts for health care expenses.</summary>
</bill>
