<bill session="119" type="s" number="1236" updated="2026-02-25T16:57:01Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FISCAL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FISCAL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom in School Cafeterias and Lunches Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require schools to offer a variety of milk to students participating in the school lunch program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2025-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2539" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-25T16:56:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Freedom in School Cafeterias and Lunches Act or the FISCAL Act

This bill revises requirements for milk provided by the National School Lunch Program of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to require that schools offer plant-based milk.

Under current law, schools must provide a substitute for fluid milk for students whose disability restricts their diet (on receipt of a written statement from a licensed physician). Schools may also substitute a nondairy beverage for fluid milk for students who have an identified medical or other special dietary need (on receipt of a written statement from a medical authority or a&#160;student's parent or legal guardian).

The bill eliminates the exceptions and documentation requirements. Instead, schools participating in the school lunch program must offer all students a plant-based milk option that is&#160;consistent with (1) the most recent U.S. Dietary Guidelines, or (2) USDA-established nutritional standards&#160;if the milk is&#160;not included under those guidelines.</summary>
</bill>
