<bill session="119" type="h" number="3227" updated="2026-05-01T21:41:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farm Workforce Modernization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm Workforce Modernization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Strategy and Investment in Rural Housing Preservation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for terms and conditions for nonimmigrant workers performing agricultural labor or services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000605" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2025-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2026-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2026-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Workforce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Workforce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Workforce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Workforce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-22T17:04:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Farm Workforce Modernization Act of 2025

This bill establishes a new certified agricultural worker (CAW) visa status for foreign farmworkers, heightens requirements under the current H-2A temporary worker program, and provides for mandatory employment eligibility verification for the agricultural workforce.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may grant CAW status to an applying non-U.S. national (alien under federal law) who meets certain requirements, such as hours worked in agricultural labor during a specified time period and having a continuous presence in the United States.

The bill establishes a path to lawful permanent resident status for those with CAW status.&#160;

CAW status shall be valid for 5.5 years and may be extended. The applicant's spouse or children may receive CAW dependent status.

A CAW applicant may not be detained or removed by DHS and shall be authorized for employment until DHS makes a final decision on the application.

The bill also modifies the H-2A visa program, which allows employers to hire foreign workers for temporary or seasonal agricultural work. The changes include&#160;(1) requiring H-2A employers to guarantee certain minimum work hours, and (2) making the program available for agricultural work that is not temporary or seasonal.

DHS must also establish an electronic system patterned on the E-Verify Program for employers to verify an individual's identity and employment authorization. Employers hiring individuals for agricultural employment must use the system.

The bill extends through FY2030 and codifies the Multifamily Housing Preservation and Revitalization program for rural and farmworker housing.</summary>
</bill>
