<bill session="119" type="s" number="966" updated="2026-03-23T18:18:26Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Traveler's Gun Rights Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Traveler's Gun Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to define "State of residence" and "resident", and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001243" joined="2025-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2060" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-23T18:14:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Traveler's Gun Rights Act

This bill broadens the scope of allowable firearms transactions involving active duty servicemembers&#160;and their spouses and individuals who do not have a residence in any state.

Currently, federal firearms laws generally prohibit a federal firearms licensee (e.g., a gun dealer) from selling or delivering a firearm to an individual whose state of residence is different than the state where the licensee's place of business is located.

This bill defines the term state of residence as the state in which an individual is present with an intention of making a home.

In the case of an individual who does not have a physical residence in any state, the term state of residence means the address of the individual's private mailbox or post office box.

In the case of a member of the Armed Forces on active duty, or his or her spouse, the term state of residence means (1) the state in which the member's permanent duty station is located, and (2) the state where the member maintains a place of abode from which he or she commutes to the permanent duty station.</summary>
</bill>
