<bill session="119" type="h" number="9022" updated="2026-05-29T15:11:59Z">
  <state datetime="2026-05-22">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2027</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2027</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2027, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000459"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-05-22">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 119-667, by Mr. Fleischmann.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-05-22" calendar="Union" number="581">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 581.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3635" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7250" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-29T15:07:41Z" status="Reported to House">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2027

This bill provides FY2027 appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation, the Department of Energy (DOE), and several independent agencies.

The bill provides appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, including for

Investigations,Construction,Mississippi River and Tributaries,Operation and Maintenance,the Regulatory Program,Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies,Expenses,the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, andthe Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Program.The bill provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project and the Bureau of Reclamation.

The bill provides appropriations to DOE for energy programs, including

Critical Minerals and Energy Innovation;Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response;Electricity;Nuclear Energy;Hydrocarbons and Geothermal Energy;Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves;the Strategic Petroleum Reserve;the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve;the Energy Information Administration;Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup;the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund;Science;Nuclear Waste Disposal;the Advanced Research Projects Agency&#8212;Energy;the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program;the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program;the Tribal Energy Loan Guarantee Program;Indian Energy Policy and Programs;Departmental Administration; andthe Office of the Inspector General.The bill also provides appropriations to DOE for

Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration,Environmental and Other Defense Activities, andthe Power Marketing Administrations.The bill provides appropriations to several independent agencies, including the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.

The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-667</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
