<bill session="119" type="s" number="1107" updated="2026-03-24T17:19:38Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MATCH Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Access To Cleanup Happen Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MATCH Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Credit Act of 1978 with respect to preagreement costs of emergency watershed protection measures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2025-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5781" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-24T17:16:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Making Access To Cleanup Happen Act of 2025 or the MATCH Act of 2025

This bill modifies the Department of Agriculture's (USDA's) Emergency Watershed Protection (EWP) program to allow sponsors (i.e., states, local governments, and Indian tribes) to undertake certain emergency watershed protection measures prior to entering into a project agreement with&#160;USDA and count the costs as part of the sponsor's share of the project cost once&#160;an agreement with USDA is in place.

As background, USDA's&#160;EWP Program offers assistance to sponsors to carry out projects that help safeguard people and property from floods, drought, fires, windstorms, and other natural disasters that impair a watershed.

This bill requires USDA to identify a list of emergency watershed protection measures that a sponsor may incur costs for prior to entering into a&#160;project agreement with USDA under the EWP Program.&#160;USDA must develop a procedure, to be implemented at the state level, through which these entities may request additional emergency watershed protection measures. The cost of undertaking these additional measures may be incurred by a sponsor prior to entering into an agreement with USDA.

Further, USDA must consider pre-agreement costs incurred by a sponsor for undertaking the emergency watershed protection measures as meeting part of a sponsor's contribution towards the project costs.</summary>
</bill>
