<bill session="119" type="h" number="2069" updated="2026-03-19T08:06:51Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Secret Spending Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Secret Spending Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 to ensure that other transaction agreements are reported to USAspending.gov, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000604" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001096" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="872" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-02T23:37:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Secret Spending Act of 2025

This bill expands a requirement for federal agencies to report expenditures on the USAspending.gov website to include other transaction agreement expenditures. (Other transaction agreements, or OTAs, are contractual instruments other than standard procurement contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements; they are exempt from many federal procurement laws and regulations).

Under current law, federal agencies must report expenditures on federal awards to USAspending.gov with the term federal award defined as federal grants, loans, cooperative agreements, contracts, and certain other types of expenditures. This bill expands the definition of federal award to include expenditures under OTAs, and therefore such expenditures must be included on the USAspending.gov website.

The Department of the Treasury must ensure that data relating to OTAs are automatically transmitted to the website and a centralized view of this data is available on the website.&#160;Treasury must also annually post on the&#160;USAspending.gov website a report that includes (1) the total amount of federal spending on federal awards for which data has not been posted on the website, and (2) the reason why such spending data was not posted.

For 10 years after enactment, the Office of Inspector General of specified federal agencies must periodically submit to Congress and make publicly available a report assessing the agency's spending data and use of data standards.</summary>
</bill>
