<bill session="119" type="s" number="2926" updated="2026-04-08T13:03:57Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New York-New Jersey Watershed Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New York-New Jersey Watershed Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2025-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2025-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5762" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-08T13:03:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">New York-New Jersey Watershed Protection Act

This bill establishes programs to restore and protect the New York-New Jersey Watershed. The watershed is composed of all land area the surface water of which drains into the New York-New Jersey Harbor, the waters contained within that land area, and associated estuaries.

Specifically, the bill requires the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to establish the New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program, a nonregulatory program, to coordinate restoration and protection activities among government entities and conservation partners throughout the watershed.

The bill also establishes the New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Grant Program, a voluntary grant and technical assistance program, to provide competitive matching grants to certain entities to implement restoration and protection activities for the watershed. The federal government may not maintain ownership of any land acquired under the bill except for the purpose of promptly transferring ownership to grant recipients.

The bill ceases to have force or effect on October 1, 2031.</summary>
</bill>
