<bill session="119" type="h" number="8872" updated="2026-06-05T23:21:23Z">
  <state datetime="2026-05-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Waste, Fraud, and Abuse in TANF Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Preventing Waste, Fraud, and Abuse in TANF Act</title>
    <title type="display">Preventing Waste, Fraud, and Abuse in TANF Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to target funds to low-income families, strengthen program integrity guardrails for State expenditure of funds, require measurement of improper payments, and establish goals for eliminating fraud and improper payments under the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000375" joined="2026-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001314" joined="2026-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2026-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2026-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001222" joined="2026-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001213" joined="2026-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2026-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2026-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-29">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 119-670.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-05-29" calendar="Union" number="584">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 584.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T09:18:44-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1333 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8646, H.R. 7726, H.R. 7892 and H.R. 8872. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8646 under a structured rule and H.R. 7726, H.R. 7892, and H.R. 8872 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each bill. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T14:32:11-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1333 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T15:22:38-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1333.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3805-3810" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3805-3806" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T15:22:43-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8646, H.R. 7726, H.R. 7892 and H.R. 8872. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8646 under a structured rule and H.R. 7726, H.R. 7892, and H.R. 8872 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each bill. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T15:23:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 8872.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T16:08:09-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T16:08:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the Chair announced further proceedings on H.R. 8872 is postponed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2242" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2359" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1333" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h225"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2026-06-01T16:43:32Z" status="Reported to House">Preventing Waste, Fraud, and Abuse in TANF Act

This bill limits how and when states may use Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) funds and establishes an eligibility threshold for all TANF-funded assistance and services.

Currently, each state sets its own eligibility threshold for TANF-funded cash assistance. The bill establishes an upper limit on eligibility applicable to all assistance and services (including non-cash benefits) funded by TANF family assistance grants. Under this provision, only families with income under 200% of the federal poverty guidelines may receive TANF-funded assistance and services.

Further, the bill generally requires states to obligate TANF funds by the end of the fiscal year after they are paid and to spend funds by the end of the second fiscal year after they are paid. However, states may reserve a specified portion of their TANF funds for future use. (There is currently no requirement to use&#160;TANF funds within a specified period.)

The bill also explicitly requires states to use federal TANF funds to supplement, not replace, state and local funding for TANF-supported programs. (Current law requires states to spend a specified minimum amount on TANF-eligible activities and populations, known as the maintenance of effort requirement.)

States must also take specified steps to track and report on improper payments of federal funds (e.g., overpayments, underpayments, payments to ineligible recipients). Within one year of enactment, HHS must submit to Congress a plan to reduce or eliminate improper payments made by states under the TANF program within 10 years.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-670</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
