<bill session="119" type="h" number="1555" updated="2026-06-02T14:52:21Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bureau of Land Management Mineral Spacing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Land Management Mineral Spacing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to streamline the oil and gas permitting process and to recognize fee ownership for certain oil and gas drilling or spacing units, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000740"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000482" joined="2025-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2025-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000601" joined="2025-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-02T14:50:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Bureau of Land Management Mineral Spacing Act

This bill exempts certain oil and gas exploration and production activities from permit and environmental review requirements. This exemption applies to activities conducted on&#160;nonfederal surface estates located on partially federally-held mineral rights.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the&#160;Bureau of Land Management (BLM)&#160;from requiring an operator to obtain a federal drilling permit under the&#160;Mineral Leasing Act&#160;for oil&#160;and&#160;gas exploration and production activities conducted on a nonfederal surface estate if (1) less than 50% of the subsurface mineral estate to be accessed by the proposed action is federally owned, and (2) the operator submits to the BLM a state permit to conduct such activities on the nonfederal surface estate.

Those activities are not considered to be a major federal action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA), and thus are exempt from&#160;environmental review requirements under NEPA. Further, those&#160;activities are exempt from&#160;requirements for federal actions under the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966 and the Endangered Species Act of 1973.

The bill does not apply to Indian lands.</summary>
</bill>
