<bill session="119" type="s" number="4455" updated="2026-06-29T15:27:18Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Lands Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Lands Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 313 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to designate provisions resulting in the sale, disposal, or transfer of Federal lands as extraneous under the Byrd Rule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2026-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2026-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2026-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2026-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2026-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="9167" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-29T15:24:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Lands Integrity Act

This bill generally prohibits&#160;provisions that result in the sale, disposal, or transfer of federal lands from being included in reconciliation legislation by requiring the provisions&#160;to be considered extraneous under the Senate's Byrd Rule.&#160;

The Senate's Byrd Rule (named after it's principal author, Senator Robert&#160;Byrd of West Virginia) prohibits the inclusion of matter in reconciliation legislation that is extraneous to a congressional committee's reconciliation directives in the associated congressional budget resolution. Reconciliation is an expedited method by which Congress may adopt changes in spending and revenue laws to achieve the budgetary goals reflected in a congressional budget resolution. Reconciliation bills are considered by Congress using expedited legislative procedures that prevent a filibuster and restrict amendments in the Senate.

For additional information, see CRS Report R48640, The Senate&#8217;s Byrd Rule: Frequently Asked Questions.</summary>
</bill>
