<bill session="119" type="h" number="6338" updated="2026-06-10T10:56:32Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-08T17:16:48-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-08T17:16:48-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Illegal Fishing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Stop Illegal Fishing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons and foreign vessels that engage in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official">To require the imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons and foreign vessels that engage in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Illegal Fishing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001137"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2026-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2026-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2025-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 47 - 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:12:25-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mast moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:12:48-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3968-3970" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:12:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6338.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-06-08T17:16:48-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3968-3969" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:16:51-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-04T13:42:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Illegal Fishing Act

This bill requires the President to impose&#160;sanctions on foreign vessels and persons&#160;engaged in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing (IUU fishing).

The bill directs the President to block and prohibit all transactions involving property (including interests in property) of a covered foreign vessel or person if such property comes within the United States or within&#160;the possession or control of a U.S. person. The President must also deny or revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to or sought by a covered foreign person. Civil and criminal penalties apply to violations, including attempts or conspiracies to violate the sanctions.&#160;

A covered foreign vessel is any vessel that is&#160;registered or operated under the authority of a foreign country and engages in IUU fishing. Covered foreign persons are individuals or entities that are not U.S. persons and&#160;knowingly (1) own any vessel that engages in IUU fishing, (2) work as a captain or senior crew member on any vessel that engages in IUU fishing, (3)&#160;operate as an entity primarily engaged in&#160;IUU fishing, or&#160;(4) serve as an officer or senior manager in an entity primarily engaged in IUU fishing.

The President may waive the application of these sanctions after notifying Congress that the waiver is important to U.S. national security interests. Other exceptions apply, such as to provide life-saving assistance to a covered vessel.

The bill directs the President to periodically report to Congress on efforts to carry out these provisions.</summary>
</bill>
