<bill session="119" type="h" number="2406" updated="2026-06-02T13:39:01Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to address sexual harassment and sexual assault involving National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2025-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-02T13:38:11Z" status="Introduced in House">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2025

This bill expands requirements for addressing sexual harassment and sexual assault involving personnel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).

The bill specifies that NOAA's sexual harassment prevention and response policy applies to personnel such as observers, at-sea monitors, and voting members and staff of regional fishery management councils.

The bill removes the requirement that certain acts, such as assault, intimidation, and sexual harassment of an observer or a data collector, be forcible in nature&#160;to be unlawful.

The bill also requires NOAA's Office of Marine and Aviation Operations to establish a policy for reporting to the Coast Guard the names of NOAA personnel involved in a&#160;sexual&#160;harassment or sexual assault claim. Specifically, such reports must identify employees or contractors who are the subject of such claim, the time and date of&#160;the incident, and the location of the vessel when the incident&#160;occurred.

The bill prohibits a person convicted of certain sexual offenses&#160;from enlisting with or being commissioned by NOAA.

Additionally, the bill directs NOAA to update its&#160;policies to develop a restricted reporting system that allows employees and other personnel to confidentially report sexual harassment or assault and receive services without triggering an investigation.

Finally, the bill also expands reporting requirements on sexual harassment, sexual assault, and equal employment.</summary>
</bill>
