<bill session="119" type="s" number="3027" updated="2026-04-08T16:35:46Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Interstate Commerce Simplification Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Interstate Commerce Simplification Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend Public Law 86-272 to expand the prohibition of State taxation relating to certain solicitation of orders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="427" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-08T16:33:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Interstate Commerce Simplification Act of 2025

This bill expands the definition of solicitation of orders to include business activities that serve an independently valuable business function apart from the solicitation of orders for purposes of the limitation on a state&#8217;s authority to impose a net income tax on an out-of-state seller.

Under current law, a state is prohibited from imposing a net income tax on income derived from within the state from interstate commerce if the only business activity within the state is the solicitation of orders for the sale of tangible personal property, provided that the orders are approved (or rejected) and filled by shipment or delivery from outside of the state. Further, the Supreme Court has held&#160;that the term&#160;solicitation of orders includes (1) activities that are strictly essential to making requests for purchases, and (2) ancillary activities that serve no independent business function apart from their connection to requests for purchases.

Under the bill, the definition of solicitation of orders is expanded to include business activities that facilitate the solicitation of orders even if such business activities serve an independently valuable business function apart from the solicitation.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
