<bill session="119" type="h" number="9137" updated="2026-06-22T15:29:06Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect College Sports Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect College Sports Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the name, image, and likeness rights of, and provide protections for, student athletes and to promote fair competition among intercollegiate athletics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001322"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="4668" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-22T15:25:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect College Sports Act of 2026

This bill establishes requirements for name, image, or likeness (NIL) agreements for college student athletes and provides a limited antitrust exemption for schools and conferences to pool and sell certain college sports media rights. The requirements address elements of the court-approved agreement to settle&#160;In re College Athlete NIL Litigation (i.e., House settlement).

First, the bill statutorily prohibits institutions, conferences, or interstate intercollegiate athletic associations (e.g., the National Collegiate Athletic Association [NCAA]) from restricting student athletes from entering NIL agreements (subject to specified limitations). Students must report to their institution NIL compensation greater than $600.

The bill requires agents to register with a state and caps agent endorsement contract fees at 5%.The bill also provides student athletes with one transfer without losing athletic eligibility and restricts&#160;football personnel from becoming the head football coach at a different institution during the same season.

Further, the bill prohibits institutions, conferences, or specified entities acting for the benefit of an institution from providing athletes with compensation that circumvents&#160;the limit on sharing revenue with student athletes established under the House settlement. The bill also makes the limit permanent and provides for an annual inflation adjustment.

Additionally, the bill establishes (subject to specified conditions) a limited antitrust exemption for institutions or conferences that form joint agreements to transfer their sports telecasting rights to a third party. Such an agreement requires participation from at least 75% of the institutions in the Football Bowl Subdivision.</summary>
</bill>
