<bill session="119" type="hr" number="1336" updated="2026-06-05T14:58:28Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-04T17:50:54-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-04T17:50:54-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000450"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 119-685, by Ms. Foxx.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T17:07:54-04:00">
      <text>The resolution waives a requirement of clause 6(a) of Rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-06-03" calendar="House" number="78">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 78.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04T14:30:47-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04T14:31:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1336.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04T14:59:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res 1336, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04T16:45:20-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04T17:08:59-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 212 - 210 (Roll no. 202).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="203" datetime="2026-06-04T17:50:54-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 213 - 211 (Roll no. 203).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-04T17:50:55-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-05T14:17:14Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution provides for the House of Representatives to consider&#160;on the same day without a two-thirds vote&#160;any resolution reported by the Committee on Rules through the legislative day of June 5, 2026, relating to a measure providing for reconciliation pursuant to title II of S.Con.Res.33. Specifically, the resolution waives a House Rule requiring a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-685</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
