<bill session="119" type="s" number="629" updated="2026-03-25T11:33:21Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-24">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Conservation Program Improvement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Conservation Program Improvement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Emergency Conservation Program Improvement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Credit Act of 1978 to remove barriers to agricultural producers in accessing funds to carry out emergency measures under the emergency conservation program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2025-02-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24">
      <text>Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2026-03-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T14:02:29-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T14:11:22-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-01-29T15:06:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emergency Conservation Program Improvement Act of 2025 

This bill revises the Emergency Conservation Program (ECP) and the Emergency Forest Restoration Program (EFRP) to expand eligibility for payments to agricultural producers and owners of forest land impacted by natural disasters. The bill also&#160;provides additional options to receive an advance on cost-sharing payments before carrying out emergency measures.

The bill expands advance ECP payments to include&#160;the replacement, repair, or restoration of farmland or conservation structures requiring an immediate response. Producers may receive an advance on cost-sharing payments for 75% of the cost of the replacement and 50% of the cost of the repair or restoration. Current law limits advance payments to 25% of the cost of the repair or replacement of fencing.

Under EFRP, the bill allows owners of nonindustrial private forest land impacted by a natural disaster to receive an advance on cost-sharing payments for up to 75% of the cost of the emergency measures. Currently, advance payments are not available under the program.

ECP and EFRP recipients must use the funds within 180 days after the funds are disbursed. This provides additional time to ECP recipients who currently must use the funds within 60 days.

The bill also expands eligibility for payments under the programs to include emergency measures to address damages caused by (1) a wildfire that is not caused naturally, if the damage is caused by the spread of the wildfire due to natural causes; and (2) a wildfire that is caused by the federal government.</summary>
</bill>
