<bill session="119" type="h" number="2120" updated="2026-03-31T08:05:36Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ROCR Value Based Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Radiation Oncology Case Rate Value Based Program Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ROCR Value Based Program Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend Title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create a Radiation Oncology Case Rate Value Based Payment Program exempt from budget neutrality adjustment requirements, and to amend section 1128A of title XI of the Social Security Act to create a new statutory exception for the provision of free or discounted transportation for radiation oncology patients to receive radiation therapy services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001306" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000668" joined="2026-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2026-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2026-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2026-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2025-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000302" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000399" joined="2026-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2026-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2025-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2025-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000048" joined="2026-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2026-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001221" joined="2025-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000831" joined="2026-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1031" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-11T21:55:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Radiation Oncology Case Rate Value Based Program Act of 2025 or the ROCR Value Based Program Act

This bill establishes a specialized payment program under Medicare for providers and suppliers of radiation oncology services.&#160;

Specifically, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) must establish a program under which radiation therapy providers (i.e., hospital outpatient departments) and suppliers (i.e., physician group practices and freestanding radiation therapy centers) receive payments for each episode of care provided to individuals with specified types of cancer. An episode of care&#160;means the period beginning on the day radiation therapy planning is furnished to the individual and ending (1) for individuals with bone or brain metastases, 30 days later; and (2) for individuals with other cancer types, 90 days later.

Participation in the program is mandatory for providers and suppliers that participate in Medicare, unless the provider or supplier is part of a state-based Center for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Innovation model or qualifies for a significant hardship exemption. The CMS must set payment rates for the program based on national payment rates with specified adjustments (e.g., geographic adjustments). Providers and suppliers who provide certain transportation&#160;services for individuals under their care may receive an additional payment. Providers and suppliers must be accredited in accordance with certain standards, subject to payment reductions.

The Government Accountability Office must report on (1) implementation of the program, and (2) underserved areas that are in need of more or newer radiation therapy resources.</summary>
</bill>
