<bill session="119" type="h" number="8463" updated="2026-06-10T08:06:18Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-08T14:39:08-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-08T14:39:08-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pre-Payment Fraud Prevention and Treasury Data Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Pre-Payment Fraud Prevention and Treasury Data Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish governmentwide requirements for pre-payment fraud prevention actions, to provide the U.S. Treasury appropriate data resources, to facilitate participation in governmentwide anti-fraud data sharing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official">To establish governmentwide requirements for pre-payment fraud prevention actions, to provide the U.S. Treasury appropriate data resources, to facilitate participation in governmentwide anti-fraud data sharing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Pre-Payment Fraud Prevention and Treasury Data Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001108"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000375" joined="2026-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2026-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000598" joined="2026-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 35 - 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 119-688, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-06-08" calendar="Union" number="600">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 600.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T14:33:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gill (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T14:33:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3919-3923" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T14:33:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 8463.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-06-08T14:39:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3919-3922" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T14:39:13-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Data collection, sharing, protection"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-05T16:04:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Pre-Payment Fraud Prevention and Treasury Data Access Act

This bill expands efforts to identify, prevent, and recover improper payments of federal funds (e.g., overpayments, underpayments, payments to ineligible recipients).

Specifically, the Department of the Treasury must establish certain requirements that agencies must meet before directing Treasury to make a payment of federal funds. These pre-payment requirements must include verification of payee information, payment details, and fund availability. Further, agencies must, to the extent practicable, verify the accuracy of payee bank account information before directing Treasury to make a payment.

The bill also expands the Do Not Pay system, which provides agencies with access to centralized data for the purpose of verifying payee eligibility, and provides statutory authority for Treasury&#8217;s role as administrator of the system. The bill requires specified data assets to be added to the system and authorizes Treasury to (1) designate additional data assets for inclusion, and (2) access certain taxpayer and Social Security information for the system. The bill specifies that information obtained through the system may only be used to prevent and recover improper payments and establishes penalties for the unlawful disclosure of such information.

The bill explicitly requires executive agencies and state and local governments administering federally funded programs to screen payees against all appropriate Do Not Pay data assets and risk tools before making an award or directing a payment.

Finally, the bill establishes post-award reporting requirements for certain first-time fund recipients under federal programs for awards of&#160;$50,000 or more.</summary>
</bill>
