<bill session="119" type="h" number="3387" updated="2026-05-15T20:51:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ETS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing the Transitioning Servicemember&#8217;s Experience Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ETS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 10 and 38, United States Code, to make improvements to certain programs for a member nearing separation, or for a veteran who recently separated, from the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000135"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-15T20:46:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Enhancing the Transitioning Servicemember&#8217;s Experience Act or the ETS Act

This bill expands the provision of pre-separation counseling&#160;under the Transition Assistance Program (TAP) and&#160;other services for members of the Armed Forces who are transitioning to civilian life.

Regarding pre-separation counseling under TAP, the bill

sets a minimum&#160;duration of counseling depending on a member's post-service employment, education, or training status;prohibits individuals who are responsible for the retention of members in any of the Armed Forces from providing counseling;removes restrictions on the types of counseling for which a spouse of a member may be included;expands financial planning counseling to include information about debt and investing;requires that financial planning counseling be provided by an individual who has significant experience in financial planning; andrequires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and Department of Labor to audit counseling annually.If a military department determines an individual is at risk for a difficult transition to civilian life, that department must provide the individual's information to the VA&#160;and Labor. The VA and Labor must timely contact&#160;the individual, as specified.

Additionally, the bill extends transitional health care for members separating from service to 270 days (currently 180).

The bill also

expands eligibility for certain Labor job counseling, training, and placement services for veterans to members of the Armed Forces who are eligible for TAP; andexpands the Solid Start program by requiring the VA to provide TAP materials to veterans and analyze data assessing the effectiveness of TAP.</summary>
</bill>
