<bill session="119" type="h" number="7142" updated="2026-04-16T16:07:05Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACE Agriculture Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACE Agriculture Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Cutting Edge Agriculture Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to extend and permanently authorize the Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000613"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2026-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2026-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2026-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-16T16:02:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing Cutting Edge Agriculture Act or the ACE Agriculture Act

This bill reauthorizes the Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority (AGARDA) through FY2032 and expands the program's environmental sustainability goals. This Department of Agriculture (USDA) program supports innovative research and development of technology, research tools, and products to address long-term and high-risk challenges related to food and agriculture.

The bill expands the program's goals to include

water conservation;responding to greenhouse gas emissions; andresilience to drought, infectious diseases, and plant and animal pathogens and pests.The bill also expands the program's goals to include undertaking advanced research and development in areas in which industry by itself is not likely to do so because of economic cost.

Further, the bill removes the current pilot program designation and requires USDA to establish and maintain an AGARDA staff.

Finally, the bill allows USDA to use any unobligated USDA funds to implement the program.</summary>
</bill>
