<bill session="119" type="s" number="3354" updated="2026-04-03T14:58:37Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">QUIET Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quashing Unwanted and Interruptive Electronic Telecommunications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">QUIET Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require disclosures with respect to robocalls using artificial intelligence and to provide for enhanced penalties for certain violations involving artificial intelligence voice or text message impersonation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1027" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-03T14:57:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Quashing Unwanted and Interruptive Electronic Telecommunications Act or the QUIET Act

This bill establishes a disclosure requirement for robocalls that use artificial intelligence (AI) to emulate a human being and increases forfeiture and fine amounts for certain violations of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act (TCPA). (The TCPA prohibits certain telemarketing calls made without the recipient&#8217;s consent and using specified automated technologies.)

Specifically, any robocall that uses AI to emulate a human being must include a disclosure at the beginning of the message indicating that AI is being used. Under the bill, robocalls are defined as calls made or text messages sent (1) using automatic dialing technology, or (2) using an artificially generated message or an artificial or prerecorded voice. Calls or texts that are made or sent using equipment that requires substantial human intervention are excluded.&#160;

Further, the bill doubles the maximum forfeiture penalty and criminal fine that may be imposed for certain violations of the TCPA involving the use of AI to impersonate an individual or entity with the intent to defraud, cause harm, or wrongfully obtain anything of value. This provision applies to violations that occur after the bill&#8217;s enactment.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
