<bill session="119" type="h" number="905" updated="2026-05-01T13:06:24Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EITC Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EITC Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the earned income tax credit to all taxpayers with dependents and to qualifying students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000822"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000381" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000477" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000400" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001237" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001229" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2025-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2025-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-01T13:02:44Z" status="Introduced in House">EITC Modernization Act

This bill expands eligibility for the earned income tax credit (EITC), provides a minimum EITC amount of $1,200 (subject to limitations), and allows an individual to receive the EITC as monthly payments. The bill also establishes a grant program for tax return preparation assistance for low-income individuals.

Under the bill, EITC eligibility is expanded to include a student who meets certain requirements and an individual with a qualifying dependent, which includes a

qualifying child,dependent who attains the age of 65 within the tax year and for whom the individual may claim a&#160;tax deduction for a&#160;personal exemption, anddependent or spouse who is physically or mentally incapable of caring for themselves and meets certain residency requirements.Further, for an individual who does not have a qualifying dependent, the bill lowers the EITC eligibility age to 18 years (from 25 years) and eliminates the maximum age limit.

The bill allows an individual who meets certain requirements to receive the EITC in monthly payments and provides for a one-time increase in the first monthly payment. The bill also provides a new parent (through birth or adoption) an increase in their monthly EITC payments (subject to limitations).

Finally, the bill establishes a grant program, which is similar to the existing Volunteer Income Tax Assistance program&#160;and provides funding for tax&#160;return preparation assistance for&#160;low-income taxpayers and members of underserved populations.</summary>
</bill>
