<bill session="119" type="h" number="9310" updated="2026-06-15T15:37:41Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-12">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2027</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2027</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2027</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2027, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-06-12">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 119-697, by Mr. Amodei (NV).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-06-12" calendar="Union" number="605">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 605.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2729" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-15T15:35:07Z" status="Reported to House">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2027

This bill provides FY2027 appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Specifically, the bill provides appropriations to DHS for Departmental Management, Intelligence, Situational Awareness, and Oversight, including

the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management;the Management Directorate;Intelligence, Analysis, and Situational Awareness; andthe Office of Inspector General.In addition, the bill provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations, including

U.S. Customs and Border Protection,U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement,the Transportation Security Administration,the U.S. Coast Guard, andthe U.S. Secret Service.The bill provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery, including

the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, andthe Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).The bill provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services, including

U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services,the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers, andthe Science and Technology Directorate.The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-697</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
