<bill session="119" type="s" number="2250" updated="2026-04-24T17:06:01Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring the Armed Career Criminal Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring the Armed Career Criminal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, relating to sentencing of armed career criminals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2025-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4334" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-24T17:03:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring the Armed Career Criminal Act&#160;This bill expands the criminal offenses that qualify as prior convictions for the purpose of enhanced sentencing under the Armed Career Criminal Act (ACCA).&#160;Currently, the ACCA imposes a 15-year mandatory minimum prison term on a defendant who possesses, receives, or transports a firearm as a prohibited person (e.g., felon) and has three or more prior convictions for a serious drug offense or violent felony (or both)&#160;committed on separate occasions.

The term serious drug offense means a federal or state offense with a statutory maximum prison term of 10 years or more. A state offense must involve the manufacture, distribution, or possession of a controlled substance as defined in the Controlled Substances Act.

The term violent felony means any crime punishable by a prison term of more than one year that (1) has as an element the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force; or (2) is burglary, arson, or extortion, or involves explosives.

This bill replaces serious drug offense and violent felony with a new category of qualifying prior offense: serious felony convictions. The term serious felony conviction means (1) any conviction that, at the time of sentencing, was a felony offense punishable by a statutory maximum prison term of 10 years or more; or (2) any group of convictions imposed in the same proceeding or in consolidated proceedings with a total prison term of 10 years of more, regardless of how many years the defendant served.</summary>
</bill>
