<bill session="119" type="h" number="7640" updated="2026-04-17T15:52:15Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shut Down Sanctuary Policies Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shut Down Sanctuary Policies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Shut Down Sanctuary Policies Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve public safety through the enforcement of Federal immigration law in the interior of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2026-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000478" joined="2026-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001096" joined="2026-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2026-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2026-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 119-541.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-03-12" calendar="Union" number="465">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 465.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-17T15:45:37Z" status="Reported to House">Shut Down Sanctuary Policies Act of 2026

This bill addresses issues related to state and local government cooperation with federal immigration enforcement efforts, including by prohibiting limitations on cooperation, revising detainer authority, and restricting funding for certain jurisdictions.

Federal, state, and local government entities, including personnel,&#160;must be allowed to (1) comply with or enforce immigration laws or cooperate with immigration enforcement efforts, or (2) inquire about an individual's immigration status. Currently, such government entities must be allowed to share immigration-related information with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

DHS must issue a detainer&#160;for individuals arrested for any criminal or motor vehicle offense if&#160;DHS has probable cause that they are inadmissible or deportable.

Jurisdictions not in compliance with this bill, as determined by&#160;DHS, are ineligible for certain funding for law enforcement or immigration. This funding must be reallocated to jurisdictions that are in compliance.

The bill also creates a private right of action for victims of certain crimes to bring against a state or local government that, for example, released the individual who was convicted of the crime despite a detainer.

The bill provides federal immunity for officials and entities in compliance with the bill and removal to federal court for related prosecutions.

DHS&#160;may&#160;decline transfer&#160;of an individual in its custody if the requesting jurisdiction is not in compliance with this bill.&#160;DHS&#160;is prohibited from transferring an individual with a final order of removal.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-541</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
