<bill session="119" type="s" number="357" updated="2026-04-20T15:47:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Freeze Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Freeze Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose restrictions on Federal agencies with respect to appointments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="200" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-20T15:47:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Freeze Act

This bill bars pay raises for federal employees for one year and requires reductions in the number of employees at each federal agency.

The bill prohibits agencies from increasing the basic pay of any employee for one year after enactment. Also in that first year, the bill prohibits each federal agency from increasing the number of its employees beyond the number employed on the date of the bill's enactment, except that the agency may increase such number (1) when making appointments to positions related to law enforcement, public safety, or national security; or (2) if the individual so appointed is essential to emergency response under the Stafford Act. (The Stafford Act authorizes the President to issue declarations that provide states, tribes, and localities with a range of federal assistance in response to natural disasters and man-made incidents).

Additionally, the bill requires reductions in force such that within three years of the bill's enactment the number of employees at each agency is 5% lower than it was on the date of the bill's enactment. Employees that serve the interest of law enforcement, public safety, or national security or are essential to emergency response under the Stafford Act are not counted for the purposes of determining the number of employees at each agency.</summary>
</bill>
