<bill session="119" type="h" number="6547" updated="2026-05-02T11:56:20Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Least Cost Exception Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Least Cost Exception Act</title>
    <title type="display">Least Cost Exception Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to provide an exception to the least-cost resolution requirement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2025-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2026-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001217" joined="2025-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000612" joined="2025-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 50 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-02">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 119-474.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-02-02" calendar="Union" number="405">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 405.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="6955" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-08T19:37:27Z" status="Reported to House">Least Cost Exception Act

This bill allows the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to waive the least-cost resolution requirement for failed insured depository institutions and use alternative methods of resolution, particularly alternatives that do not involve global systemically important banks (G-SIBs).

Under current law, the&#160;FDIC must use the resolution method (such as a deposit payoff or the purchase and assumption of a bank&#8217;s assets and liabilities) that costs the&#160;FDIC's Deposit Insurance Fund the least to implement when an insured depository institution fails.

The bill provides an exception to this requirement if the following criteria are met:

the alternative method is the least costly of all alternatives that do not involve a G-SIB and that do not exceed the cost of liquidation;the difference in cost between the selected alternative and the cost of a resolution involving a purchase and assumption by a G-SIB is less than a maximum cost as established by rule;if the alternative involves a person purchasing assets or assuming liabilities, that person must pay an assessment to the&#160;FDIC; andit is determined that the risks to the fund are outweighed by the benefits of limiting the concentration of U.S. banking under G-SIBs.FDIC must issue a report on any use of the exception established by this bill containing an analysis of the economic impact of cost differences between the selected alternative and the least-cost alternative.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-474</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
