<bill session="119" type="s" number="920" updated="2026-06-11T20:50:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Child Labor Exploitation in Federal Contracting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Child Labor Exploitation in Federal Contracting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that Federal contractors comply with child labor laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2025-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-11T20:50:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing Child Labor Exploitation in Federal Contracting Act

This bill prohibits federal agencies from awarding contracts to entities and offerors that (1) admit to having violated federal child labor laws,&#160;and (2) have failed to take corrective action.&#160;The bill also increases civil penalties for violations of specified child labor provisions.

Under the bill, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council must amend regulations to require

any entity that enters into a contract with a federal agency to annually represent whether such entity has been determined to have violated federal child labor laws in the preceding three years, andany offeror, as well as each subcontractor or service provider to be used in performing the offeror's contract or considered for the performance of such contract, to certify whether it has been determined to have violated federal child labor laws in the preceding three years.Those who affirm they have violated child labor laws&#160;must update their representation or certification regarding any corrective measures they have taken.&#160;

Federal agencies are prohibited from awarding contracts to entities or offerors (including applicable subcontractors or service providers) that affirm they have violated federal child labor law and that have failed to implement required corrective measures.

The Department of Labor must annually prepare a list of entities, offerors, subcontractors, and service providers that are subject to this prohibition and conduct suspension and debarment proceedings against them. Federal agencies may not solicit offers, award contracts, or consent to subcontracts with those listed for at least four years.</summary>
</bill>
