<bill session="119" type="s" number="3094" updated="2026-07-01T16:56:28Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pay Our Capitol Police Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Our Capitol Police Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that officers, employees, and contractors of the Capitol Police are paid during the Government shutdown that began on October 1, 2025, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2025-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-07-01T16:51:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pay Our Capitol Police Act

This bill provides FY2026 continuing appropriations for the U.S. Capitol Police (USCP) to pay and provide benefits for employees who are working during the government shutdown that began on October 1, 2025, due to a lapse in appropriations.&#160;

Specifically, the bill provides the appropriations to the&#160;USCP for the pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments otherwise payable on a regular basis to all USCP officers and employees for work performed during the shutdown.

The bill also provides appropriations for payments to USCP contractors who are providing support to USCP officers and employees&#160;who are working during the shutdown.

The appropriations are available until the earlier of (1) the enactment into law of legislation to provide FY2026 appropriations for the USCP or the legislative branch (including continuing appropriations), or (2) September 30, 2026.

The bill must take effect as if it had been enacted on September 30, 2025.</summary>
</bill>
