<bill session="119" type="s" number="1185" updated="2026-03-05T16:46:55Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIGHTING for America Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIGHTING for America Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fighting Illicit Goods, Helping Trustworthy Importers, and Netting Gains for America Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 321 of the Tariff Act of 1930 to enhance transparency with respect to shipments seeking an administrative exemption from duties for low-value entries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-05T16:45:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fighting Illicit Goods, Helping Trustworthy Importers, and Netting Gains for America Act of 2025 or the FIGHTING for America Act of 2025

This bill makes changes to the de minimis exemption, including by eliminating the exemption for certain U.S. imports. (Section 321 of the Tariff Act of 1930 allows for U.S. imports under a de minimis threshold of $800 per shipment to enter free of tariffs, fees, and taxes.)

The bill prohibits U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) from applying the de minimis exemption to certain goods, such as goods that are&#160;

subject to specified trade remedies, such as&#160;safeguard measures (Section 201 of the Trade Act of 1974), actions in response to unfair trade practices (Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974), or actions for national security purposes (Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962);designated as import sensitive under the Generalized System of Preferences (e.g., textiles and apparel); oridentified as presenting persistent and significant evidence of illegal importation.The bill directs CBP to collect additional information&#160;on goods&#160;that may qualify for the de minimis exemption. The bill establishes penalties for related violations, including a civil penalty for providing a false statement to CBP and a minimum penalty for aiding unlawful importation.

The bill establishes a specific fee for each shipment entering under the de minimis exemption.&#160;

CBP must designate as a priority trade issue the smuggling of&#160;fentanyl and other drugs by abusing entry procedures for goods qualifying for the de minimis exemption.</summary>
</bill>
