<bill session="119" type="h" number="8428" updated="2026-06-13T05:53:29Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-08T19:05:12-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-08T19:05:12-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act</title>
    <title type="short">Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish a mandatory antifraud and improper payment training program for Federal program administrators, to provide for the availability of such training to State and local entities administering Federally funded programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish an antifraud and improper payment training program for Federal program administrators, to provide for the availability of such training to State and local entities administering Federally funded programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2026-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 40 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gill (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T15:20:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3934-3936" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T15:20:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 8428.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T15:27:46-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T18:57:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3975-3976" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="209" datetime="2026-06-08T19:05:12-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 393 - 0 (Roll no. 209).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3934-3935" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T19:05:13-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T19:05:15-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-05T13:14:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and the Department of the Treasury to&#160;establish and maintain a mandatory antifraud and&#160;improper payment prevention training program for federal employees whose&#160;roles involve federal financial assistance or oversight of federal programs. The program must also be made available to state, local, and tribal governments to train relevant personnel.

Under the bill, federal agencies must ensure that all federal employees in roles involving oversight of federal programs or federal financial assistance complete the training every two years. (Such positions include program administrator or officer, financial administrator or manager, disbursement certifying official, auditing official, and grants manager.) The Office of Personnel Management shall certify and maintain records of completion.

Treasury must also provide the program and related technical assistance to state, local, and tribal governments for training&#160;employees who are responsible for the administration of federally funded programs. Federal agencies may make completion of the program a condition of a federal grant or award.

The program curriculum must include comprehensive instruction on specified topics, including (1) identifying fraud and improper payment risks in federal programs; (2) using government-wide&#160;antifraud data sharing and&#160;other payee validation programs; and (3) reporting mechanisms for suspected fraud, waste, and abuse.

No later than two years after the date of the bill's enactment, Treasury and OMB must provide&#160;Congress with a report on program implementation.

Finally, Treasury may prescribe any regulations necessary to implement and administer the training program.</summary>
</bill>
