<bill session="119" type="h" number="5337" updated="2026-03-30T13:34:27Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Motor Carrier Safety Selection Standard Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Motor Carrier Safety Selection Standard Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national motor carrier safety selection standard for entities that contract with certain motor carriers to transport goods, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001212"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-30T13:33:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Motor Carrier Safety Selection Standard Act of 2024

This bill establishes a standard of care for the selection of brokers and other entities that contract with motor carriers (e.g., trucking companies) for the shipment of goods or household goods. (A broker is the middle person between a shipper and a motor carrier. Brokers arrange for the transportation of property or household goods.)

Specifically, the bill requires such entities to verify that a transporting motor carrier (1) is properly registered with the Department of Transportation (DOT); (2) has obtained the minimum required insurance coverage; and (3) is in compliance with all Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration safety standards, including through a public confirmation statement. Entities that comply with the verification requirements shall be considered reasonable and prudent in the selection of a covered motor carrier (for the purposes of a claim of negligent selection of a motor carrier).&#160;

Further, DOT must promulgate final regulations that revise the methodology for issuing motor carrier safety fitness determinations. The regulations must provide a procedure for DOT to determine whether a motor carrier is not fit to operate a commercial motor vehicle that is in, or affects, interstate commerce.&#160;

The bill exempts from the verification requirements an individual shipper (i.e., a shipper that owns the goods being transported and pays the tariff transportation charges) that contracts with a covered motor carrier.</summary>
</bill>
