<bill session="119" type="s" number="3095" updated="2026-04-09T19:56:50Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">An original bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to convey a parcel of property of the Forest Service to Perry County, Arkansas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to convey a parcel of property of the Forest Service to Perry County, Arkansas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Boozman. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-11-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="259">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 259.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3187" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-09T19:56:45Z" status="Reported to Senate">This bill directs the Forest Service to convey approximately one acre of land to Perry County, Arkansas, upon the request of the county. The county must use the land for public purposes, such as supporting education and youth development. If it ceases to be used for such purposes, then the property must, at the discretion of the Forest Service, revert to the United States.

The exact acreage of land to be conveyed must be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Forest Service.

The conveyance must be subject to valid existing rights, made without consideration, made by quitclaim deed, and subject to other terms and conditions that&#160;the Forest Service considers to be appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.

As a condition of the conveyance, the county must pay costs associated with the conveyance, including the cost of a survey, any environmental analysis or resources survey required under federal law, and any analysis required to comply with the National Historic Preservation Act.

The bill prohibits the Forest Service from having to provide any covenant or warranty for the property and improvements conveyed to the county.</summary>
</bill>
