<bill session="119" type="h" number="7971" updated="2026-04-22T20:20:00Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Experience Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Taxpayer Experience Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Taxpayer Experience Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for modernization and technological improvements of services provided by the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2026-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 43 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 119-607.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-09" calendar="Union" number="527">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 527.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3931" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Data collection, sharing, protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-07T13:53:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Taxpayer Experience Improvement Act

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to provide certain information related to call volume, wait times, and other metrics. The bill also expands online taxpayer accounts and electronic access to federal tax return and refund information.

Specifically, the bill requires the IRS to provide in real time on its public website the number of callers for each applicable phone number extension that are&#160;(1) connected to speak with an IRS representative, (2) connected to speak with an automated system, and (3) waiting to speak with either an IRS representative or an automated system.

The website also must include

the longest wait time of any caller waiting to speak with an IRS representative;the estimated wait time to speak with an IRS representative;if a callback service is available or when such service is scheduled to be available; andcertain monthly metrics, including the average and median wait times and call lengths.Further, the bill expresses the sense of Congress that, by 2028, the IRS should provide an option to receive a callback for any call that is not answered within five minutes.

Finally, the bill requires the IRS to make available (via website or mobile application) to any taxpayer certain information, including

tax returns, documents, notices, or letters sent to the taxpayer by the IRS or filed with (or sent to) the IRS by the taxpayer;the status of a federal tax return or refund; andan estimated date for receipt of a refund.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-607</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
