<bill session="119" type="s" number="3842" updated="2026-03-04T14:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2026-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">21st Century WIC Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century WIC Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to permit video or telephone certifications under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2026-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-04T14:16:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">21st Century WIC Act of 2026

This bill permanently allows individuals to remotely certify their eligibility for, and receive benefits through, the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC).

Specifically, the bill requires that a state agency allow&#160;an individual seeking a WIC certification, recertification, or a nutritional risk evaluation to do so by phone or through video teleconference, in addition to the in-person option.

A state agency has 90 days to collect data for a nutritional risk evaluation&#160;for a remotely certified individual. Further, a&#160;state agency may consider an applicant who meets the income eligibility standards to be&#160;temporarily eligible on an interim basis&#160;to participate in the program and may certify the individual for immediate participation without waiting for a nutritional risk evaluation.

The bill also allows states to provide benefits on WIC electronic benefit transfer cards through mail or remote issuance instead of requiring participants to pick up or reload benefits in person at a WIC office.

Further, the Department of Agriculture must report to Congress about the use of remote technologies and other digital tools in the WIC program.

Currently, individuals are generally required to be physically present to certify their WIC eligibility and receive benefits, with exceptions. The Food and Nutrition Service has temporarily waived these requirements and allowed remote certification and benefits using authorities that were originally provided by laws that were enacted to address&#160;COVID-19.</summary>
</bill>
