<bill session="119" type="s" number="1581" updated="2026-06-12T15:20:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Universal Savings Account Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Universal Savings Account Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create Universal Savings Accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000312" joined="2025-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3186" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-12T15:18:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Universal Savings Account Act of 2025

This bill establishes Universal Savings Accounts, which are tax-advantaged savings accounts that allow contributions up to a certain amount, exempt earnings and distributions from federal income taxes, and allow distributions to be used for any purpose. (Conditions and exceptions apply.)

Specifically, the bill allows cash contributions to a Universal Savings Account of up to $10,000 in 2025 (maximum base contribution), excluding qualified amounts rolled over from another tax-advantaged account (e.g., individual retirement account).&#160;The maximum base contribution amount is increased by $500 each year beginning in 2026 and adjusted annually for inflation, up to a total maximum contribution of $25,000 (also adjusted annually for inflation beginning in 2026).

Under the bill, earnings and distributions from a Universal Savings Account are excluded from gross income for federal tax purposes and, thus, are not subject to federal income&#160;taxes (similar to the federal tax treatment of distributions from a Roth individual retirement account). (Some exceptions apply.)

Further, distributions from such accounts are not restricted and may be used for any purpose (unlike other types of tax-advantaged accounts currently available).

The bill also imposes&#160;

a federal excise tax on contributions to a Universal Savings Account in excess of the applicable contribution limit,a federal&#160;excise tax on certain transactions involving a Universal Savings Account and disqualified persons,certain reporting requirements on Universal Savings Account trustees, anda federal excise tax for failing to meet such reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
