<bill session="119" type="h" number="8464" updated="2026-06-09T23:06:22Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Fraudulent Payments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Stopping Fraudulent Payments Act</title>
    <title type="display">Stopping Fraudulent Payments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to authorize pausing and segmenting payments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001108"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000375" joined="2026-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2026-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 119-684.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-06-03" calendar="Union" number="597">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 597.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T19:22:01-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1345 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8312, H.R. 8464, H. Res. 1335 and S. 2. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8312, H.R. 8464, H. Res. 1335, and S. 2 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for a motion to recommit H.R. 8312 and H.R. 8464 and a motion to commit S. 2.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1345" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-05T19:14:42Z" status="Reported to House">Stopping Fraudulent Payments Act

This bill establishes requirements to prevent fraudulent or improper payments from federal programs.

Specifically, the bill directs executive agencies to take corrective actions to temporarily pause, condition, or segment payment voucher requests before certifying them if the agencies have sufficient reason to determine that the payments present elevated risks of fraud or improper payments resulting in financial loss to the government. The corrective actions must be (1) based on objective, documented fraud-risk indicators; (2) narrowly applied to the portion of the payments presenting the elevated risk; and (3) limited in duration to the minimum period necessary to verify the eligibility or accuracy of the payments.

The Department of the Treasury must return certified payment vouchers to agencies for corrective action if they present an elevated risk of fraud based on an output of Treasury&#8217;s Do Not Pay system.

The bill also prohibits officers or employees of the federal government from being personally liable for actions taken in good faith under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-684</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
