<bill session="119" type="h" number="7855" updated="2026-04-03T16:03:36Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to expand access to school-wide arts and music programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">GAAME Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GAAME Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guarantee Access to Arts and Music Education Act of 2026</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2026-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2026-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2026-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001229" joined="2026-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2026-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2026-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="4018" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-03T16:03:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Guarantee Access to Arts and Music Education Act of 2026 or the GAAME Act of 2026

This bill specifies that funds that support the instructional needs of elementary and secondary students from low-income families (i.e., Title I funds) may be used for arts and music programs.

First, the bill specifies that schools operating school-wide programs may include descriptions related to arts and music education in their comprehensive plans. Such a plan may include a description of (1) how sequential, standards-based arts education taught by certified educators and providers meet the challenging state academic standards, and (2) how sequential, standards-based music education taught by certified educators align with the challenging state academic standards.

Second, the bill specifies that schools operating targeted assistance programs may use funds for arts and music programs that address the academic needs of students. This assistance may include providing support for certified educators, professional development, supplies, instruments, and other expenses.</summary>
</bill>
