<bill session="119" type="h" number="1077" updated="2026-03-07T09:06:38Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STEAM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEAM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining Thermal Energy through Advanced Mechanisms Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to expedite geothermal exploration and development in previously studied or developed areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000605" joined="2025-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001228" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2026-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="456" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-01-05T14:44:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Streamlining Thermal Energy through Advanced Mechanisms Act or the STEAM Act

This bill expedites the environmental review of certain geothermal energy activities under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). Specifically, the bill expands&#160;the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to include certain geothermal exploration or development activities in an existing categorical exclusion from NEPA for certain oil or gas activities.&#160;

A&#160;categorical exclusion applies to a class of actions that do not require an environmental assessment nor an environmental impact statement under NEPA.

The categorical exclusion established by the bill applies to&#160;drilling a geothermal well (1) in an area where drilling has occurred previously within the five years prior to the date when drilling begins; or (2) within a developed field for which an approved land use plan or environmental document prepared under NEPA determined drilling to be a reasonably foreseeable activity, so long as the plan or document was approved within the five years prior to the date when drilling begins.</summary>
</bill>
