<bill session="119" type="h" number="4054" updated="2026-06-11T05:06:24Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accreditation Choice and Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Accreditation Choice and Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="display">Accreditation Choice and Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reform accreditation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000484"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001233" joined="2025-07-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Workforce. H. Rept. 119-414.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-12-18" calendar="Union" number="360">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 360.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-10T16:21:01Z" status="Reported to House">Accreditation Choice and Innovation Act

This bill revises the accreditation process for reviewing the quality of education offered by institutions of higher education (IHEs).

Under current law, an IHE seeking to participate in many federal programs (e.g., federal student aid programs) must be accredited by an agency recognized by the Department of Education (ED) as a reliable authority on the quality of the education being offered at the IHE. An ED-recognized accrediting agency must meet various provisions under the Higher Education Act of 1965 and in regulations.

Under this bill, states may designate an entity (e.g., an industry-specific quality assurance entity) as an accrediting agency for programs or IHEs in the state. The bill outlines the requirements for the state to submit a plan to ED and for ED to respond to the plan.&#160;

Additionally, the bill provides an accelerated path to recognition by authorizing ED to recognize new accrediting agencies within two years of their application.&#160;

ED must convene a panel of experts to develop common terminology for accrediting agencies to use in making accrediting decisions and publish those recommendations.

Further, the bill (1) requires accrediting agencies to establish specified standards for measures assessing student success (e.g., labor market outcomes), and (2) requires accrediting agencies to establish procedures for assessing compliance with agency standards that reflect an IHE's risk of losing accreditation.

The bill reauthorizes through September 30, 2028, and revises the National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity, which advises ED on matters related to accreditation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-414</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
