<bill session="119" type="h" number="6978" updated="2026-06-11T23:26:35Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Integrity in Immigration Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Preserving Integrity in Immigration Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="display">Preserving Integrity in Immigration Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services to conduct a review of certain approved immigration benefit requests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000475"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 119-465.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-01-27" calendar="Union" number="398">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 398.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-06T21:30:33Z" status="Reported to House">Preserving Integrity in Immigration Benefits Act

This bill requires the U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) to review certain approved immigration benefit requests for proper approval. The review must include requests approved during the period starting on January 20, 2021, and ending on the date of enactment of this bill.&#160;

Immigration benefit requests covered by this bill include those conferred during this period to individuals from the following countries: Angola, Afghanistan, Antigua and Barbuda, Benin, Burkina Faso, Burma, Burundi, Chad, the Republic of the Congo, Cote d'Ivoire, Cuba, Dominica, Equatorial Guinea, Eritrea, Gabon, the Gambia, Haiti, Iran, Laos, Libya, Malawi, Mali, Mauritania, Niger, Nigeria, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Somalia, Sudan, South Sudan, Syria, Tanzania, Togo, Tonga, Turkmenistan, Venezuela, Yemen, Zambia, and Zimbabwe. This also includes individuals traveling using documents issued or endorsed by the Palestinian Authority.

The bill requires USCIS to report on any findings by September 15, 2026.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-465</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
