<bill session="119" type="s" number="1787" updated="2026-03-24T12:48:03Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dolores River National Conservation Area and Special Management Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dolores River National Conservation Area and Special Management Area Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Dolores River National Conservation Area and the Dolores River Special Management Area in the State of Colorado, to protect private water rights in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2025-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-11T00:15:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dolores River National Conservation Area and Special Management Area Act

This bill establishes the Dolores River National Conservation Area and the Dolores River Special Management Area in Colorado to protect certain natural, recreational, scenic, cultural, historical, and other values of the areas.

The conservation area must&#160;consist of approximately 52,872 acres of Bureau of Land Management land. The special management area must consist of&#160;approximately 15,452 acres of federal land in the San Juan National Forest.

A management plan must be developed for each area. The&#160;bill directs the Department of the Interior to allow for the continued use of the areas by members of Indian tribes for traditional ceremonies and as a source of traditional plants and other materials.

Additionally, Interior must manage the&#160;portions of the&#160;areas identified as Ponderosa Gorge in a manner that maintains its wilderness character, including by prohibiting (1) road construction; (2) the use of motor vehicles, motorized equipment, or mechanical transport; and (3) projects undertaken for the purpose of harvesting commercial timber.

Interior must also establish the Dolores River National Conservation Area Advisory Council.

Finally, the bill releases segments of the Dolores River inside the areas from further study for potential addition to the Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</summary>
</bill>
