<bill session="119" type="h" number="7892" updated="2026-06-04T15:36:22Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Aid for Ghost Students Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">No Aid for Ghost Students Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="display">No Aid for Ghost Students Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require to the Secretary of Education to use an identity fraud detection system to review each FAFSA to determine whether the FAFSA presents a reasonable suspicion of identity fraud.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000086"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2026-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2026-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2026-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2026-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-26">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Workforce. H. Rept. 119-669.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-05-26" calendar="Union" number="583">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 583.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T09:18:44-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1333 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8646, H.R. 7726, H.R. 7892 and H.R. 8872. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8646 under a structured rule and H.R. 7726, H.R. 7892, and H.R. 8872 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each bill. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="4428" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1333" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-01T16:08:45Z" status="Reported to House">No Aid for Ghost Students Act of 2026

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to establish an identity fraud detection system for the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA).

Beginning on October 1, 2026, ED must use an identity fraud detection system to review each submitted application to determine whether the applicant presents a reasonable suspicion of identity fraud. If ED makes such a determination, it must notify the applicant and each institution of higher education (IHE) designated on the application that the applicant is subject to additional identity verification.

An IHE may not disburse federal financial aid to an applicant that presents a reasonable suspicion of fraud unless the IHE verifies the applicant's identity in person or by live video. If the applicant's identity is confirmed, the IHE must notify ED that the applicant's identity has been verified.

ED must establish guidelines for the identity verification procedures conducted by IHEs.

(On April 26, 2026, ED began implementing a real-time identity fraud detection process within the FAFSA form that places applicants into one of four risk categories. High-risk applicants must confirm their identity by presenting documentation during the online application process, including via a live camera process. Applicants who are rejected via this automated process must then have their identity verified in person by IHEs.)</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-669</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
