<bill session="119" type="h" number="5995" updated="2026-06-24T13:42:46Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Have You Served Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Have You Served Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of carrying out Ask the Question Campaigns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2025-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2025-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-24T13:38:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Have You Served Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide grants to certain states (including U.S. territories and possessions and the District of Columbia), American Indian tribes, or Alaska Native tribes to carry out campaigns to encourage human services professionals, state and local governments, and community providers to ask consumers whether they or a loved one have served in the Armed Forces. To be eligible, a state, American Indian tribe, or Alaska Native tribe must develop and submit a veteran suicide prevention plan to the VA.

Such grants must be used for training about (1) how to appropriately ask consumers whether they or a loved one have served in the Armed Forces, and (2) resources available through the VA or other providers for members of the Armed Forces and veterans to encourage the trained individuals to&#160;refer consumers to such resources.

The VA must also develop a plan to work with each federal department and agency to implement similar campaigns.</summary>
</bill>
