<bill session="119" type="h" number="2616" updated="2026-05-01T21:11:24Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parental Rights Over The Education and Care of Their Kids Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Kids Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Parental Rights Over The Education and Care of Their Kids Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">PROTECT Kids Act</title>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Kids Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require public elementary and middle schools that receive funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to obtain parental consent before changing a minor's gender markers, pronouns, or preferred name on any school form or sex-based accommodations, including locker rooms or bathrooms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000177" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2025-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-13">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Workforce. H. Rept. 119-441.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-01-13" calendar="Union" number="377">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 377.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29T08:12:07-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1224 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7567, H.R. 2616, S. Con. Res. 33, S. 1318 and H.R. 1346. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 7567 under a structured rule and H.R. 2616, S. Con. Res. 33, S. 1318, and H.R. 1346 under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on H.R. 7567, H.R. 2616, and H.R. 1346, and one motion to commit on S. 1318.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1224" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-23T20:07:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Parental Rights Over The Education and Care of Their Kids Act or the PROTECT Kids Act

This bill requires public elementary and middle schools, as a condition of receiving certain federal funds for elementary and secondary education, to obtain parental consent before changing a student's gender on school forms or changing a student's sex-based accommodations.

Specifically, an elementary school or a school consisting of only grades 5-8 must obtain parental consent before changing a minor student's (1) gender markers, pronouns, or preferred name on any school form; or (2) sex-based accommodations, including locker rooms or bathrooms.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-441</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
