<bill session="119" type="h" number="7084" updated="2026-03-26T08:06:44Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending American Property Abroad Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Defending American Property Abroad Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="display">Defending American Property Abroad Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, with respect to the types of vessels that may enter or operate in navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2026-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000246" joined="2026-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2026-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001239" joined="2026-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2026-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2026-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001220" joined="2026-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 36 - 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 119-563.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-03-20" calendar="Union" number="484">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 484.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T19:55:44-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1131 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8029, H. Res. 1128, H.R. 5103 and H.R. 7084. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8029, H. Res. 1128, H.R. 5103, and H.R. 7084 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on H.R. 8029, H.R. 5103, and H.R. 7084.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-25T14:06:38-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1131 passed House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1131" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-24T14:27:35Z" status="Reported to House">Defending American Property Abroad Act of 2026

This bill authorizes the President to prohibit the entry of a vessel into the United States if the vessel has transited any U.S. port, harbor, or marine terminal that has been nationalized or expropriated (e.g., seized) by a Western Hemisphere country that has a free trade agreement with the United States.&#160;

Under the bill, the President may prohibit the entry and operation of a vessel if it has called at any port, harbor, or marine terminal that was&#160;owned, held, or controlled by a U.S. entity or individual, but has been nationalized or expropriated by the government of a country that is located in the&#160;Western Hemisphere and has a free trade agreement in effect with the United States.

The prohibition ends when the President determines that (1) the applicable country has restored ownership of the property that had been nationalized or expropriated, (2) the applicable country has provided mutually acceptable compensation for&#160;the nationalized or expropriated property, (3) the conditions for the prohibition are no longer satisfied, or (4)&#160;the dispute has been otherwise resolved to the satisfaction of the President.&#160;

The bill permits certain foreign vessels that are otherwise prohibited from entering the United States under this bill or current law to enter if the vessel is experiencing an emergency (involving the vessel or an individual on the vessel)&#160;and in certain instances where access to a covered facility was granted by a U.S. property owner.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-563</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
