<bill session="119" type="h" number="8029" updated="2026-03-26T16:36:15Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pay Our Homeland Defenders Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Our Homeland Defenders Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T19:55:44-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1131 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8029, H. Res. 1128, H.R. 5103 and H.R. 7084. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8029, H. Res. 1128, H.R. 5103, and H.R. 7084 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on H.R. 8029, H.R. 5103, and H.R. 7084.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7147" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4213" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7744" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1131" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-23T13:19:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Pay Our Homeland Defenders Act

This bill provides appropriations to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for the remainder of FY2026. It also ends the partial DHS shutdown that began on February 14, 2026, because the continuing resolution (CR) that was funding DHS expired and a regular FY2026 DHS appropriations bill had not been enacted.&#160;

Specifically, the bill provides appropriations to DHS for Departmental Management, Intelligence, Situational Awareness, and Oversight, including

the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management;the Management Directorate;Intelligence, Analysis, and Situational Awareness; andthe Office of Inspector General.In addition, the bill provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations, including

U.S. Customs and Border Protection,U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement,the Transportation Security Administration,the U.S. Coast Guard, andthe U.S. Secret Service.The bill provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery, including

the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, andthe Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).The bill provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services, including

U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services,the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers, andthe Science and Technology Directorate.The bill also authorizes back pay, in accordance with current law, for federal employees who were affected by the partial&#160;DHS shutdown.

Finally, the bill ratifies and&#160;approves certain obligations that were incurred during the partial DHS&#160;shutdown, including obligations incurred to maintain the essential level of activity to protect life and property and bring about an orderly termination of government functions.</summary>
</bill>
