<bill session="119" type="h" number="3292" updated="2026-04-16T14:44:09Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reviewing Economic and Protection Objectives for Reciprocal Tariffs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the publication of a detailed justification with respect to certain tariff modifications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001100" joined="2025-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-16T14:42:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Reviewing Economic and Protection Objectives for Reciprocal Tariffs Act or the REPORT Act

This bill requires public and congressional&#160;notification of certain increases or decreases in a duty&#160;(i.e., tariff) imposed by the President on articles imported into the United States.&#160;

Specifically, the President must publish information in the Federal Register within 48 hours of increasing or decreasing a duty on articles imported into the United States&#160;pursuant to a law or regulation authorizing modifications to duties on an emergency or discretionary basis. This publication must include (1) notice of such determination, and (2) a detailed justification for such increase or decrease.

Additionally, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative must brief specified congressional committees within seven days of the President making a determination to modify a duty. The briefing must include the justification for the President's determination.</summary>
</bill>
