<bill session="119" type="s" number="1711" updated="2026-05-28T20:20:26Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP China Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Transit Operations to Prohibit China Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP China Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address national security risks and prohibit the use of Federal funds for the procurement of certain vehicles and vehicle technologies produced or provided by entities based in certain countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2025-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2025-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2025-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2025-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2025-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2025-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4361" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-28T20:19:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safeguarding Transit Operations to Prohibit China Act or the STOP China Act&#160;

This bill prohibits federal transportation funds from being used to purchase rolling stock (e.g., rail cars or buses) or fueling or charging infrastructure from entities with ties to China, North Korea, Russia, or Iran (i.e.,&#160;a covered nation). In general, this replaces a current prohibition on the use of Federal Transportation Administration (FTA)&#160;funds for rolling stock from manufacturers owned or controlled by corporations based in certain countries.

Specifically, Department of Transportation (DOT)&#160;funds, which include&#160;FTA funds,&#160;may not be used&#160;for the purchase of rolling stock&#160;or bus fueling or charging infrastructure from entities with ties to a covered nation. This prohibition also applies to&#160;vehicles that incorporate electric power trains from such entities.

The prohibition broadly applies to corporations, joint ventures, individuals, and organizations with ties to covered nations.&#160;Examples of applicable entities include an individual whose activities are directed or financed by a covered nation or an entity that is owned or controlled by a covered nation or such an individual.

The United States Trade Representative (USTR) must publish a list of the applicable entities and update the list annually.

The bill includes an exception for motor vehicles or fueling and charging stations used for (1) inspecting or investigating vehicles or equipment; or (2) vehicle safety research, development, or testing.</summary>
</bill>
