<bill session="119" type="s" number="1941" updated="2026-05-27T20:42:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cure Hepatitis C Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cure Hepatitis C Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out activities to eliminate hepatitis C virus in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2025-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-27T20:37:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cure Hepatitis C Act of 2025

This bill establishes programs and requirements to provide free medications to treat hepatitis C in certain high-risk or vulnerable populations. It also establishes grants and other resources to support testing and treatment for hepatitis C. The bill provides funding for FY2025 to implement these provisions.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must enter into a five-year purchasing contract with manufacturers of drugs&#160;that treat hepatitis C so that eligible individuals may receive the drugs&#160;without cost-sharing.&#160;Eligible individuals are&#160;those diagnosed with&#160;hepatitis C who are (1) enrolled in Medicaid or the Children&#8217;s Health Insurance Program (CHIP), (2) confined to federal, state, or local correctional facilities (or&#160;were released and began&#160;treatment there), (3) uninsured, or (4) receiving health care through the Indian Health Service.

Eligibility&#160;is limited to those with specified legal immigration statuses. State Medicaid and CHIP programs and state and local correctional facilities may opt into the program; participation is mandatory for federal correctional facilities and the Indian Health Service.&#160;

HHS must award grants to certain entities, including states, public health organizations, and correctional facilities, to support the coordination and provision of screening, treatment, and supportive services for the affected populations.&#160;

The bill also allows Medicare beneficiaries to receive hepatitis C drugs without cost-sharing from 2027-2031.</summary>
</bill>
