<bill session="119" type="h" number="1148" updated="2026-03-02T15:23:49Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMARTER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMARTER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Misappropriating Ratepayer Tariffs for Excessive Resources Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to require States to consider prohibiting cost recovery related to smart grid projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-02T15:23:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Misappropriating&#160;Ratepayer Tariffs for Excessive Resources Act or the SMARTER Act

This bill requires nonregulated utilities and state regulators of utilities to consider implementing a standard&#160;to prohibit electric utilities from recovering costs relating to the deployment of any smart grid system from their consumers. It also repeals the current requirement for states to consider authorizing electric utilities to recover costs relating to the deployment of certain smart grid systems from their consumers.

Within a year, each nonregulated&#160;utility and state regulatory authority must consider adopting the prohibition. Within two years, they must determine whether or not to implement the prohibition. However, the deadlines do not apply if a state has already considered or implemented a comparable standard.</summary>
</bill>
