<bill session="119" type="h" number="8466" updated="2026-06-09T08:06:21Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-08T18:57:18-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-08T18:57:18-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRUE Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="display">TRUE Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain agencies to develop plans for internal control in the event of an emergency or crisis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001230" joined="2026-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 40 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T14:56:24-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gill (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T14:56:38-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T14:56:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 8466.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T15:05:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T15:06:08-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T18:31:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="208" datetime="2026-06-08T18:57:18-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 384 - 0 (Roll no. 208).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T18:57:20-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-03T22:01:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act or the TRUE Accountability Act

This bill requires agencies to develop and implement plans for preventing fraud and improper payments relating to federal emergency spending (e.g., providing funding relating to disasters or pandemics).

The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) must issue, and review every three years, guidance to agencies for developing plans with appropriate internal controls. The guidance must incorporate the current Government Accountability Office frameworks for managing fraud risk in federal programs and managing improper payments in federal emergency assistance.

Within one year after the bill&#8217;s enactment, agencies must submit to&#160;OMB plans required by the guidance. Each plan must include procedures to (1) evaluate the risk of financial loss to the federal government caused by improper payments and fraud relating to the agency&#8217;s federal emergency spending; (2) develop risk reduction strategies that are, to the extent possible, implemented prior to expenditure; and (3) adopt payment monitoring to identify and reduce improper and fraudulent payments (e.g., anomaly detection). Agencies must revise and resubmit plans, as necessary, at least every three years.

OMB must annually submit the plans to Congress along with information relating to helping agencies implement the plans and legislative recommendations for emergency appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
