<bill session="119" type="h" number="1789" updated="2026-05-21T17:06:58Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promptly Ending Political Prosecutions and Executive Retaliation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promptly Ending Political Prosecutions and Executive Retaliation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Promptly Ending Political Prosecutions and Executive Retaliation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28, United States Code, to clarify the removability of certain actions against current and former Presidents and other senior Executive officials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000478"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 14 - 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 119-28.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-03-21" calendar="Union" number="18">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 18.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-21T17:04:00Z" status="Reported to House">Promptly Ending Political Prosecutions and Executive Retaliation Act of 2025

This bill expands the types of federal officials who may remove (i.e., transfer) state cases brought against them to federal court.&#160;It also&#160;establishes a presumption of immunity for federal officials in these cases.

The federal officer removal statute authorizes certain defendants&#160;(e.g., federal officers) to remove to federal court a civil action or criminal prosecution brought against them in state court&#160;if the claims or charges relate to official duties. Often, defendants who invoke the federal officer removal statute raise claims of official immunity.

In recent years, the statute received public attention when then-former President Donald Trump and former officials sought to invoke the statute. For example, in Georgia v. Meadows, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit&#160;held that former White House Chief of Staff Mark Meadows could not remove Georgia&#8217;s criminal prosecution of him to federal court based on the federal officer removal statute because it does not apply to former federal officers, and even if it did, the charges were not related to Meadows&#8217;s official duties.

This bill allows&#160;a defendant&#160;who is a former federal officer&#160;or current or former President or Vice President&#160;to remove state cases brought against them to federal court based on the federal officer removal statute.&#160;It&#160;also establishes a presumption that federal officials have immunity in cases that are removable, which may only be rebutted by a showing that their actions were not related to official duties.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-28</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
