<bill session="119" type="s" number="2701" updated="2026-04-15T20:51:52Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Headwaters Protection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Headwaters Protection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to reauthorize and improve the Water Source Protection Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2025-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="605" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-15T20:51:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Headwaters Protection Act of 2025

This bill reauthorizes through FY2034 and expands the Water Source Protection Program (WSPP) under which the Forest Service carries out watershed protection and restoration projects on federal land. It also requires the Forest Service's Watershed Condition Framework for National Forest System land to ensure certain activities and authorizations do not result in long-term degradation of the health of a watershed.

The bill authorizes the WSPP to support projects on state, local, or private land that is adjacent to projects on National Forest System land, so long as (1) the adjacent land is within the same watershed as the project on federal land, and (2) the owner of the adjacent land supports the project.

Further, the bill expands the types of&#160;end water users that may participate in the program to include (1) an&#160;acequia association (an organization that manages traditional irrigation systems found in the Southwest); (2) a public entity that manages water infrastructure, such as stormwater or wastewater resources; (3) certain land grant entities in New Mexico called land-grant&#160;mercedes; and (4) a local, regional, or other private entity that has water delivery authority.

The bill requires projects under the program to (1) protect and restore watershed health, water supply and quality, a municipal or agricultural water supply system, and water-related infrastructure; (2) protect and restore forest health from insect infestation and disease or wildfire; or (3) advance any combination of those purposes.

Additionally, the bill reduces the cost share for nonfederal WSPP participants.</summary>
</bill>
