<bill session="119" type="s" number="1620" updated="2026-02-25T20:28:44Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MEME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MEME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modern Emoluments and Malfeasance Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 131 of title 5, United States Code, with respect to prohibited financial transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2025-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2025-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-25T20:28:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Modern Emoluments and Malfeasance Enforcement Act or the MEME Act

This bill prohibits the President, the Vice&#160;President, Members of Congress, those holding Senior Executive Service positions, admirals, generals, and other federal public officials from engaging in or benefiting from the issuance, sponsorship, or promotion of certain assets. The spouse and dependent children of such an official are also covered by the prohibition.

Assets covered by the bill are securities, security futures, commodities, digital assets such as cryptocurrency or a meme coin, as well as derivatives, options, warrants, mutual funds, or exchange traded funds of the preceding assets.

The prohibition applies to (1) such officials during their term of service and for 180&#160;days prior to and after their service, and (2) the spouse and dependent children of such an official during that same period.

Civil and criminal penalties under the bill include disgorging (giving) to the Treasury any profits from prohibited transactions, fines, and imprisonment for up to five years. The bill provides additional penalties for such prohibited activities if they involve bribery or insider trading.

The U.S. Office of Special Counsel may also determine that federal employees or officers serving in other positions are covered by the prohibition.</summary>
</bill>
