<bill session="119" type="h" number="8107" updated="2026-06-04T14:35:45Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Government Audit and Accountability of Federally Funded State-Administered Programs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Audit and Accountability of Federally Funded State-Administered Programs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the establishment of a list identifying program areas and administrative practices presenting the greatest risk to the integrity of Federal funds administered by States and local governments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000389"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001309" joined="2026-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 41 - 0.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-04T14:34:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Government Audit and Accountability of Federally Funded State-Administered Programs Act

This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on federally funded state-administered programs (including programs subject to federal single audit requirements)&#160;that are at high risk for waste, fraud, and abuse.

Specifically, the report must

identify program areas and administrative practices that make such programs systematically vulnerable to waste, fraud, and abuse;assess best practices that strengthen the administration of federally funded programs and prevent such vulnerabilities;identify federal tools, resources, and assistance to address vulnerability patterns; andinclude recommendations for addressing high-risk program areas and administrative practices.</summary>
</bill>
