<bill session="119" type="h" number="5248" updated="2026-06-09T20:14:18Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-08T17:18:33-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-08T17:18:33-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the alignment of economic and foreign policies, to position the Department of State to reflect that economic security is national security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To ensure the alignment of economic and foreign policies, to position the Department of State to reflect that economic security is national security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2025-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2025-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:17:10-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mast moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:17:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3970-3974" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:17:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5248.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-06-08T17:18:33-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3970-3974" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:18:34-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-05T20:42:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill restructures the Department of State's Office of the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs, dividing the office into four bureaus and two offices. (The current structure is here.)&#160;The bill also specifies the functions of these organizations and the responsibilities of the organizations' leaders.&#160;

Under the bill, the following organizations fall under the Office of the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs:

the Bureau of Commercial Diplomacy covers trade and investment promotion and policy, international finance and development, and transportation affairs;the Bureau of Water, Environment, and Space Affairs covers space, oceans, environmental quality, fisheries, wildlife, wildlife trafficking, and conservation affairs;the Bureau of Energy Security and Diplomacy formulates and implements international energy, energy technology, critical minerals, and relevant supply chain policies;the Bureau of Sanctions Policy develops policies governing the imposition of sanctions and sanctions strategies;the Office of the Chief Economist&#160;provides expert economic advice and analysis; andthe Office of&#160;Subnational Diplomacy enables the department&#8217;s work with state and local governments within the United States to improve the ability of those governments to attract foreign investment, counter foreign malign influence within the United States, and contribute to U.S. foreign policy priorities.An assistant secretary with specified responsibilities leads each of the four bureaus. The heads of the two offices also have specified responsibilities.

The Office of the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs shall administer and oversee the International Technology Security and Innovation Fund, which provides for technology security and semiconductor supply chain activities.</summary>
</bill>
