<bill session="119" type="h" number="1365" updated="2026-03-19T14:30:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">America First Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America First Energy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act to place certain restrictions on members and activities of the Foundation for Energy Security and Innovation of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000806"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001101" joined="2025-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-19T14:22:04Z" status="Introduced in House">America First Energy Act

This bill places certain restrictions on board members and employees of the Foundation for Energy Security and Innovation of the Department of Energy (DOE). The foundation is an independent, agency-related foundation that assists DOE in addressing energy and environmental challenges through science and technology solutions, including by accelerating the development and commercialization of critical energy technologies and fostering public-private partnerships.&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires the foundation's voting&#160;board members, executive director, officers, and employees to be U.S. citizens, U.S. nationals, non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law) admitted as&#160;refugees, or&#160;non-U.S. nationals lawfully admitted for permanent residence.

Finally, the bill directs the foundation to require covered individuals listed on an&#160;application for a research and development award from the foundation to&#160;disclose all current and pending research support received or expected to be received by the individuals. Covered individuals&#160;means individuals who (1)&#160;contribute in a substantive, meaningful way to the scientific development or execution of a research and development project proposed to be carried out with an&#160;award from the foundation; and (2) are designated as a covered individual by the foundation.</summary>
</bill>
