<bill session="119" type="h" number="1237" updated="2026-06-08T17:52:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PANELS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PANELS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Agriculture, Nutrients, and Essential Lands from Solar Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to deny the energy credit to property located on prime or unique farmland, as defined by the Secretary of Agriculture in part 657 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, if such property is used for generating solar energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2026-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000600" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000490" joined="2025-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-08T17:48:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Agriculture, Nutrients, and Essential Lands from Solar Act or the PANELS Act

This bill excludes expenses for solar property placed in service on prime or unique farmland from the energy investment tax credit. The bill also excludes solar facilities placed on prime or unique farmland from the clean electricity production tax credit.

Under current law, businesses may be able to claim an energy investment tax credit for qualified solar property placed into service before January 1, 2025. This bill excludes expenses for solar property placed into service on prime or unique farmland (e.g., land with the best combination of physical and chemical characteristics for the production of food and other related uses)&#160;from the energy investment tax credit.

Further, under current law, a business may also be able to claim the clean electricity production&#160;tax credit for the production of electricity using a&#160;qualified facility that has no greenhouse gas emissions. The amount of the tax credit is based on the amount of electricity produced and sold by a qualified facility placed into service in 2025 or after. This bill modifies the definition of qualified facility to exclude solar facilities placed on prime or unique farmland.</summary>
</bill>
