<bill session="119" type="s" number="1294" updated="2026-06-17T11:03:25Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Firearm Licensee Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Firearm Licensee Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the business of selling firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2026-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2025-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2025-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2025-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2175-2181" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2618" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-20T18:02:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Firearm Licensee Act

This bill establishes new security requirements and expands recordkeeping and reporting requirements for federally licensed dealers, importers, and manufacturers of firearms (i.e., federal firearms licensees, or FFLs). The bill also&#160;broadens the authority of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) to administer federal firearms laws and enforce violations.

Specifically, bill requires FFLs to implement and comply with a plan to secure their business premises, conduct quarterly physical checks of their business inventories, maintain video surveillance of the area where firearms are sold or transferred, and initiate firearms-related background checks for employees.

Additionally,&#160;the bill requires&#160;FFLs to report to the ATF any inventory firearm that is lost, stolen, or unaccounted for&#160;and to notify the ATF about default-proceed transactions (i.e., allowable firearm transfers to an unlicensed person prior to the completion of a background check when the submitted background check remains incomplete after three business days).

Finally, the bill removes limits on the ATF's authority to conduct activities related to the administration of federal firearms laws. It enhances the&#160;ATF's inspection authority, including by removing the limit on the number of annual compliance inspections (currently, one), requiring&#160;inspections of high-risk FFLs, and authorizing an additional 650 investigators. Finally, the bill directs the ATF to deny an application for a federal firearms license if it would endanger public safety or if the applicant is unlikely to comply with the law.</summary>
</bill>
