<bill session="119" type="hc" number="86" updated="2026-06-04T08:08:09Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-03T17:17:24-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-03T17:17:24-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the President, pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution, to remove United States Armed Forces from hostilities with Iran.</title>
    <title type="display">Directing the President, pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution, to remove United States Armed Forces from hostilities with Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001137"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000380" joined="2026-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000604" joined="2026-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2026-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001184" joined="2026-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2026-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-20">
      <text>Submitted in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20T13:29:04-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Mast asked unanimous consent that, it be in order at any time to consider H. Con. Res.86 in the House if called up by the chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs or his designee; that the concurrent resolution be considered as read; and that the previous question be considered as ordered on the concurrent resolution without intervening motion except for one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by Representative Mast of Florida and Representative Meeks of New York, or their respective designees. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20T13:30:20-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a previous order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3647-3648" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20T13:30:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a previous order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3648-3652" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3648" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20T13:30:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Con. Res. 86.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20T14:16:03-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20T14:16:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Con. Res. 86, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the concurrent resolution and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Meeks demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-02T14:30:49-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Issa asked unanimous consent That, notwithstanding clause 8 of rule XX, further proceedings on the vote by the yeas and nays on the question of adoption of H. Con. Res. 86, may be postponed until the legislative day of June 3, 2026. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T17:09:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="199" datetime="2026-06-03T17:17:24-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 208 (Roll no. 199).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03T17:17:26-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hc" number="40" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hc" number="93" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hc" number="75" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hc" number="103" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-18T13:26:05Z" status="Introduced in House">This concurrent resolution directs the President to remove U.S. Armed Forces from hostilities against Iran unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or a congressional authorization for use of military force against Iran.

Elements of the U.S. Armed Forces needed to defend the United States, an ally, or a partner from imminent attack are not covered by this requirement provided the President complies with a specified provision of the War Powers Resolution. (The provision generally requires the President to remove U.S. Armed Forces from hostilities no more than 60 days after the President notifies or is required to notify Congress of such involvement, unless Congress authorizes such use. For more information on the War Powers Resolution, see&#160;CRS In Focus 13134.)</summary>
</bill>
