<bill session="119" type="h" number="6861" updated="2026-02-24T23:49:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to transfer certain functions of the Department of Labor to the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Consolidating Veteran Employment Services for Improved Performance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consolidating Veteran Employment Services for Improved Performance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-24T23:49:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Consolidating Veteran Employment Services for Improved Performance Act

This bill transfers specified programs from the jurisdiction of the Department of Labor to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and establishes the Office of the Deputy Under Secretary for Veterans Economic Opportunity and Transition to implement such programs.

Specifically, the bill transfers to the VA (1) job counseling, training, and placement services for veterans, (2) federal government employment services for veterans, (3) administration of employment and reemployment rights of members of the uniformed services, and (4) homeless veterans reintegration programs. The VA must include funding requests for such programs in its budget request for FY2028 and each subsequent year.

The transfer of such programs does not affect any suits, proceedings or applications for benefits, services, licenses, permits, certificates, or financial assistance that are pending on the date of the enactment of this bill.

The Office of Management and Budget is authorized to determine the functions (e.g., duties) that are transferred under this bill, and may make additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances as may be necessary to implement this bill.

The bill also (1) modifies state responsibilities regarding the employment of full or part-time veterans&#8217; employment specialists (currently known as veteran employment representatives), and (2) expands the purpose and responsibilities of such specialists.

The VA and Labor must jointly conduct a study and report on the implementation of the transfer of programs and functions and amendments made by this bill.</summary>
</bill>
