<bill session="119" type="s" number="956" updated="2026-03-02T16:16:09Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Customs Facilitation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Customs Facilitation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the entry and processing of merchandise and trade enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2025-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-02T16:15:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Customs Facilitation Act of 2025

This bill revises procedures for customs and trade enforcement and establishes related data and reporting requirements.&#160;

Specifically, the bill provides statutory authority for the Border Interagency Executive Council to enhance coordination&#160;with border management authorities.

The Department of Homeland Security must (1) ensure that a uniform automated platform provides a system to process and release cargo being imported into and exported from the United States, and (2) provide for the continuous modernization of the Automated Commercial Environment (the system through which the trade community reports imports and exports and the government determines admissibility).

The bill allows for an accelerated payment of duty drawbacks (i.e., refunds on duties for imported items that are reexported or destroyed)&#160;for claims in which the claimant has submitted required documentation and obtained a properly executed bond.

The Department of Commerce must issue regulations allowing for the submission of export manifest data prior to departure. Clerical errors in the submission of export data shall generally be exempt from penalties.

The bill establishes requirements for specified agencies to follow when issuing regulations related to data collection for trade enforcement and facilitation.

The Government Accountability Office must submit certain reports, including on the fee schedule of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP).&#160;

Additionally, among other actions,&#160;CBP must (1) notify members of the trade community when it makes changes to the minimum-security criteria for participation in the Customs Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program, and (2) review deadlines for CBP responses to requests.</summary>
</bill>
