<bill session="119" type="s" number="2323" updated="2026-04-08T15:25:13Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEADWAY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Head start Education And Development Workforce Advancement and Yield Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEADWAY Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Head Start Act to permit some teachers in Early Head Start programs to teach while earning a child development associate credential.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000790"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-19">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="336" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-08T15:25:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Head start Education And Development Workforce Advancement and Yield Act or the HEADWAY Act

This bill allows some teachers in Early Head Start programs to teach while in the process of earning their Child Development Associate (CDA) credential and completing training.

Currently, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must ensure that all teachers providing direct services to children and families in Early Head Start centers (1) have a minimum of a CDA credential and have been trained in early childhood development, and (2) have been trained in early childhood development with a focus on infant and toddler development.

The bill revises this requirement by requiring at least one teacher per classroom (instead of all teachers) to have a CDA credential and training. In particular, the bill requires HHS to ensure that (1) each additional teacher providing direct services to children and families is in the process of earning a CDA credential and completing training, and (2) the Early Head Start agency provides a mentor to oversee the progress and guide the work of a teacher who is in the process of earning a CDA credential and completing training.</summary>
</bill>
