<bill session="119" type="h" number="3466" updated="2026-05-22T18:56:50Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Migration, Addressing Reform, and Talent Retention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish a skills-based immigration points system, to focus family-sponsored immigration on spouses and minor children, to eliminate the Diversity Visa Program, to set a limit on the number of refugees admitted annually to the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2408"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-22T18:52:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Migration, Addressing Reform, and Talent Retention Act or the SMART Act

This bill modifies the U.S. immigration system, including by eliminating the diversity and employment-based visa systems, establishing a points-based system, and capping other immigration categories.

The diversity visa program&#8212;which makes visas available to individuals from countries that send fewer immigrants&#8212;is eliminated.

The bill caps annual refugee admission at 50,000. Currently, the President sets annual limits.

The bill limits the current family-sponsored immigration system by lowering the annual cap and narrowing the qualifications by, for example, lowering the&#160;age limit of qualifying children and eliminating siblings as a qualifying relationship. The bill also disqualifies noncitizen parents of adult U.S. citizens from this category and creates a new nonimmigrant visa for such parents. This visa has an initial authorization period of five years and may be extended for additional five-year periods.

The bill also eliminates the employment-based visa system and replaces it with a points-based system. Points are awarded on the basis of characteristics such as age, education, English proficiency, the salary of prospective employment, investment in and management of a new commercial enterprise, and number of dependent children. Visas are awarded to the applicants with the most points (and their immediate family members)&#160;until the annual&#160;cap is reached.

The bill also revises the H-1B visa program to&#160;award visas in order of compensation rate.

The bill also creates a&#160;visa for immigrants who invest at least $5 million into a new commercial enterprise.</summary>
</bill>
