<bill session="119" type="s" number="870" updated="2026-06-12T13:18:30Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native ELDER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Native Elders' Longevity, Dignity, Empowerment, and Respect Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native ELDER Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to enhance the longevity, dignity, empowerment, and respect of older individuals who are Native Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2026-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-28T12:31:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhancing Native Elders' Longevity, Dignity, Empowerment, and Respect Act or the Native ELDER Act

This bill establishes a tribal advisory committee, revises certain grants, and requires reporting related to older (i.e., aged 60 or older)&#160;American Indians, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians.&#160;

Specifically, the bill directs the Administration on Aging (AOA) to establish a tribal advisory committee to provide advice and guidance on matters relating to older Native Americans.

Additionally, the bill specifies that the technical assistance and training programs provided to grant recipients (e.g., tribal organizations providing supportive services) may include topics such as program management, data development and use, basic business skills, grant development, program and service innovations, and staff training and certification.

The bill directs the AOA, when making grants to tribal organizations to provide supportive services for older Native Americans, to prioritize organizations that will use these grants for necessary home modifications that will facilitate the ability of older Native Americans to remain at home.

The&#160;AOA must also report to Congress on (1) the feasibility of modeling the Native American Caregiver Support Program after the Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers, (2) the level of need for in-home services that include accessible home modifications for older Native Americans, and (3) the barriers to Indian tribes accessing programs for older Native Americans. This report must be made publicly available.

The Department of Labor must report to Congress on how recipients of funding under the Senior Community Service Employment Program&#160;are serving older Native Americans.</summary>
</bill>
