<bill session="119" type="h" number="5620" updated="2026-04-14T15:09:05Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prioritizing Offensive Agricultural Disputes and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prioritizing Offensive Agricultural Disputes and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of a task force to identify trade barriers to United States agricultural exports and carry out other related duties.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2025-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000110" joined="2026-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2025-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000595" joined="2025-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2025-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7567" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-12-17T11:41:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Prioritizing Offensive Agricultural Disputes and Enforcement Act

This bill establishes a joint task force to identify and address trade barriers to U.S.&#160;agricultural exports.

Specifically, the bill directs the President to establish the Agricultural Trade Enforcement Task Force. Members of this task force must include employees of the Department of Agriculture's Foreign Agricultural Service and the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative.

The bill requires the task force to (1) identify trade barriers to U.S. agricultural exports that are vulnerable to dispute settlement under the World Trade Organization (WTO) or other trade agreements, (2) develop and implement a strategy for enforcing violations of trade agreements related to those trade barriers, (3) identify like-minded trading partners for specific trade barriers that could act as complainants on disputes that are systemically or economically important to the United States, and (4) submit periodic reports to Congress.

In its initial report, the task force must include a plan for filing a request under the WTO dispute settlement process for consultations&#160;to address India's minimum price supports.</summary>
</bill>
