<bill session="119" type="h" number="5877" updated="2026-03-30T20:28:50Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Combatting Money Laundering in Cyber Crime Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combatting Money Laundering in Cyber Crime Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the authority of the United States Secret Service to investigate various crimes related to digital asset transactions and to counter transnational cyber criminal activity, including unlicensed money transmitting businesses, structured transactions, and fraud against financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000471"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2025-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2025-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2025-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 54 - 0.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1273" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-30T20:28:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Combatting&#160;Money Laundering in Cyber Crime Act of 2025

This bill expands the investigative authority of the U.S. Secret Service, extends reporting requirements related to public-private information sharing, and requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to evaluate existing requirements to combat money laundering and related crimes.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Secret Service to investigate money laundering and structured transactions (i.e., structuring currency transactions to evade currency reporting requirements).

Additionally, the bill extends&#160;the requirement for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) to report on the efforts of the FinCEN Exchange. The FinCEN Exchange is a voluntary public-private information sharing partnership among law enforcement agencies, national security agencies, financial institutions, and FinCEN to combat money laundering and related crimes, including the financing of terrorism.

The bill also extends&#160;the requirement for the U.S. executive director at the International Monetary Fund to support the increased use of the fund's administrative budget to help&#160;members prevent money laundering and the financing of terrorism. The requirement expires on December 20, 2025.

Finally, the bill directs the GAO to report on implementation of provisions of the&#160;Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020 that expanded information sharing with tribal authorities and expanded reporting requirements related to money laundering and terrorist financing. The GAO must&#160;focus on evaluating the ability of law enforcement to identify and deter money laundering in cybercrimes.</summary>
</bill>
