<bill session="119" type="sr" number="377" updated="2025-09-10T17:55:42Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-08">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An executive resolution authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</title>
    <title type="display">An executive resolution authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate. Placed on Senate Executive Calendar under Over, Under the Rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08">
      <text>Placed on Senate Executive Calendar under Over, Under the Rule. Calendar No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Point of order by Senator Schumer that the motion to proceed to Executive Calendar No. 1, S.Res. 377, is not in order because legislation that provides for the en bloc consideration of individual nominations is legislative business and such resolution should be required to be considered in legislative session raised in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>The Chair, under the provisions of Rule XX, submits the question to the Senate for its decision: Is a resolution for the en bloc consideration of specific nominations on the executive calendar requireed to be considered in legislative session?.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Motion to table the point of order made by Senator Schumer, the question being: Is a resolution for the en bloc consideration of specific nominations on the executive calendar required to be considered in legislative session? agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53 - 46. Record Vote Number: 510.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Ruling of the Chair that the point of order raised by Senator Schumer that a resolution for the en bloc consideration of specific nominations on the executive calendar required to be considered in legislative session not sustained.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Motion to proceed to executive session to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53 - 45. Record Vote Number: 511.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Cloture motion on the measure presented in Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-10T17:55:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate"></summary>
</bill>
