<bill session="119" type="h" number="2694" updated="2026-05-18T13:09:48Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Election Results Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Results Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish deadlines for States to count the ballots cast in elections for Federal office and to certify the results of elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000480" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2025-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2025-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-18T13:09:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Election Results Accountability Act

This bill establishes deadlines for states to count ballots and certify results in federal elections.&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires a state to count not less than 90% of the ballots cast in a federal election held in the state not later than 72 hours after polls close and make the result of the count publicly available. Further, the state must certify and make publicly available the complete election results not later than two weeks after the election.&#160;

The bill provides exceptions to these deadlines, including for bona fide emergencies (e.g., major disasters) or technical difficulties (e.g., malfunctioning election equipment or software).

The bill prohibits a state from receiving federal election administration funds for subsequent elections if the state does not comply with the deadlines established by the bill. However, a state may regain eligibility for these funds if (1) the state submits a compliance plan to the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) and the Department of Justice (DOJ), and (2) the EAC and DOJ each certify that the state has taken actions to comply with the plan.</summary>
</bill>
