<bill session="119" type="s" number="2016" updated="2026-03-24T12:48:03Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Chugach Alaska Land Exchange Oil Spill Recovery Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chugach Alaska Land Exchange Oil Spill Recovery Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to exchange non-Federal land held by the Chugach Alaska Corporation for certain Federal Land in the Chugach Region, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3903" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-10T20:17:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Chugach Alaska Land Exchange Oil Spill Recovery Act of 2025

This bill authorizes a land exchange&#160;between the Chugach Alaska Corporation (also known as Chugach, an Alaska Native regional corporation in&#160;southcentral Alaska) and the federal government.

Specifically, if Chugach offers to convey to the Department of the Interior all rights, title, and interest of Chugach in and to approximately 231,000 acres of subsurface estate within one year of the bill's enactment, then Interior must accept the offer and convey in exchange all rights, title, and interest of the federal government in and to approximately 65,374 acres of fee simple land located in the Chugach region. (The Chugach region includes portions of land on the Kenai Peninsula and the coast of Prince William Sound in Alaska.)

The bill directs Chugach to exclude from its conveyance to Interior all rights, title, and interest in any land, not to exceed a total of 209 acres, for which a village&#160;corporation has retained development rights (other than timber development rights) or that has been designated for a shareholder&#160;homesite program.</summary>
</bill>
