<bill session="119" type="s" number="3475" updated="2026-04-08T15:20:09Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize, ratify, and confirm the Agreement of Settlement and Compromise to Resolve the Akwesasne Mohawk Land Claim in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to authorize, ratify, and confirm the Agreement of Settlement and Compromise to Resolve the Akwesasne Mohawk Land Claim in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2026-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2916" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-08T15:19:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill recognizes and settles the Akwesasne land claim in northern New York. (Akwesasne is a Mohawk territory that extends into the United States and Canada, specifically New York, Ontario, and Quebec.)

The bill authorizes, ratifies, and confirms a specified settlement agreement entered into by the Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe (SRMT), the Mohawk Council of&#160;Akwesasne, the State of New York, Franklin and Saint Lawrence Counties in New York, the towns of Fort Covington and Bombay in New York, and the New York Power Authority. (Among its provisions, the settlement agreement restores land rights and provides access to land to SRMT, provides&#160;tuition assistance for tribal members to certain postsecondary institutions, and requires the New York Power Authority to make annual payments to&#160;SRMT.)

Additionally, the bill authorizes, ratifies, and confirms any transfer of land, right-of-way, or easement that is the subject of claims in specified court cases.

The bill also recognizes as Indian country any land owned or subsequently acquired by SRMT within the settlement acquisition areas. (The term Indian country, for purposes of criminal jurisdiction, generally refers to all lands within a tribal reservation, dependent Indian communities, and tribal allotments.)</summary>
</bill>
