<bill session="119" type="h" number="7266" updated="2026-06-30T15:08:17Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-29T16:35:44-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-29T16:35:44-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural and Municipal Utility Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Rural and Municipal Utility Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Rural and Municipal Utility Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to reauthorize the Rural and Municipal Utility Advanced Cybersecurity Grant and Technical Assistance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001086" joined="2026-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2026-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 119-629.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-30" calendar="Union" number="545">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 545.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:25:45-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Guthrie moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:25:53-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4299-4300" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:25:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7266.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-06-29T16:35:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4299" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:35:46-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-25T13:37:51Z" status="Reported to House">Rural and Municipal Utility Cybersecurity Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2030 a program that provides cybersecurity-related assistance and funding to rural electric cooperatives and municipal or small, investor-owned electric utilities. The bill also revises methods of awarding support and expands protections for information shared under the program.

This program, known as the Rural and Municipal Advanced Cybersecurity Grant and Technical Assistance Program, is administered by the Department of Energy (DOE). Current law requires DOE to provide technical assistance and funding under the program on a competitive basis; under the bill, assistance and funding may be provided on a competitive&#160;or noncompetitive basis.

Current law also requires DOE to prioritize providing technical assistance and funding to certain entities, including entities that own defense critical electric infrastructure. The bill specifies that DOE must also prioritize entities that operate such infrastructure. (Defense critical electric infrastructure is electric infrastructure that (1) is located in the contiguous United States, and (2) serves a designated critical defense facility but is not owned or operated by the owner or operator of the critical facility.)

Finally, the bill expands an existing protection against disclosure to cover all information shared under the program by or with the federal government or a state, tribal, or local government. This provision protects against disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act and other state, tribal, or local disclosure laws.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-629</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
