<bill session="119" type="h" number="8595" updated="2026-05-13T14:23:38Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-30">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Security, Department of State, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2027</title>
    <title type="display">National Security, Department of State, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2027</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for national security, Department of State, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2027, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 119-631, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-30" calendar="Union" number="547">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 547.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-05T15:41:50Z" status="Reported to House">National Security, Department of State, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2027

This bill provides FY2027 appropriations for national security, the Department of State, and related programs.

The bill provides appropriations to the State Department for

Administration of Foreign Affairs,International Organizations, andInternational Commissions.The bill provides appropriations for related programs, including

the Asia Foundation,the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund,the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship Program,the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program,the East-West Center, andthe National Endowment for Democracy.The bill provides appropriations for other commissions, including

the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad,the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom,the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe,the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China, and&#160;the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission.The bill provides appropriations to

the House Democracy Partnership,the Offices of Inspector General,the State Department and the President for International Security Assistance, andInternational Financial Institutions for Multilateral Assistance.The bill provides appropriations for bilateral economic assistance, including programs and activities conducted by

the President;Independent Agencies, including the Peace Corps, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, and the U.S. Foundation for Natural Security and Counterterrorism,the Department of the Treasury.The bill provides appropriations for export and investment assistance to

the Export-Import Bank of the United States,the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, andthe U.S. Trade and Development Agency.The bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-631</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
