<bill session="119" type="h" number="2385" updated="2026-03-25T08:05:44Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CREATE AI Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CREATE AI Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Resources for Every American To Experiment with Artificial Intelligence Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2025-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2026-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2025-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2025-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2025-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2025-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000477" joined="2025-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2025-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000602" joined="2026-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2025-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000398" joined="2025-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000590" joined="2026-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2025-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000607" joined="2025-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2025-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001238" joined="2025-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001218" joined="2025-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001237" joined="2025-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001241" joined="2026-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2025-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2025-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2025-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2025-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000136" joined="2026-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-13T17:03:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Creating Resources for Every American To Experiment with Artificial Intelligence Act of 2025 or the CREATE AI Act of 2025

This bill establishes a national program to provide U.S. researchers, educators, and students with access to artificial intelligence (AI) data, computational resources, educational tools and services, and testbeds.

The program, to be known as the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource (NAIRR), must be established by the National Science Foundation (NSF) to improve U.S. AI research capacity and spur the strategic development of AI capabilities. NAIRR may accept and use donated resources from the private sector and federal agencies.

Those eligible to use NAIRR resources are (1) researchers, educators, and students based in the United States and affiliated with a U.S. institution of higher education, nonprofit, executive agency, or other specified entity; and (2) employees of U.S. executive agencies or federally funded research and development centers with a demonstrable mission need.

NSF must select a nongovernmental organization to operate NAIRR (i.e., an operating entity) through a competitive and transparent process. The operating entity must ensure that a significant percentage of the annual allotment of computational resources is provided to projects primarily focused on AI privacy, ethics, safety, security, risk mitigation, or trustworthiness. The operating entity must also establish minimum security requirements for all individuals interacting with NAIRR.

The operating entity may establish a fee schedule for access to NAIRR, which must include a free tier of access and must ensure that the primary purpose of NAIRR is to support research.</summary>
</bill>
