<bill session="119" type="s" number="275" updated="2026-03-10T11:03:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans&#8217; Assuring Critical Care Expansions to Support Servicemembers (ACCESS) Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans&#8217; Assuring Critical Care Expansions to Support Servicemembers (ACCESS) Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the provision of care and services under the Veterans Community Care Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2025-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2025-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2026-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001244" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2025-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2025-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Markup By, Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="740" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-12-31T16:33:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans' Assuring Critical Care Expansions to Support&#160;Servicemembers (ACCESS) Act of 2025

This bill addresses the administration of the Veterans Community Care Program (VCCP) and other Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health care matters.

Among other provisions regarding the VCCP, the bill

establishes in statute access standards that determine when a veteran is eligible to receive non-VA care through the VCCP,requires the VA to notify veterans regarding their eligibility for care within two business days after the VA is aware the veteran is seeking care, andextends the deadline for the submittal of claims under the&#160;VCCP by health care entities and providers.The VA must address its mental health treatment programs by

establishing a standardized screening process to determine whether a veteran satisfies criteria for priority or routine admission to a mental health residential rehabilitation treatment program or a program for residential care for mental health and substance abuse disorders,tracking the performance of medical facilities and Veterans Integrated Service Networks in meeting the requirements for mental health treatment screenings and timely admission to treatment programs under such screenings, andestablishing an appeal process for when a veteran is denied admission to a covered treatment program or is accepted into a program but not offered bed placement in a timely manner.Additionally, the VA must establish an online self-service module for veterans to request and manage appointments, track referrals, and appeal and track decisions related to requests for care.</summary>
</bill>
