<bill session="119" type="h" number="1194" updated="2026-03-04T16:07:41Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Lands and Waters Leasing Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands and Waters Leasing Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act and the Mineral Leasing Act to require reports on rejected bids, to clarify timelines for the issuance of leases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001096" joined="2025-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-04T16:05:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Lands and Waters Leasing Transparency Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to provide explanations to the highest bidders when it rejects their bids for certain offshore oil and gas leases. The bill also prohibits courts from invalidating or delaying certain onshore and offshore oil and gas leases.

When Interior determines that the federal government will not receive the fair market value for offshore lease tracts on submerged lands of the Outer Continental Shelf from the highest bidder, then Interior must provide a report to the bidder that explains the basis for the determination.&#160;If the bid was subject to a resource and economic evaluation, the report must include information on how the bid compares to specified valuation metrics. These requirements apply to lease sales in which Interior received at least one bid and did not issue a lease to the highest bidder.

Additionally, courts may not prevent Interior from issuing certain onshore oil and gas leases by a 60-day statutory deadline unless the lease would violate federal law.

Further, the bill prohibits civil actions that challenge certain offshore oil and gas lease sales from (1) invalidating leases issued under such sales; and (2) delaying the consideration of plans, documents, or applications for a federal authorization or approval of activities for a lease. If a court finds that the sale was not carried out in compliance with federal law, the court must (1) remand the matter to Interior, and (2) direct Interior to correct the noncompliance.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
