<bill session="119" type="h" number="1640" updated="2026-07-01T08:09:17Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEIRS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEIRS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Heirs Estate Inheritance Resolution and Succession Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program for States that adopt the Uniform Partition of Heirs Property Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000788"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000481" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2026-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2026-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 51 - 0.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-30T20:38:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Heirs Estate Inheritance Resolution and Succession Act of 2025 or the HEIRS Act of 2025

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to provide grants to assist individuals with the legal processes associated with inheriting certain real property.

Under the first program, HUD must provide grants to states&#160;that have enacted the Uniform Partition of Heirs Property Act (UPHPA) (or similar state law). The UPHPA provides due process protections against forced property sales&#160;for individuals who inherit real property from a landowner without a will. Historically, state property laws have provided that recipients of such property become tenants-in-common, which permits a single tenant to exercise their right to partition and sell the property.

A state or local government must use grant funds to assist residents with expenses related to establishing and documenting property ownership rights or settling a decedent's estate, including&#160;costs related to

obtaining title reports, title abstracts, copies of public records, and land surveys;estate planning;heirs searches or tracing services; andrecording and filing fees, notary fees, and legal fees and expenses.Under the second program, HUD must provide grants to housing counseling agencies, legal services&#160;clinics at&#160;institutions of higher education, and qualified nonprofits.&#160;Such organizations must use grant funds to&#160;provide housing counseling, legal assistance, and financial assistance related to title clearing and home retention efforts for individuals who&#160;inherit property as tenants-in-common.</summary>
</bill>
