<bill session="119" type="s" number="2880" updated="2026-04-08T12:13:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Mass Marking Program Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Mass Marking Program Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Great Lakes Mass Marketing Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001104" joined="2025-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1917" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-08T12:12:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Great Lakes Mass Marking Program Act of 2025

This bill provides statutory authority for a program of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS) for the mass marking of hatchery-produced fish in the Great Lakes basin. Mass marking is the practice of tagging large numbers of hatchery-produced fish in order to distinguish them from the wild fish population. The FWS initiated the program in 2010 on a limited scale. Under the existing program, the FWS (1) tags hatchery-produced fish stocked in the Great Lakes, and (2) produces data used by state and tribal fish management agencies to make management decisions regarding Great Lakes fisheries.

This bill allows the FWS, in carrying out the program, to (1) purchase items to support and carry out tagging and tag recovery operations on a greater scale, and (2) hire additional personnel.

The FWS must make the data collected under the program available to applicable federal, state, and tribal fish management agencies to

increase the understanding of the outcomes of management action;assist in meeting the restoration objectives of the Great Lakes;assist in balancing predators and prey;support and improve the economic status of tribal, recreational, and commercial fisheries; andassist in evaluating the effectiveness of habitat restoration efforts in the Great Lakes.</summary>
</bill>
