<bill session="119" type="h" number="1390" updated="2026-04-14T17:43:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ocean Pollution Reduction Act II</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocean Pollution Reduction Act II</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify permitting requirements with respect to the discharge of any pollutant from the Point Loma Wastewater Treatment Plant in certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2025-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2025-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2025-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2025-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-14T17:43:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Ocean Pollution Reduction Act II

This bill provides an alternative permitting process for the&#160;Point Loma Wastewater Treatment Plant located in San Diego, California, to comply with the requirements of the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES) permit program.

Currently, the plant operates with a temporary&#160;variance (or waiver) from certain NPDES treatment standards&#160;under the Clean Water Act (CWA). The City of San Diego has applied for a new variance&#160;for the plant. If the variance is not granted, then the city must obtain a new NPDES permit and fully comply with the treatment standards.

The bill allows the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue an&#160;NPDES permit that requires the plant to comply with certain conditions. Thus, it eliminates the need for the city to apply for another variance so long as it obtains&#160;the conditional&#160;NPDES permit and the plant:

maintains its current&#160;deep ocean outfall pipe;complies&#160;with specified annual and monthly limits for&#160;total suspended solids (e.g., sewage);removes at least 80% of&#160;total suspended solids from the discharge on a monthly average and 58%&#160;of biochemical oxygen demand on an annual average;attains all other effluent limitations of secondary treatment;complies with CWA pretreatment requirements and other requirements applicable to NPDES permits;provides to the EPA 10 consecutive years of compliance data and analysis; anddemonstrates&#160;that it will produce at least 83 million gallons per day on an annual average of water safe for human consumption by December 31, 2039.</summary>
</bill>
