<bill session="119" type="s" number="3482" updated="2026-05-28T19:15:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">First Step Implementation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Step Implementation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform sentencing laws and correctional institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2025-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8732-8737" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-28T19:13:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">First Step Implementation Act of 2025

This bill relaxes federal sentencing laws for drug offenses in certain situations and for offenses committed by juveniles. It&#160;also requires the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish procedures to ensure the prompt release and accuracy of employment-related background check records.

The bill

allows certain reduced mandatory minimum sentences for drug offenses to be applied retroactively to offenders who committed their offenses on or before December 21, 2018;permits a court, in certain circumstances, to grant safety valve relief (i.e., impose a sentence without regard to the statutory mandatory minimum penalty for certain drug offenses) for an otherwise eligible defendant who does not meet the requirement pertaining to criminal history;permits a court to reduce a sentence imposed on a defendant convicted as an adult for an offense committed as a juvenile if the defendant has served at least 20 years of the sentence;establishes a process to seal and expunge certain records of juvenile nonviolent offenses; andrequires DOJ to establish and enforce procedures to ensure that records exchanged for employment-related background checks are promptly released and accurate.</summary>
</bill>
