<bill session="119" type="h" number="4435" updated="2026-05-26T19:53:57Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to increase transparency with respect to cosmetic ingredients, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2026-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2025-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2025-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2025-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2026-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2025-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2025-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2025-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-26T19:52:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025

This bill requires cosmetic products to be labeled with a full list of their ingredients, including fragrance and flavor ingredients, and imposes other disclosure and labeling requirements related to certain potentially harmful ingredients. A cosmetic product that fails to meet such requirements may not be sold.

Under current law, a cosmetic product&#8217;s packaging must generally include a list of its ingredients, but fragrance or flavor ingredients may be listed as fragrance or flavor in lieu of listing specific ingredient names.

Within two years of the bill&#8217;s enactment, a cosmetic product's labeling or packaging must include a full list of its ingredients, including fragrance and flavor ingredients. Further, if the cosmetic includes certain ingredients, its labeling or packaging must also contain a specified statement directing consumers to the brand owner's website for information on health impacts of the product&#8217;s ingredients. Ingredients that trigger this requirement include those identified on specified lists of harmful or potentially harmful chemicals, such as chemicals identified as carcinogenic by the Environmental Protection Agency. The Food and Drug Administration must maintain a public list of all such ingredients.

Within one year of enactment, a brand owner must disclose certain information on its website for each of its cosmetic products, including

a full list of ingredients;the functional purpose served by each fragrance or flavor ingredient; andif any ingredient is identified on the specified lists of harmful or potentially harmful chemicals, a link to the relevant list.</summary>
</bill>
