<bill session="119" type="s" number="2912" updated="2026-04-23T12:58:36Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit deceptive practices in Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2025-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4894" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-23T12:58:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Deceptive Practices and Voter Intimidation Prevention Act of 2025

This bill generally prohibits deceptive communications and voter interference regarding federal elections.

Specifically, the bill prohibits any person, within 60 days before a federal election, from communicating, causing to be communicated, or producing for communication certain information on voting, if the person (1) knows such information to be materially false, and (2) has the intent to impede or prevent another person from voting in an election.

Additionally, the bill prohibits any person, within 60 days before a federal election, from&#160;using an artificial intelligence system to produce certain information on voting, if the person has the intent to use the system to (1) produce false information, and (2) impede or prevent another person from voting in an election.

The bill also prohibits hindering, interfering with, or preventing voting or registering to vote.

A private right of action for preventive relief is established for persons aggrieved by violations of these prohibitions.

Criminal penalties are also established for violations.

If the Department of Justice (DOJ) receives a credible report that materially false information has been or is being communicated in violation of the prohibitions on deceptive communications, and state and local election officials have not adequately communicated corrected information, then DOJ must communicate to the public accurate information designed to correct the materially false information.

The bill extends the prohibition on certain types of intimidation in federal elections to also prohibit intimidation for processing ballots or tabulating, canvassing, or certifying votes.</summary>
</bill>
