<bill session="119" type="h" number="3217" updated="2026-05-30T08:06:05Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to expand the summer electronic benefits transfer for children program to include benefit transfer during school closures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Child Hunger Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Child Hunger Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2025-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2026-05-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1622" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-01-22T20:03:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Child Hunger Act of 2025

This bill expands the Department of Agriculture's (USDA's)&#160;Summer Electronic Benefit Transfer Program for Children (Summer EBT) to include coverage during a school closure period. (Summer EBT provides grocery-buying benefits to low-income families with school-aged children when schools are closed for the summer.)

Under the bill, a&#160;school closure period means a period in which an elementary school or secondary school is closed, operating remotely, or operating in a hybrid manner for five or more consecutive weekdays during a calendar year.

The bill also increases the daily value of the benefit to cover the cost of breakfast, lunch, and a snack for every day school is closed.

For FY2026, USDA must pay each state agency and covered tribal organization 100% of the administrative expenses (currently 50%) incurred in operating the program. The&#160;rate that USDA must pay for administrative expenses decreases each fiscal year until it reaches 50% of the expenses for FY2031 and each fiscal year thereafter.

USDA must also provide grants to states to support the development or upgrading of data systems that are necessary to implement Summer EBT.</summary>
</bill>
