<bill session="119" type="s" number="500" updated="2026-06-23T19:54:25Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CAREER Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CAREER Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Addiction Recovery through Effective Employment and Reentry Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize certain programs under the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001242" joined="2025-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2121" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2483" relation="contained in public law"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="891" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1768" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-23T19:54:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Comprehensive Addiction Recovery through Effective Employment and Reentry Act of 2025 or the CAREER Act of 2025

This bill reauthorizes and expands programs to assist individuals in substance use disorder&#160;treatment and recovery to live independently and participate in the workforce.

Specifically, the bill reauthorizes through FY2030 the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAHMSA)&#160;Treatment, Recovery, and Workforce Support Grant Program, which provides employment training and recovery support services in coordination&#160;with state and local stakeholders. The bill further authorizes using 5% of such grant&#160;funds for transportation services and requires grantees to report on the employment and earnings outcomes of program participants.

The bill also reauthorizes through FY20230 the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Recovery Housing Pilot Program, which assists states in providing individuals in recovery from a substance use disorder with stable, temporary housing for up to two years.</summary>
</bill>
