<bill session="119" type="h" number="5254" updated="2026-03-17T08:05:46Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-16T17:18:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-16T17:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gateway Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gateway Partnership Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Gateway Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Gateway Arch Park Foundation to host private events in Gateway Arch National Park buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2025-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2025-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-02">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 119-536.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-03-02" calendar="Union" number="461">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 461.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T17:10:08-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wittman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T17:10:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T17:10:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5254.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-03-16T17:18:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T17:18:02-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2767" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-12T18:59:10Z" status="Reported to House">Gateway Partnership Act

This bill authorizes the National Park Service (NPS) to enter into a one-time agreement with the Gateway Arch Park Foundation to host private events at the Gateway Arch National Park and its buildings for a period of up to five years. The NPS manages the park, located in St. Louis, Missouri, and&#160;its buildings, such as the Arch Visitor Center and the Old Courthouse.

The bill outlines the terms and conditions that must be included in the agreement. The bill also requires private events hosted at the park or its buildings to be consistent with the park's purposes and compatible with NPS programs. Such events may not (1) degrade the integrity, appearance, or purposes of the park; or (2) take place during times or in locations that prevent or disrupt public use or access to the park or its buildings.

The NPS must charge a fee to cover the cost of wear and tear resulting from the private events. The NPS may recover all costs incurred as a result of the private events, including maintenance, utilities, administrative expenses, security, and personnel costs.

The bill terminates the NPS's authority to enter&#160;and&#160;carry out an agreement with the foundation seven years after the enactment of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-536</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
