<bill session="119" type="s" number="2183" updated="2026-03-26T14:02:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Wood Facilities Assistance Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to improve assistance to community wood facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Wood Facilities Assistance Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2025-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2025-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2517" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-26T14:00:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Wood Facilities Assistance Act of 2025 

This bill makes changes to grant programs administered by the Forest Service to promote wood products.

Specifically, the bill reauthorizes through FY2030, modifies, and renames the Community Wood Facilities Grant program. Currently named the Community Wood Energy and Wood Innovation Program, this program provides competitive grants to fund a portion of the capital costs for installing community wood energy systems or building innovative wood products facilities.

Modifications to the program include increasing the maximum grant amount per facility, increasing the portion of a project's cost that may be covered by a grant,&#160;and changing&#160;the grant selection criteria.

The bill also modifies the&#160;Wood Innovation Grant Program, which provides grants to develop and expand the market for innovative wood products. Specifically, the bill increases the portion of a project's cost that may be covered by such a grant.

The bill also modifies both programs to prioritize grants for the construction, use, or retrofitting of forest products manufacturing.</summary>
</bill>
