<bill session="119" type="h" number="1782" updated="2026-03-26T15:27:59Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SHOPP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHOPP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting all Healthy Options when Purchasing Produce Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to provide families year-round access to nutrition incentives under the Gus Schumacher Nutrition Incentive Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001130"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000379" joined="2025-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001324" joined="2025-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2026-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2025-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000481" joined="2025-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2025-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000601" joined="2025-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001233" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2025-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2025-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="813" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-26T15:24:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting all Healthy Options when Purchasing Produce Act of 2025 or the SHOPP Act&#160;of 2025

This bill modifies the&#160;Gus Schumacher Nutrition Incentive Program&#160;(GusNIP) to include fresh frozen fruits and vegetables.

GusNIP is&#160;a Department of Agriculture&#160;(USDA) program that provides grants for projects that increase low-income consumers' purchases of fruits and vegetables. It&#160;is made up of three competitive grant programs, including the GusNIP Nutrition Incentive Program, which provides grants for projects that provide incentives for Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) participants to purchase&#160;fruits and vegetables.

The bill&#160;directs USDA, in awarding GusNIP Nutrition Incentive Program grants, to give priority to projects that&#160;increase year-round availability of nutrition incentives by offering fresh frozen fruits or vegetables in the program.

In addition, the bill amends another GusNIP program,&#160;the Produce Prescription Program, to include fresh frozen fruits and vegetables, as well as fresh and fresh frozen legumes. Currently, only fresh fruits and vegetables are covered under the program.

The&#160;GusNIP Produce Prescription Program supports projects that demonstrate and evaluate the impact of fruit and vegetable prescriptions on&#160;increasing procurement and consumption of fruits and vegetables, reducing individual and household food insecurity, and reducing healthcare usage and associated costs.</summary>
</bill>
