<bill session="119" type="s" number="924" updated="2026-03-11T15:17:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-10">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations and Other Extensions Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations and Other Extensions Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2025, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-03-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="25">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1974" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-11T15:14:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations and Other Extensions Act, 2025

This bill provides continuing FY2025 appropriations for federal agencies through April 11, 2025.&#160;It also extends various expiring programs and authorities, including several public health programs.

Specifically, the bill provides continuing FY2025 appropriations to federal agencies through the earlier of April 11, 2025, or the enactment of the applicable appropriations act. It is known as a continuing resolution (CR) and prevents a government shutdown that would otherwise occur if the FY2025 appropriations bills have not been enacted when the existing CR expires on March 14, 2025.

The CR funds most programs and activities at the FY2024 levels with some exceptions that provide funding flexibility and additional appropriations for various programs. For example, the&#160;CR

provides additional emergency funding for the Federal Emergency Management Agency's Disaster Relief Fund,permits the Navy to apportion funds at the rate necessary to fund the Columbia-class submarine program and cost increases for certain shipbuilding programs, andprovides additional funding for the Office of Navajo and Hopi Relocation.In addition, the bill extends several expiring programs and authorities, including

several public health, Medicare, and Medicaid authorities and programs;authorities related to the Commodity Futures Trading Commission&#160;whistleblower program;authorities for the Department of Homeland Security&#160;and the Department of Justice to take actions to mitigate a credible threat from an unmanned aircraft system;the special assessment on&#160;nonindigent persons or entities convicted of certain offenses involving sexual abuse or human trafficking; andthe National Cybersecurity Protection System.</summary>
</bill>
