<bill session="119" type="h" number="311" updated="2026-04-28T16:31:18Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Fuel Market Freedom Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Fuel Market Freedom Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the alcohol fuels credit, the biodiesels fuel credit, the sustainable aviation fuel credit, the clean fuel production credit, the alcohol fuel, biodiesel, and alternative fuel mixtures credit, and other related provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001316" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2025-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-28T15:53:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Fuel Market Freedom Act of 2025

This bill repeals multiple fuel-related federal tax credits and the credit or refund of federal fuel excise taxes paid on certain fuels used for nontaxable&#160;purposes.

Specifically, the bill repeals the

business tax credit for clean fuel production (tax credit for the production of clean fuels produced after 2024 and sold before 2028);business tax credit for second-generation biofuel producers (tax credit for the production before 2025 of fuel derived from qualified feedstocks that meets certain other requirements);business tax credit for biodiesel fuels (tax credit for biodiesel fuel sold or used before 2025);business tax credit for sustainable aviation fuel (tax credit for sustainable aviation fuel sold or used before 2025); andtax credit for alcohol fuel, biodiesel, and alternative fuel mixtures (tax credit for alcohol fuel, biodiesel, and alternative fuel mixtures sold or used before 2025).Finally, the bill repeals expired provisions that allow a credit or refund of excise taxes paid on&#160;alcohol,&#160;biodiesel, alternative fuel, or sustainable aviation fuel that is used for nontaxable purposes.</summary>
</bill>
