<bill session="119" type="h" number="5587" updated="2026-04-21T16:21:19Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Harnessing Energy At Thermal Sources Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEATS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Harnessing Energy At Thermal Sources Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">HEATS Act</title>
    <title type="display">HEATS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to waive the requirement for a Federal drilling permit for certain activities, to exempt certain activities from the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001323" joined="2025-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000605" joined="2025-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-15">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 119-613.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-15" calendar="Union" number="531">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 531.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-04-20T19:09:52-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1189 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4690, H. Res. 1182, H.R. 1897 and H.R. 5587. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4690, H. Res. 1182, H.R. 1897, and H.R. 5587 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on H.R. 4690, H.R. 1897, and H.R. 5587.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1189" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-08T14:41:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Harnessing Energy At Thermal Sources Act or the HEATS Act

This bill exempts certain geothermal activities on state and private lands (except Indian lands) from drilling permit requirements as well as environmental and historic preservation review requirements.

First, the bill prohibits the Department of the Interior from requiring an operator to obtain a drilling permit under the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 for any geothermal exploration and production activity conducted on a nonfederal surface estate (i.e., the part of the estate that is above ground) if (1) the United States holds an ownership interest of less than 50% of the subsurface geothermal estate to be accessed by the proposed action, and (2) the operator submits to Interior a state permit to conduct the geothermal exploration and production activity on the nonfederal surface estate.&#160;

Next, the bill states that such geothermal exploration and production activity is not considered a major federal action under National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). Thus, such activity does not trigger NEPA's environmental review requirements.

In addition, the bill exempts such activity from the consultation requirements under the Endangered Species Act of 1973. It also exempts the activity from review under the National Historic Preservation Act unless the state in which the activity occurs does not have a state law that addresses the preservation of historic properties.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-613</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
