<bill session="119" type="h" number="6615" updated="2026-06-26T08:07:31Z">
  <state datetime="2025-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Climate Justice Grants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Justice Grants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out a grant program for projects and activities to address climate justice concerns of environmental justice communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001324" joined="2026-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-10T15:43:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Climate Justice Grants Act

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a grant program to assist tribal governments, local governments, nonprofits, or community-based organizations in addressing issues relating to climate justice and carrying out activities that address climate justice concerns of environmental justice communities. Environmental justice communities refers to any population of color, community of color, indigenous community, or low-income community that experiences a disproportionate burden of the negative human health and environmental impacts of pollution or other environmental hazards.</summary>
</bill>
