<bill session="119" type="s" number="4161" updated="2026-06-22T21:06:36Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-28">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maverick Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maverick Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Maverick Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the transfer by the Secretary of the Navy to the U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama, of certain F-14 Tomcat aircraft.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2026-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-28">
      <text>Senate Committee on Armed Services discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-28">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2075" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2026-04-28" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2075" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-05-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-04T10:32:46-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-04T10:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="4784" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5437"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2026-05-19T21:38:45Z" status="Passed Senate">Maverick Act

This bill authorizes the Department of the Navy to transfer three surplus F-14D Tomcat aircraft to the U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama. (The F-14D Tomcat was a naval fighter aircraft that was retired from service in 2006.)

The bill provides for certain conditions for the transfer, including that the transfer must be free of cost to the federal government. Additionally, the commission must not convey ownership interest in the aircraft to another party without Navy approval. If the commission breaches any conditions, the aircraft must revert to the United States.

The bill also specifies that such aircraft may not have any combat capability. The Navy may provide excess spare parts to the commission to make one of the aircraft flyable or complete for a static display.

The Navy may authorize the commission to enter into agreements with qualified&#160;nonprofit&#160;organizations to restore and operate the aircraft for public display, air shows, and commemorative events.</summary>
</bill>
