<bill session="119" type="s" number="1745" updated="2026-03-19T18:43:20Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dismantling Ideological Policies for Semiconductors and Science Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dismantling Ideological Policies for Semiconductors and Science Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal certain provisions of the CHIPS Act of 2022 and the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act, to limit Federal mandates imposed on entities seeking Federal funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2025-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2025-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2025-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-19T18:41:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dismantling Ideological Policies for Semiconductors and Science Act

This bill repeals requirements and eliminates positions related to diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) in various federal programs and offices focused on science. Each of the repealed provisions was originally included in the CHIPS and Science Act.

Among other modifications, the bill

repeals a provision authorizing the National Institute for Standards and Technology to conduct outreach to and develop research collaborations with historically Black colleges and universities, tribal colleges and universities, and other minority-serving institutions;eliminates the position of Chief Diversity Officer within the National Science Foundation (NSF);repeals an NSF grant program to enable institutions of higher education and nonprofit organizations to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) studies and careers; andeliminates references to diversity in the purposes and responsibilities of the Office of STEM Engagement within the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.The bill also prohibits executive branch agencies from requiring entities seeking federal funding to have certain policies in place, unless such a requirement is imposed by a federal statute. Such policies include those related to hiring, training, and retaining a diverse workforce; providing childcare for employees; minimizing adverse impacts on the environment and local communities; and consultation with labor organizations.

(On January 20, 2025, President Trump issued an executive order titled Ending Radical and Wasteful Government DEI Programs and Preferencing, which directed the termination of all federal DEI programs, offices, and positions, including Chief Diversity Officer positions.)</summary>
</bill>
