<bill session="119" type="s" number="153" updated="2026-06-03T11:41:06Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Repeal the TikTok Ban Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Repeal the TikTok Ban Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal the Protecting Americans from Foreign Adversary Controlled Applications Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="564" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-03T10:17:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Repeal the TikTok Ban Act

This bill repeals the prohibition on distributing, maintaining, updating, or providing internet hosting services for a foreign adversary controlled application (e.g., TikTok) and nullifies any existing designation of a website or application as a foreign adversary controlled application.&#160;

Under current law, a foreign adversary controlled application is a website or application directly or indirectly operated by (1) ByteDance, Ltd., TikTok, their subsidiaries, successors, or related entities they control; or (2) a social media company that is controlled by a foreign adversary country and determined by the President to present a significant threat to national security. (Here, the term social media company excludes any website or application primarily used to post product reviews, business reviews, or travel information and reviews. The term foreign adversary country means North Korea, China, Russia, and Iran.)&#160;

Current law generally prohibits the distribution, maintenance, implementation of updates, or provision of hosting services for a foreign adversary controlled&#160;application, unless an approved divestiture transaction results in the application no longer being controlled by a foreign adversary country, among other requirements.</summary>
</bill>
