<bill session="119" type="h" number="7388" updated="2026-03-25T08:05:45Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-24T15:55:22-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-24T15:55:22-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smart Space Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Smart Space Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="display">Smart Space Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of General Services to convene consultation meetings to identify alternative financing solutions for the construction of new public buildings that will reduce costs to the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001316"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 119-562.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-03-20" calendar="Union" number="483">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 483.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T15:47:21-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Taylor moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T15:47:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T15:47:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7388.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-03-24T15:55:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-03-24T15:55:23-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-20T19:35:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Smart Space Act of 2026

This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to publish a recommended list of public building projects for which public-private partnerships and alternative financing methods should&#160;be used.

Under the bill, GSA must hold consultation meetings to identify alternative financing solutions for the construction, renovation, or preparation for disposal&#160;of public buildings that will reduce costs to the federal government.&#160;Such meetings must include experts in private commercial real estate and federal real estate.&#160;If available, state real estate experts with experience leveraging private financing for public buildings and facilities must also be included.

GSA must submit to the President and Congress, and publish on its website (1) recommendations on types of public-private partnerships and alternative financing methods best suited for meeting the federal government's public building needs, and (2) a list of recommended projects for which such methods should be used.

Projects included on the recommended projects list must meet certain criteria, including&#160;consolidating or relocating federal agencies out of costly, inefficient, and underutilized spaces that GSA intends to sell or dispose of once vacated.</summary>
</bill>
