<bill session="119" type="h" number="8665" updated="2026-06-09T08:06:25Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-08T17:02:06-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-08T17:02:06-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Allied Defense Sales Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Allied Defense Sales Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the implementation of a strategy to encourage foreign partners to participate in the foreign military sales and direct commercial sales processes on a multinational basis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2026-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2026-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000484" joined="2026-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2026-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2026-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2026-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2026-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2026-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 44 - 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T16:53:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mast moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T16:53:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3965-3967" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T16:53:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 8665.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-06-08T17:02:06-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3965-3966" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T17:02:08-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-05T16:58:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Allied Defense Sales Act

This bill directs the Department of State to implement a strategy to encourage foreign entities to participate in a multinational military procurement process. The State Department must also periodically report on the strategy and its implementation.

Under the bill, this process involves the sale by the United States to a lead foreign nation of defense articles or services which are subsequently transferred to other qualifying countries.

The strategy must incorporate existing efforts by the State Department to, for example, survey interest, identify countries and partners who could serve as lead purchase coordinators, review pathways for participation for countries that are ineligible for foreign military financing loans, identify challenges and solutions regarding compliance with the Arms Export Control Act, and identify opportunities to develop and promote exportable defense articles and services (including for purposes of supporting the trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States).</summary>
</bill>
