<bill session="119" type="s" number="1249" updated="2026-03-11T13:09:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drone Integration and Zoning Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Integration and Zoning Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prescribe zoning authority with respect to commercial unmanned aircraft systems and to preserve State, local, and Tribal authorities and private property with respect to unmanned aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-11T13:07:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Drone Integration and Zoning Act 

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to prescribe regulations or standards related to unmanned aircraft systems (i.e.,&#160;drones) and allow&#160;limited state and local regulation of drones.

The FAA must designate the area between 200 feet and 400 feet above ground level for use by (1) civil drones, and (2) commercial and recreational drones.

The bill prohibits the FAA from authorizing the operation of civil drones within 200 feet above ground level above private property without the property owner's permission. For structures above this level, the FAA may not authorize civil drone operations (1) within 50 feet of the top of the structure, or (2) within 200 feet laterally or inside the property line, whichever is closer to the structure, with exceptions.

Further, the bill specifies that the FAA must preserve state, local, and tribal authority to issue reasonable restrictions on the time, manner, and place of operation of drones below 200 feet above ground level. The bill includes additional exceptions to federal preemption requirements allowing for these entities to regulate specific drone activities.

The FAA must also establish a process for the designation of authorized commercial routes, which must be at least 200 feet above ground level.

The Department of Transportation must also establish a process for state, local, and tribal authorities to apply for a designation of complex airspace.&#160;This designation for an area allows the FAA to assign these entities with designated responsibilities for the management of drone operations.</summary>
</bill>
