<bill session="119" type="s" number="3971" updated="2026-03-18T08:06:37Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-17T15:44:52-04:00">PASSED:BILL</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-03-17T15:44:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Innovation and Economic Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Small Business Innovation and Economic Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the SBIR and STTR programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2026-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-03-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S752-756" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S752-756" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-03-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-04T12:05:29-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-04T12:10:16-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T15:01:04-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Van Duyne moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T15:01:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2491-2497" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2491-2495" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T15:01:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3971.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-16T15:13:10-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-17T15:37:37-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="89" datetime="2026-03-17T15:44:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 345 - 41 (Roll no. 89).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-03-17T15:44:53-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-16T14:46:55Z" status="Passed Senate">Small Business Innovation and Economic Security Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2031 and modifies the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) program, the Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) program, and related pilot programs.&#160;(The SBIR and STTR programs are administered by various federal agencies and provide competitive awards for domestic small businesses to conduct research and development projects that have the potential for commercialization.)

Specifically, the bill expands the requirements for federal agencies administering these programs to evaluate the security risks of the small businesses that apply for awards under the programs. If an agency denies an application for security reasons, the agency must provide the small business with&#160;the basis for such determination.

Further, each agency must set a maximum number of proposals per fiscal year that a small business concern may submit in response to Phase I and Phase II solicitations.

The bill expands the training requirements for agencies' contracting officers and acquisition workforce with respect to Phase III (commercialization of technologies) awards under the&#160;SBIR and STTR programs.

The bill also establishes strategic breakthrough allocations for critical technology areas. These are additional Phase II SBIR and STTR awards to&#160;small businesses that demonstrate an effective technology and receive matching funds.</summary>
</bill>
