<bill session="119" type="h" number="7305" updated="2026-07-01T08:06:06Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-29T16:43:31-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-29T16:43:31-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Threat Analysis Center Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Energy Threat Analysis Center Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Energy Threat Analysis Center Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to reauthorize the Department of Energy's Energy Sector Operational Support for Cyberresilience Program to provide operational support for energy sector cybersecurity and resilience.</title>
    <title type="official">To amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to reauthorize the Department of Energy&#8217;s Energy Sector Operational Support for Cyberresilience Program to provide operational support for energy sector cybersecurity and resilience.</title>
    <title type="display">Energy Threat Analysis Center Act of 2026</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000300" joined="2026-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 119-646.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-05-12" calendar="Union" number="563">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 563.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:36:10-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Guthrie moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:36:13-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4300-4302" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:36:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7305.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-06-29T16:43:31-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4300-4301" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-29T16:43:35-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-26T12:56:43Z" status="Reported to House">Energy Threat Analysis Center Act of 2026

This bill reauthorizes through FY2031 and expands the pilot Energy Sector Operational Support for Cyber Resilience Program of the Department of Energy (DOE).&#160;The program aims to protect energy infrastructure through collaboration between the federal government and the energy sector and enhancing DOE&#8217;s emergency response capabilities.

Specifically, the bill expands the program objectives to include&#160;

enhancing collaboration between the government and the energy sector to address threats to energy systems,advancing the collective understanding of national security risks and vulnerabilities associated with the energy sector that may be exploited by adversaries, andhelping the energy sector increase its understanding of tactics of adversaries that present risks to the energy sector.The bill allows&#160;DOE to establish an Energy Threat Analysis Center at one or more physical locations for program activities.

The bill also&#160;eliminates technical assistance provided under the program to small electric utilities.

Under the bill, the&#160;decision to provide assistance or information under the program to a governmental or private entity is at the sole discretion of the Secretary of Energy and is unreviewable.

The bill authorizes the Secretary to (1) enter into and perform contracts, grants, and other transactions with public agencies, private organizations, and persons to carry out the program; and (2) establish and utilize preapproved national security contracting mechanisms, model partnership agreements, and expedited review procedures for purposes of entering into such transactions.

In addition, the bill exempts the program from&#160;certain public disclosure and&#160;other&#160;transparency requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-646</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
