<bill session="119" type="s" number="4328" updated="2026-06-05T21:35:05Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FLEX Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLEX Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Learning and Excellence in Charter Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 in order to provide for greater flexibility in the Federal programs supporting the planning and implementation of charter schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2026-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2026-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7082" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-05T21:34:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fostering Learning and Excellence in Charter Schools Act or the FLEX Act

This bill expands and revises the Charter Schools Program (CSP), including by expanding the allowable uses of&#160;CSP funds.

Current law authorizes competitive grants to state entities (e.g., state educational agencies and state charter school boards) and, through them, subgrants to eligible applicants (i.e., charter school developers) to enable them to open and prepare for the operation of a new charter school or replicate or expand an existing&#160;high-quality charter school.&#160;

The bill allows subgrants to also be used for&#160;adding or expanding programs or other offerings at these schools, such as through the adoption of new academic programs or delivery models, personalized learning, or a new curricular approach. New offerings must enable additional students to enroll in and benefit from the school.

Eligible applicants may also use CSP funds for activities such as&#160;

hiring and compensating teachers and other school staff (currently, this may only occur during the planning period);carrying out necessary renovations, upgrades, or facility repairs, or acquiring portable classrooms; andproviding transportation to students (currently, only one-time,&#160;start-up transportation&#160;costs are permitted).Eligible applicants may request and receive advance payments of subgrants.

Among other requirements, the Department of Education must (1)&#160;use&#160;CSP funds for additional activities (e.g., increasing the number of available seats in charter schools that serve rural students and students with disabilities), and (2) consult with charter school operators prior to issuing a notice of&#160;proposed rulemaking relevant to charter schools.</summary>
</bill>
