<bill session="119" type="s" number="222" updated="2026-06-16T14:05:12Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to allow schools that participate in the school lunch program to serve whole milk, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2025-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000312" joined="2025-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001243" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 119-55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-10">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Reported by Senator Boozman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="111">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 111.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2025-11-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8259-8261" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8261" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-11-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-20T18:03:10-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-20T18:18:16-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15T14:21:04-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thompson (PA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15T14:21:15-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5857-5861" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15T14:21:17-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 222.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2025-12-15T14:51:43-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-12-15T14:51:48-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2026-01-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2026-01-14" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="119-69" type="public" datetime="2026-01-14">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 119-69.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1469" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-16T13:53:24Z" status="Public Law">Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025

This act revises requirements for milk provided by the National School Lunch Program of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to allow schools to offer students&#160;whole and reduced-fat milk. The act also&#160;requires that local school food service personnel receive annual training and certification on food allergies.

The act permits schools to offer students whole, reduced-fat (2%), low-fat (1%), and fat-free flavored and unflavored milk. The milk that is offered may be organic or nonorganic. Currently, USDA regulations require milk to be&#160;fat-free or low-fat and allow milk to be flavored or unflavored.&#160;The act also removes the requirement that schools participating in the program&#160;must provide milk that is consistent with the most recent&#160;Dietary Guidelines for Americans.

The act also expands the nondairy beverages that are included in the program by allowing&#160;schools to offer all students nondairy beverages that are nutritionally equivalent to fluid milk and that meet nutritional standards established by USDA.

Further, schools currently must provide a substitute for fluid milk, on receipt of a written statement from a licensed physician, for students whose disability restricts their diet. Under the act, a parent or legal guardian may also provide the written statement.

In addition, the act excludes&#160;fluid milk from the saturated fat content calculation for school meals. Currently, schools participating in the program must provide meals that meet certain nutrition requirements;&#160;USDA regulations require that the average saturated fat content of the meals offered must be less than 10% of the total calories. Under the act, milk fat included in any fluid milk provided by the program must not be considered saturated fat for the purposes of measuring compliance with USDA regulations.

Finally, the program's mandatory training and certification for local school food service personnel&#160;must include&#160;a module on food allergies, including information on the best practices to prevent, recognize, and respond to food-related allergic reactions. Food service personnel must receive an annual certification to&#160;demonstrate competence in the food allergies training and other training modules that are&#160;provided.</summary>
</bill>
