<bill session="119" type="h" number="1352" updated="2026-05-20T17:22:08Z">
  <state datetime="2026-05-19T16:05:40-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-05-19T16:05:40-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the General George C. Marshall House, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To designate the General George C. Marshall House, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001230"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-02">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 119-580.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-02" calendar="Union" number="500">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 500.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T15:58:17-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T15:58:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3572-3573" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T15:58:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1352.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-05-19T16:05:40-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3572" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T16:05:44-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-14T20:25:22Z" status="Reported to House">This bill designates the General George C. Marshall House in Leesburg, Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System (NPS). (George Catlett Marshall, Jr. served as Army Chief of Staff during World War II, and later as Secretary of State, president of the American Red Cross, and Secretary of Defense.)

The bill designates the George C. Marshall International Center as the management entity for the affiliated area. The Department of the Interior must enter into an agreement with the center that delineates the roles and responsibilities for management of the affiliated area that are in accordance with policies and standards applicable to NPS. Further, Interior may provide technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the center for the purpose of providing financial assistance for the marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the affiliated area.&#160;

Interior must complete a management plan for the affiliated area within three years of funds being made available to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-580</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
