<bill session="119" type="s" number="285" updated="2026-04-20T15:58:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness for Crime Victims Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Crime Victims Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to curtail the use of changes in mandatory programs affecting the Crime Victims Fund to inflate spending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-20T16:06:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness for Crime Victims Act of 2025

This bill establishes budget points of order in the House of Representatives and the Senate against considering provisions in appropriations legislation that contain changes in mandatory programs (CHIMPs) that would cause the amount available for obligation during the fiscal year from the Crime Victims Fund to be less than the annual average for the three previous fiscal years.

A CHIMP is a provision that (1) would have been estimated as affecting direct spending or receipts if the provision were included in legislation other than an appropriations bill; and (2) results in a net decrease in budget authority in the current year or the budget year, but does not result in a net decrease in outlays over the period of the total of the current year, the budget year, and all fiscal years covered under the most recently adopted budget resolution.

The points of order do not apply if the difference between the amount in the Crime Victims Fund as of September 30 of the fiscal year immediately preceding the fiscal year to which the CHIMP relates and the amount available for obligation under the CHIMP is not more than $2 billion.</summary>
</bill>
