<bill session="119" type="s" number="1291" updated="2026-06-09T12:27:59Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CLEAN FTZ Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAN FTZ Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Containing and Limiting the Extensive Abuses Noticed in Free Trade Zones Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to identify and evaluate the compliance of foreign free trade zones with international standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2025-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-09T12:23:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Containing and Limiting the Extensive Abuses Noticed in Free Trade Zones Act of 2025 or the CLEAN&#160;FTZ Act of 2025

This bill creates a system to classify countries based on compliance with international standards within their free trade zones and establishes related penalties. (Free trade zones are designated areas, typically located at or near ports, that contain production facilities and related infrastructure. Generally, these zones are treated as being outside the customs territory despite being physically located inside the geographic boundaries of countries.)

Specifically, U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) must identify, publish, and update a list of non-U.S. free trade zones that includes the identity, location, and administrators of each zone.

Upon publication of the list of zones,&#160;CBP must then publish a classification of the countries in which those zones are located into four tiers based on specified standards (e.g., complying with international standards and countering illicit international trade). CBP must notify the government of each country of the tier to which the country was classified and periodically review the tier classification.&#160;

The bill directs CBP to take additional actions with respect to countries classified as tier II, III, or IV, such as creating a hotline for reporting instances of illicit international trade.

The bill also establishes related penalties, such as authorizing the President to impose property- and visa-blocking sanctions on any foreign person that has facilitated or supported illicit international trade within a zone located in a country classified as tier II, III, or IV.</summary>
</bill>
