<bill session="119" type="h" number="5911" updated="2026-06-04T08:06:05Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-02T15:16:29-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-02T15:16:29-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crystal Reservoir Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Crystal Reservoir Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Crystal Reservoir Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the City of Ouray, Colorado, certain land managed by the Forest Service, together with a reservoir.</title>
    <title type="official">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the City of Ouray, Colorado, certain land managed by the Forest Service, together with a reservoir.</title>
    <title type="display">Crystal Reservoir Conveyance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 119-662.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-05-20" calendar="Union" number="576">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 576.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-02T15:05:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-02T15:05:19-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3752-3754" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-02T15:05:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5911.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-06-02T15:16:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3752-3753" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-02T15:16:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2754" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-29T15:19:05Z" status="Reported to House">Crystal Reservoir Conveyance Act

This bill directs the Forest Service to convey specified property and water rights in&#160;Ouray County, Colorado, to the City of Ouray, Colorado, for use as open space for recreational activities (such as fishing) at no cost to the public.

The property and water rights include the site known as Crystal Reservoir and the associated lake and infrastructure, Full Moon Dam and the associated facilities, and the approximately 45-acre parcel of land underlying and surrounding Crystal Reservoir.

The conveyance must (1) convey fee simple title to the land; (2) be subject to existing valid rights and easements; and (3) be completed at no cost to the city, except for costs related to necessary surveys.

The conveyance must also be subject to a reversionary interest whereby if the land is used in a manner that violates the conveyance, the land shall revert to the United States, subject to the discretion of the Forest Service.&#160;

In addition to holding the land open to the public for recreational purposes, the city must assume responsibly for Full Moon Dam and must not conduct unneeded development or commercial operations, nor alter Crystal Reservoir in a manner that would harm wetlands located upstream, subject to certain conditions.&#160;

After the completion of this conveyance, the Forest Service&#160;must recognize a perpetual easement for the site known as Red Mountain Ditch for use by the city&#160;for specified activities related to Crystal Reservoir.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
