<bill session="119" type="h" number="4930" updated="2026-04-29T10:56:41Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-27T15:09:28-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-04-27T15:09:28-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-08-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the sharing of information with respect to suspected violations of intellectual property rights in trade.</title>
    <title type="official">To expand the sharing of information with respect to suspected violations of intellectual property rights in trade.</title>
    <title type="display">To expand the sharing of information with respect to suspected violations of intellectual property rights in trade.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001126" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2025-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2025-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-08-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 40 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-30">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 119-415.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-12-30" calendar="Union" number="361">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 361.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-04-27T15:00:36-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Moore (UT) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-27T15:00:56-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3098-3100" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-27T15:00:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4930.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-04-27T15:09:28-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3098-3099" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-04-27T15:09:33-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2677" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-23T13:58:11Z" status="Reported to House">This bill expands the authority of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to provide information to&#160;certain persons (e.g., trademark or copyright owners) regarding suspected violations of intellectual property rights in trade.&#160;

Under current law, if&#160;CBP suspects that merchandise is being imported in violation of certain trademark and copyright laws,&#160;it may request assistance from specified persons when determining whether the merchandise is imported in violation of these laws. To permit the party to conduct examination and testing, CBP must provide them with specified information that appears on the merchandise and&#160;its packaging and labels.&#160;

This bill (1) expands the definition of person to allow CBP to request assistance from any other appropriate party with an interest in the imported merchandise, and (2) expands the scope of information that CBP is authorized to share with others to include information on and images of&#160;packing materials and containers.

The bill allows CBP to request this assistance if it has a reasonable suspicion (currently, suspects) that the merchandise being imported is in violation of certain trademark and copyright laws.

Additionally,&#160;CBP may provide a person with nonpublic information about the imported merchandise that was generated by an online marketplace or similar market platform, express&#160;consignment operator, freight forwarder, or any other entity that plays a role in the sale, importation, or facilitation&#160;of the merchandise&#160;into the United States and has been provided to, shared with, or obtained by CBP. CBP must&#160;provide the person with notification of the transmitted information.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-415</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
