<bill session="119" type="h" number="6192" updated="2026-05-16T08:07:44Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fertilizer Research Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fertilizer Research Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to publish a report on the fertilizer industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2025-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2025-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2026-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2025-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2025-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2808" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-12-10T11:27:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Fertilizer Research Act of 2025

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture to publish on the department's website a report on the U.S. fertilizer industry. Among other things, the report must include

a description of the impacts on the fertilizer industry that influence the prices that agricultural producers receive for their products;a description of the size and value of the U.S. fertilizer market over the previous 25 years;a description of the importation of fertilizer into the United States and the impacts that antidumping and countervailing duties have on retail fertilizer prices;a study of market concentration of the U.S. fertilizer industry;an assessment of the regulatory environment governing fertilizer production, distribution, and usage; anda description of the extent to which current public price reporting of fertilizer is transparent for market participants and recommendations on whether further reporting is needed.&#160;&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
