<bill session="119" type="s" number="1427" updated="2026-06-30T15:14:09Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Audit the IRS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Audit the IRS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that persons having seriously delinquent tax debts shall be ineligible for employment by the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-30T15:12:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Audit the IRS Act&#160;

This bill prohibits an individual who has a seriously delinquent tax debt from being appointed or continuing to serve as an officer, employee, or contract employee of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).

The bill defines seriously delinquent tax debt as any tax debt for which the IRS has filed a notice of a tax lien other than a tax debt (1) that is being paid in a timely manner pursuant to an&#160;installment agreement or offer in compromise, or (2) for which a collection due process hearing or innocent spouse relief is requested or pending.

The bill requires the IRS to verify annually that IRS officers, employees, and contract employees do not have a seriously delinquent tax debt. The IRS also must verify that applicants for such positions do not have a seriously delinquent tax debt prior to hiring.

Finally, the bill requires Office of Personnel Management to issue regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
