<bill session="119" type="s" number="4074" updated="2026-04-01T13:01:20Z">
  <state datetime="2026-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make continuing appropriations for essential Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency pay and operations in the event of a Federal Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fund CISA Personnel Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fund CISA Personnel Act of 2026</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-01T12:58:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fund CISA Personnel Act of 2026

This bill provides continuing appropriations to provide pay and benefits to Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA)&#160; employees during the partial Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shutdown that began on February 14, 2026. (A partial government shutdown is currently in effect for CISA and other DHS&#160;agencies because the FY2026 DHS appropriations bill has not been enacted and continuing appropriations for DHS are not in effect.)

Specifically, the bill provides FY2026 continuing appropriations to provide standard rates of pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments otherwise payable on a regular basis to CISA employees during the period in which interim or full-year FY2026 appropriations are not in effect.

The bill provides the continuing appropriations until the earlier of (1) the enactment into law of the applicable appropriations legislation, or (2) September 30, 2026.&#160;

The bill must take effect as if it had been enacted on February 13, 2026.</summary>
</bill>
