<bill session="119" type="h" number="3726" updated="2026-05-22T02:38:26Z">
  <state datetime="2026-05-19T16:42:05-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-05-19T16:42:05-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fisher House Availability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fisher House Availability Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fisher House Availability Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make temporary lodging facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs available for certain TRICARE beneficiaries on a space-available basis, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make temporary lodging facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs available for certain individuals on a space available basis, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fisher House Availability Act of 2026</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2025-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Health Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 119-630.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-30" calendar="Union" number="546">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 546.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T16:29:23-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bost moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T16:29:36-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3577-3579" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T16:29:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3726.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2026-05-19T16:42:05-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3577" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T16:42:08-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-19T16:42:09-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-15T18:53:12Z" status="Reported to House">Fisher House Availability Act of 2026

This bill expands eligibility for temporary lodging at a Fisher House to additional individuals receiving medical care or treatment at a Department of Veteran Affairs (VA) or non-VA facility or those accompanying individuals receiving such treatment. (Fisher Houses are where the VA furnishes no-cost lodging to veterans and other eligible individuals when receiving treatment or accompanying an individual receiving treatment.)

Specifically, the bill authorizes the VA to provide lodging at a Fisher House on a space-available basis to

members of the uniformed services performing active duty (i.e., covered beneficiaries) who must travel a significant distance to receive care or services;family members and others accompanying such covered beneficiaries to receive care or services;veterans, members of a veteran's family, and others who must travel a significant distance for a member of a veteran's family to receive care or services; andcovered beneficiaries, members of a covered beneficiary&#8217;s family, and others who must travel a significant distance for a member of a beneficiary&#8217;s family to receive care or services.Finally, the bill extends the limitation on pension amounts for certain hospitalized or institutionalized veterans through July 31, 2033.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-630</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
