<bill session="119" type="h" number="3135" updated="2026-04-14T20:31:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RACE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RACE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulation Advancement for Capital Enhancement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Act of 1933 to automatically qualify offering statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission in connection with certain securities issued under Regulation A tier 2, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-14T20:27:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Regulation Advancement for Capital Enhancement Act of 2025 or the RACE Act of 2025

This bill allows issuers with offerings that were previously exempted from securities registration requirements to issue an additional class of securities if certain criteria are met.

Specifically, this bill allows an issuer who issued securities under Regulation A&#160;(a small offering of securities exempt from registration requirements)&#160;to issue an additional class of securities if the securities in the additional class are substantially similar to the original class and the offering amount does not exceed specified dollar limits. However, the securities offered in the additional class are not required to have the same nature or terms.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
