<bill session="119" type="h" number="7399" updated="2026-05-28T15:43:34Z">
  <state datetime="2026-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Kids Off Social Media Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kids Off Social Media Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Eyes on the Board Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit users who are under age 13 from accessing social media platforms, to prohibit the use of personalized recommendation systems on individuals under age 17, and limit the use of social media in schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7433" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="278" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-22T12:38:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Kids Off Social Media Act

This bill limits children&#8217;s access to social media platforms and requires both platforms and schools to implement certain restrictions on children&#8217;s social media usage.&#160;

Specifically, the bill prohibits social media platforms from knowingly allowing children under the age of 13 to create or maintain accounts. Platforms must delete existing accounts held by children and any personal data collected from child users. Platforms are also generally prohibited from using automated systems to suggest or promote content based on personal data collected from users under the age of 17. The bill directs the Federal Trade Commission to enforce these provisions. States may also bring civil actions against platforms whose violations of these provisions have adversely affected their residents.&#160;

Further, as a condition of receiving discounted telecommunications service under the Schools and Libraries Universal Service Support (E-Rate) program, schools must enforce policies preventing the use of E-Rate-supported services, networks, and devices to access social media, and must use blocking or filtering technology to prevent such access. Schools that do not make a good faith effort to comply and correct known violations are required to reimburse any E-Rate support they received for the applicable period.&#160;Schools must also submit copies of their internet safety policies to the Federal Communications Commission for publication.&#160;

Under the bill, social media platforms are defined as public-facing sites that function primarily as forums for user-generated content. Some categories of online platforms are explicitly excluded, including sites that provide primarily videoconferencing, emailing, or educational services.</summary>
</bill>
