<bill session="119" type="h" number="6387" updated="2026-04-14T00:07:14Z">
  <state datetime="2026-01-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fire Improvement and Reforming Exceptional Events Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">FIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fire Improvement and Reforming Exceptional Events Act</title>
    <title type="display">FIRE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to require revisions to regulations governing the review and handling of air quality monitoring data influenced by exceptional events or actions to mitigate wildfire risk.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001137" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2025-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000605" joined="2025-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 13 - 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-09">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 119-595.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-04-09" calendar="Union" number="515">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 515.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-14T00:06:37Z" status="Reported to House">Fire Improvement and Reforming Exceptional Events Act or the FIRE Act

This bill modifies the definition of exceptional events under the Clean Air Act and requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to revise its regulations regarding exceptional events or actions to mitigate wildfire risk.

Generally, the EPA must exclude data from use in determinations of&#160;exceedances and violations of national ambient air quality standards (NAAQS) if a state demonstrates that an exceptional event caused a specific air pollution concentration.

The bill provides that events caused by human activity that are intended to mirror the occurrence or reoccurrence of a natural event are exceptional events. Additionally, the bill no longer excludes from consideration as an exceptional event (1) meteorological events involving high temperatures or a lack of precipitation, or (2)&#160;stagnation of air masses that does not ordinarily occur.

The bill requires the EPA to revise regulations regarding the reviewing and handling of air quality monitoring data influenced by actions to mitigate wildfire risk.

The bill also requires the EPA to conduct regional modeling and analysis when multiple states submit petitions regarding the same exceptional event or action to mitigate wildfire risk.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-595</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
