<bill session="119" type="h" number="2424" updated="2026-05-30T08:05:51Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modern, Clean, and Safe Trucks Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modern, Clean, and Safe Trucks Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the excise tax on heavy trucks and trailers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000578"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2026-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2026-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001100" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000585" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001222" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2026-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000135" joined="2026-05-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-30T11:15:03-04:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Mr. LaHood asked unanimous consent that he may hereafter be considered as the first sponsor of H.R. 2424, a bill originally introduced by Representative LaMalfa, for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-17T14:15:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Modern, Clean, and Safe Trucks Act of 2025

This bill repeals the 12% federal excise tax imposed on the first retail sale of certain heavy trucks, trailers, and tractors that generally are used on the highway.

As background, a 12% federal excise tax is imposed on the sale price (of the first retail sale) of

truck bodies and chassis suitable for use with a vehicle having a gross vehicle weight of over 33,000 pounds;truck trailer and semitrailer bodies and chassis suitable for use with a vehicle having a gross vehicle weight over 26,000 pounds; andtractors that are generally used for highway transportation in combination with a trailer or semitrailer, have a gross vehicle weight over 19,500 pounds, and have a gross combined&#160;weight of greater than 33,000 pounds.Amounts collected from the excise tax on the retail sale of heavy trucks, trailers, and tractors are deposited into the Highway Trust Fund. (The Highway Trust Fund supports surface transportation programs and projects.)

Under current law, the excise tax on the retail sale of heavy trucks, trailers, and tractors expires on October 1, 2028.</summary>
</bill>
