<bill session="119" type="s" number="2735" updated="2026-05-21T11:03:37Z">
  <state datetime="2026-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians Land Transfer Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians Land Transfer Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to take certain Federal land in the State of California into trust for the benefit of the Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2025-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6403" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2302" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-07T13:12:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians Land Transfer Act of 2025

This bill takes approximately 265 acres&#160;of specified lands in El Dorado County, California, into trust for the benefit of the Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians.

The bill revokes a specified public land order and administratively transfers the land from the Forest Service to the Department of the Interior. (In the public land order, the land was designated for use by the Forest Service as an experiment station.)

The bill directs Interior to take the following lands into trust for the benefit of the tribe: (1) approximately 80 acres of federal land managed by Interior's Bureau of Land Management (which includes the land transferred&#160;from the Forest Service), and (2) approximately 185 acres of fee land held by the tribe. These combined lands, approximately 265&#160;acres, shall be part of the tribe's reservation. Further, the bill prohibits gaming on the land taken into trust.</summary>
</bill>
