<bill session="119" type="h" number="8199" updated="2026-05-15T08:07:50Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SCHEDULES Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCHEDULES Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Scheduling for Community Health and Easy Data to Understand for Legislators to Evaluate Services Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a comprehensive standard for timing between referrals and appointments for care from the Department of Veterans Affairs and to submit a report with respect to that standard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2026-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2026-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001220" joined="2026-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2026-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2026-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000622" joined="2026-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2026-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000830" joined="2026-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="4229" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-06T14:43:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Scheduling for Community Health and Easy Data to Understand for Legislators to Evaluate Services Act of 2026 or the SCHEDULES Act of 2026

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a standard for timing between the date on which a referral for VA care is entered into the VA's system and the date on which an appointment for care occurs, whether at a VA facility or through care in the community.

The VA must publish the standard in the Federal Register and on a publicly accessible VA website. Additionally, the VA must submit a report at least quarterly on the number and percentage of referrals that meet the new timing standard.</summary>
</bill>
