<bill session="119" type="h" number="701" updated="2026-03-09T16:56:08Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REDUCE Food Prices Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REDUCE Food Prices Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Establishment Deductions and Uplifting Competition to Ease Food Prices Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for the establishment and operation of small food retail businesses in areas with high food retail concentration and low levels of competition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001207"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-09T16:54:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Establishment Deductions and Uplifting Competition to Ease Food Prices Act or the REDUCE Food Prices Act

This bill establishes a new tax credit for certain food retail businesses. The bill also increases bonus depreciation, the qualified business income (QBI) tax deduction, the rehabilitation tax credit (also known as the historic preservation tax credit), and the work opportunity tax credit (WOTC) for the businesses.

The bill establishes a new tax credit (as part of the general business tax credit) in the amount of 15% of certain capital investments by a qualified small food retail business in the first three years of operation.

The bill defines a qualified small food retail business as a private or closely-held company, a partnership, or a sole proprietorship (1) with annual average gross receipts of $200 million or less for the three tax years preceding the current tax year, (2) with at least 70% of its annual average gross receipts attributable to the retail sale of food or produce, and (3) located in a low-competition area.

The bill also increases

bonus depreciation percentages for certain property placed into service by a qualified small food retail business,the QBI tax deduction for&#160;qualified small food retail business,the rehabilitation tax credit for qualified rehabilitation expenses incurred by a qualified small food retail business, andthe&#160;WOTC for wages paid by a qualified small food retail business to eligible workers.</summary>
</bill>
