<bill session="119" type="h" number="1903" updated="2026-02-27T16:32:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congressional Trade Authority Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Trade Authority Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 to impose limitations on the authority of the President to adjust imports that are determined to threaten to impair national security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2025-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2025-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000598" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2025-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000273" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001217" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2025-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2025-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000830" joined="2025-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-27T16:29:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Trade Authority Act of 2025

This bill requires congressional approval for a presidential import adjustment due to a national security threat from an import and limits the adjustments to certain goods that are essential to national security.

Specifically, the bill limits the President's authority for such import adjustments to goods&#160;related to the development, maintenance, or protection of&#160;military equipment, energy resources, or critical infrastructure essential to national security. The bill specifies that the term national security (1)&#160;means the protection of the United States from foreign aggression, and (2)&#160;does not otherwise include the protection of the general welfare of the United States.

 The bill requires the President to submit a proposal to Congress to adjust imports. Congress must&#160;then approve the proposal with a joint resolution before an import adjustment takes effect.&#160;Under current law, the President determines whether any adjustment of an import is necessary and must submit to Congress the reasons for any action taken or not taken.&#160;Currently, there is a congressional disapproval mechanism to override presidential actions related to petroleum imports.

The bill also requires the Department of Defense (currently, the Department of Commerce) to investigate the effect of these imports on national security and submit a report before the President determines whether an adjustment to an import is&#160;necessary.

The bill retroactively applies to any proposed action made six years before enactment of this bill.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
