<bill session="119" type="h" number="8312" updated="2026-06-12T13:03:24Z">
  <state datetime="2026-06-10T16:17:26-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-06-10T16:17:26-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fraud Prevention and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fraud Prevention and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fraud Prevention and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish fraud prevention and program integrity functions and data sharing authorities within the Department of Treasury and a permanent governmentwide Inspector General for Fraud, Accountability, and Recovery, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official">To establish fraud prevention and program integrity functions and data sharing authorities within the Department of Treasury and a permanent governmentwide Inspector General for Fraud, Accountability, and Recovery, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Fraud Prevention and Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000480" joined="2026-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-03">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 119-683.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-06-03" calendar="Union" number="596">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 596.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-06-08T19:22:01-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1345 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8312, H.R. 8464, H. Res. 1335 and S. 2. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8312, H.R. 8464, H. Res. 1335, and S. 2 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for a motion to recommit H.R. 8312 and H.R. 8464 and a motion to commit S. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-10T12:11:49-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1345.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4065-4071" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-10T12:11:54-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8312, H.R. 8464, H. Res. 1335 and S. 2. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8312, H.R. 8464, H. Res. 1335, and S. 2 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution provides for a motion to recommit H.R. 8312 and H.R. 8464 and a motion to commit S. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-10T12:12:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 8312.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-10T12:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-10T12:37:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.R. 8312, the Chair put the question on passage and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Walkinshaw demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-10T16:10:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4077-4078" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="218" datetime="2026-06-10T16:17:26-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 181 (Roll no. 218).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4065-4069" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2026-06-10T16:17:27-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-06-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1345" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Data collection, sharing, protection"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h228"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2026-06-06T20:58:50Z" status="Reported to House">Fraud Prevention and Accountability Act

This bill (1) assigns financial integrity, improper payment prevention, and spending transparency functions to the Bureau of the Fiscal Service (BFS) within the Department of the Treasury; (2) establishes an Office of the Inspector General for Fraud, Accountability, and Recovery (OIGFAR) within Treasury; and (3) requires Treasury to enter into data sharing agreements with other federal agencies and allowable private entities to prevent fraud and improper payments.

Functions assigned to&#160;BFS by the bill include

administering the Do Not Pay system (which provides federal agencies and federally funded state-administered programs the ability to verify recipient identity and eligibility before making an award or issuing a payment);maintaining a voluntary governmentwide program to provide data sharing and analysis to federal agencies and to state, local, or tribal governments responsible for administering a federally funded program in order to detect fraud and prevent improper payments that result in financial loss; andsupporting&#160;OIGFAR by providing access to information technology and data.The duties of&#160;OIGFAR include auditing and investigating the use of certain federal funds, such as

funds, loans, and tax credits made available by various&#160;coronavirus response laws;any federal award of $50,000 or more;&#160;andemergency spending related to disaster relief or economic recovery.OIGFAR must ensure the expeditious reporting of suspected violations of federal criminal law to the Department of Justice. OIGFAR is authorized to provide investigative support to prosecutive and enforcement authorities to protect program integrity and prevent, detect, and prosecute fraud.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-683</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
