<bill session="119" type="s" number="4512" updated="2026-06-08T19:52:41Z">
  <state datetime="2026-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Affordable Insulin Now Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Insulin Now Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for appropriate cost-sharing for insulin products covered under private health plans, and to establish a program to support health care providers and pharmacies in providing discounted insulin products to uninsured individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-08T19:52:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Affordable Insulin Now Act of 2026

This bill limits cost-sharing for insulin under private health insurance and establishes a program to provide insulin to individuals without insurance.

Specifically, the bill caps cost-sharing under private health insurance for a month's supply of selected insulin products at $35 or 25% of a plan's negotiated price (after any price concessions), whichever is less, beginning in 2027.

Further, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must enter into agreements with pharmacies or health care providers to provide insulin to individuals without insurance. HHS must pay such pharmacies or providers an amount equal to the difference between the out-of-pocket cost to the individual for a 30-day supply of such insulin products and $35.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
