<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2247</number>
    <updateDate>2026-02-20T19:36:15Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2026-02-20T19:36:15Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2025-07-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>119</congress>
    <legislationUrl>https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/senate-bill/2247</legislationUrl>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2025-07-10T16:40:55Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2025-07-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S4316-4317)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2025-07-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000800</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Welch, Peter [D-VT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Peter</firstName>
        <lastName>Welch</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Emergency Management</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Emergency Management</name>
        <updateDate>2025-07-30T21:56:53Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2025-07-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2026-02-20T19:29:42Z</updateDate>
        <cdata>
          <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaster Assistance Improvement and Decentralization Act or the Disaster AID Act&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This bill increases, expedites, and facilitates access to disaster and hazard mitigation assistance from the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). It also increases flexibility for compensating FEMA employees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill allows FEMA’s Public Assistance (PA) program to provide greater assistance before recipients incur project costs (i.e., advance assistance), increase funding for management costs, and expand the use of simplified application procedures. Also, FEMA’s Hazard Mitigation Grant Program (HMGP) may increase the maximum federal cost share from 75% to 85% for  jurisdictions with a low capacity for investment in disaster resilience and increase the maximum advance assistance from 25% to 50% of project cost.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill also allows PA and HMGP recipients to use unexpended management cost funds for additional disaster resilience activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, under current law, FEMA may set aside funding from the Disaster Relief Fund for predisaster mitigation. The bill requires&amp;nbsp;FEMA to set aside and use such funds to provide a minimum annual amount of grant funding for predisaster mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the bill establishes grants for hazard mitigation offices and post-disaster FEMA training on obtaining assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if obligated FEMA disaster funding is not disbursed within 26 business days, FEMA must explain the delay and provide status updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the bill allows FEMA to simultaneously provide both retirement benefits and salary for certain employees. Also, it allows a tax deduction to&amp;nbsp;FEMA employees for expenses while away from home in excess of one year.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
        </cdata>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Disaster Assistance Improvement and Decentralization Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Disaster Assistance Improvement and Decentralization Act</title>
        <updateDate>2025-07-30T12:38:27Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Disaster Assistance Improvement and Decentralization Act</title>
        <updateDate>2025-07-30T12:38:25Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to enhance local capacity and expand local control over the disaster response, recovery, and preparedness process, to guarantee stable Federal funding streams for disaster-impacted communities, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2025-07-30T12:33:49Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2025-07-10T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-119s2247is/xml/BILLS-119s2247is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2025-07-10</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S4316-4317)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
