<bill session="119" type="h" number="2989" updated="2026-05-18T15:20:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Time to Choose Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Time to Choose Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit conflicts of interest among consulting firms that simultaneously contract with China or other covered foreign entities and the United States Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001327"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="731" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-18T15:20:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Time to Choose Act of 2025

This bill prohibits the federal government from awarding consulting services contracts to any entity that provides consulting services to covered foreign entities.

Foreign entities covered by the bill include

the government of China, the Chinese Communist Party, the People's Liberation Army, or any Chinese security service or intelligence agency;the government of Russia or any entity sanctioned under Executive Order 13662;the government of any country determined by the Department of State to have repeatedly provided support for international terrorism; andany entity on certain lists maintained by the Department of Commerce, such as the Denied Persons List or the Military End User List.An agency may waive the prohibition on a case-by-case basis if it is in the national security interests of the United States and no other entity without a conflict of interest can perform the work.</summary>
</bill>
