<bill session="119" type="s" number="3777" updated="2026-03-30T20:35:18Z">
  <state datetime="2026-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2026-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rebuild America&#8217;s Schools Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rebuild America&#8217;s Schools Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the long-term improvement of public school facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2026-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2026-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2026-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2026-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2026-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S491" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="7340" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-30T20:34:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rebuild America's Schools Act of 2026

This bill provides support for long-term improvements to public elementary and secondary school facilities.

First, the bill sets forth allocations to states and establishes a need-based grant program for local educational agencies (LEAs) to improve school facilities. Further, the bill specifies allowable uses of grant funds, including carrying out major repairs, improving indoor air quality, and making facilities accessible to individuals with disabilities.

Additionally, the bill requires LEAs that receive funds for new construction, modernization, or renovation projects to comply with hazard-resistance building codes and performance criteria under the WaterSense program of the Environmental Protection Agency. Further, the bill requires such LEAs to adopt certain green practices (environmental standards) and requires the use of iron, steel, and manufactured products that are made in the United States (Buy America).

The bill restores school infrastructure tax credit bonds.

The bill also sets forth reporting requirements, including annual reports on grant program projects and a report by the Government Accountability Office that requires a study of the geographic distribution of projects, the impact of selected projects on student and staff health and safety, and the accessibility of projects to high-needs schools.

The bill also establishes the Office of School Infrastructure and Sustainability within the Department of Education.

Next, the bill extends through FY2031 the Impact Aid Construction program.

Finally, the bill establishes a grant program to assist LEAs with repairing or replacing concrete foundations affected by pyrrhotite (an iron sulfide material linked to crumbling foundations).</summary>
</bill>
