<bill session="119" type="h" number="5270" updated="2026-04-01T15:50:33Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stress Testing Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Stress Testing Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="display">Stress Testing Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to issue rules to establish certain methodologies and scenarios used in stress testing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2025-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2025-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-04">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 119-366.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-11-04" calendar="Union" number="318">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 318.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-04-01T15:49:01Z" status="Reported to House">Stress Testing Accountability and Transparency Act

This bill requires the Federal Reserve Board to make public certain details concerning annual stress tests performed by the board and prohibits certain stress test practices. (Stress tests assess a financial institution&#8217;s response to a hypothetical disruptive economic event. The board sets an institution&#8217;s capital requirements or stress capital buffer based on the results.)&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires the board to issue a rule that establishes the models, assumptions, and methods used by the board to perform annual stress tests on certain nonbank financial companies and large bank holding companies. The board must also issue a rule determining the stress capital buffer requirement for certain companies that have at least two results from periodic stress tests. In addition, the board must disclose annually each scenario to be used in stress testing.

Further, the board is prohibited from materially changing stress test methodologies outside of the rulemaking process. The board must also ensure that stress capital buffer requirements and risk-based capital requirements do not contain capital requirements for the same risks. The board is also prohibited from performing climate-related stress tests.&#160;

The Government Accountability Office must report on the effectiveness of the stress tests every three years.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-366</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
