<bill session="119" type="s" number="1985" updated="2026-03-26T18:29:31Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe Operations of Shared Airspace Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Operations of Shared Airspace Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve aviation safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2025-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2025-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2025-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2025-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-03-26T18:26:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safe Operations of Shared Airspace Act of 2025

This bill addresses aviation safety, such as through increasing&#160;requirements for aircraft tracking,&#160;communication, and coordination with the military. The bill also addresses&#160;Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) workforce issues.

For example, the bill revises and increases requirements for using&#160;Automatic Dependent Surveillance-Broadcast&#160;(ADS-B) equipment, which transmits information (e.g., location and weather information) between aircraft and air traffic control.

Under the bill, aircraft must generally operate with ADS-B In (receiving) equipment. The FAA must issue performance requirements for the equipment to provide safety-enhancing capabilities (e.g., facilitating aircraft collision avoidance) for flight crews.

Further, current FAA regulations allow aircraft performing a sensitive government mission to be excepted from requirements for using ADS-B Out (broadcasting)&#160;equipment. This bill limits which flights may be considered sensitive government missions (e.g., not training flights).

The FAA must also (1) establish an office to coordinate airspace usage of military aircraft, (2) review the safety of certain&#160;flight operations and routes around airports, and (3) enter into memoranda of understanding with military agencies for safety information sharing.

The FAA must&#160;conduct a Transport Airplane Risk Assessment Methodology analysis for any transport airplane accidents in the United States that result in a fatality.

The bill also addresses FAA workforce issues, such as by

excluding the FAA workforce from a federal hiring freeze, deferred resignation program, voluntary furlough, or reduction in force;supporting the recruitment and training of air traffic controllers; andrequiring strict adherence to federal conflict of interest requirements.</summary>
</bill>
