<bill session="119" type="s" number="3040" updated="2026-02-23T12:29:49Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Edith Nourse Rogers STEM Scholarship Opportunity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Edith Nourse Rogers STEM Scholarship Opportunity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to modify the requirements of the Edith Nourse Rogers STEM Scholarship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2034" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-23T12:29:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Edith Nourse Rogers STEM Scholarship Opportunity Act of 2025

This bill expands eligibility for and modifies administration of the Edith&#160;Nourse Rogers STEM Scholarship. The scholarship allows individuals who are entitled to Post-9/11 GI Bill educational assistance and are pursuing eligible degrees in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, or health care to receive up to nine additional months of benefits (capped at $30,000).

The bill eliminates the requirement that an individual must have less than 180 days of remaining educational assistance entitlement (or no entitlement remaining) to be eligible for the scholarship.

Additionally, the bill reduces by 25% the number of credits an individual must have completed in order to be eligible for the scholarship.

In situations where there are insufficient funds available in a fiscal year, the bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs to give priority to individuals who have used the most months of their educational assistance entitlement and those who are using their entitlement to pursue a program of post-secondary education in specified fields (e.g., engineering).

The bill specifies that individuals who receive the scholarship benefit may only use the benefit after they have used all of their educational assistance entitlement under the Post-9/11 GI Bill.</summary>
</bill>
