<bill session="119" type="s" number="993" updated="2026-05-28T13:26:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Lunch Debt Cancellation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Lunch Debt Cancellation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to cancel existing school meal debt, to expand the authority of the Commodity Credit Corporation for use in nutrition assistance programming, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-28T13:21:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">School Lunch Debt Cancellation Act of 2025

This bill (1) requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to cancel school meal debts, and (2) expands USDA's authority to use&#160;Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) funds for the Commodity Supplemental Food Program (CSFP) and the Emergency Food Assistance Program (TEFAP).

Specifically, USDA must cancel and eliminate all household school meal debts (as of the date of the bill's enactment) under the school breakfast and lunch programs. USDA must also pay the amount of the cancelled debt to each local educational authority using CCC funds.

The bill also reauthorizes the CSFP&#160;through FY2030 and allows USDA to use&#160;CCC&#160;funds for the program. As background, CSFP works to improve the health of low-income persons at least 60 years of age by supplementing their diets with nutritious USDA foods.

In addition, the bill specifies that USDA may use CCC funds for all aspects of TEFAP. In recent years, USDA has used CCC funds for specific TEFAP activities. As background, through TEFAP, USDA purchases a variety of food commodities.&#160;TEFAP provides those food commodities (and cash support for storage and distribution costs) to state agencies that distribute the food&#160;to local emergency feeding organizations (e.g., food banks).</summary>
</bill>
