<bill session="119" type="h" number="3159" updated="2026-02-26T22:07:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving SCRA Benefit Utilization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving SCRA Benefit Utilization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to include training regarding financial protections under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act in certain financial literacy training programs for members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001324" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2025-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001098" joined="2025-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001066" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001159" joined="2025-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2025-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-01-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-02-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1550" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-26T22:00:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving SCRA Benefit Utilization Act

This bill expands interest rate protections under the&#160;Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (SCRA) and requires expanded training for and outreach to servicemembers regarding financial literacy and SCRA protections.

The SCRA caps the maximum interest charged on any debt incurred by a servicemember prior to entering active duty at 6% annually if the servicemember's ability to pay is materially affected by active-duty status; servicemembers must provide notice and other documentation to creditors to receive this cap.

The bill requires creditors to apply this&#160;cap to all of a&#160;servicemember&#8217;s obligations or liabilities with that creditor, regardless of whether a certain obligation or liability was specifically mentioned in the required notice provided by the member to invoke SCRA rights.&#160;Further, the bill requires creditors to provide all necessary mechanisms to ensure a&#160;servicemember is able to submit any required documentation.

The bill also requires that the financial literacy training program provided to servicemembers&#160;include information about consumer financial protections afforded to such members and their dependents, including protections regarding interest rate limits under the&#160;SCRA.



Additionally, the bill requires the military department concerned to provide written notice of benefits under the&#160;SCRA to servicemembers at the time they first enter military service and, for members of the reserve components, at the time they first enter service in the reserves and at any time when they are mobilized or ordered to active duty for more than 30 days.</summary>
</bill>
