<bill session="119" type="s" number="671" updated="2026-06-12T13:12:04Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Inspector General for Ukraine Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspector General for Ukraine Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of the Inspector General for Ukraine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-12T13:11:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Inspector General for Ukraine Act

This bill establishes the Office of the Inspector General for Ukraine, led by the Inspector General for Ukraine&#160;who shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate.

The duties of the office include

conducting, supervising, and coordinating audits and investigations of the amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the military and nonmilitary support of Ukraine, and of the programs, operations, and contracts carried out utilizing such funds;establishing, maintaining, and overseeing such systems, procedures, and controls as the office considers appropriate for such audits and investigations; andcoordinating with the Offices of Inspector General of the Department of Defense (DOD), the Department of State, and the U.S. Agency for International Development.Whenever information or assistance requested by the office is unreasonably refused or not provided, the office shall report the circumstances to the State Department or DOD, as appropriate, and to Congress without delay.

The office shall submit a report to Congress on a quarterly basis.</summary>
</bill>
