<bill session="119" type="h" number="3536" updated="2026-06-04T15:07:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CRISIS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Russian Innovation and Safeguarding Individual Scientists Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CRISIS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide certain nationals of Russia with special immigrant status, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2025-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-06-04T15:07:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Countering Russian Innovation and Safeguarding Individual Scientists Act of 2025 or the CRISIS Act of 2025

This bill makes certain Russian nationals with degrees in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) eligible to become permanent residents of the United States.

Under the bill, special immigrant status may be given to Russian nationals (and their spouse and children) who have a U.S. doctoral degree or a foreign equivalent in a STEM field and are seeking work in a STEM field in the United States. Candidates must satisfy vetting and interview requirements set by the Department of Homeland Security.

Up to 3,000 individuals may be admitted under this bill each fiscal year FY2026 through FY2029. Individuals&#160;admitted under this bill do not count towards other statutory numerical limitations for immigration.</summary>
</bill>
