<bill session="119" type="s" number="1156" updated="2026-04-16T11:03:24Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Food Secure Strikers Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Secure Strikers Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to ensure that striking workers and their households do not become ineligible for benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2026-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2025-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2357" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-02-04T11:44:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Food Secure Strikers Act of 2025&#160;

This bill allows certain&#160;striking workers&#160;and their households&#160;to&#160;maintain their eligibility for the&#160;Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP).

Specifically, the bill provides that a household that would otherwise be eligible to participate in SNAP is eligible for benefits&#160;if any member of the household is&#160;on strike because of a labor dispute. Current law generally prohibits a household from participating in SNAP if any member of the household is on strike unless the household was eligible for SNAP immediately prior to the strike. Also, under current law, households are not eligible for an increased SNAP allotment as a result of the decreased income of a striking member of the household. The bill expands SNAP eligibility for households with striking workers by repealing both of these restrictions.

The bill also allows&#160;a government employee who is dismissed for&#160;striking and their household&#160;to maintain SNAP program eligibility. Specifically, current law prohibits certain individuals who voluntarily and without good cause quit a job from participating in SNAP. Further, a federal, state, or local government&#160;employee who participates in a strike against the government that results in their dismissal is considered&#160;to have voluntarily quit without good cause. The bill eliminates the provision that considers the&#160;dismissed government employee to have voluntarily quit without good cause, thereby allowing the employee and their household&#160;to maintain SNAP program eligibility if they are otherwise eligible for the program.</summary>
</bill>
