<bill session="119" type="h" number="8365" updated="2026-05-14T03:41:22Z">
  <state datetime="2026-04-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2026-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2026-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Monitor Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Monitor Accountability Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Monitor Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for conditions on the appointment of monitors by courts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000478" joined="2026-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2026-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2026-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-04-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 13 - 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2026-05-04">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 119-635.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2026-05-04" calendar="Union" number="551">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 551.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2026-05-12T19:51:11-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1275 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5625, H.R. 6260, H.R. 8365, H. Con. Res. 96 and H.R. 8469. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5625, H.R. 6260, H.R. 8365, and H.Con.Res. 96 under a closed rule. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8469 under a structured rule. The resolution makes in order one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="1275" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2026-05-11T18:11:36Z" status="Reported to House">Monitor Accountability Act

This bill requires the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts to establish conditions on the appointment of monitors to oversee state and local governmental entities. A monitor is an independent official appointed to oversee corrective reforms as part of a civil settlement agreement or consent decree, such as to remedy a pattern or practice of unconstitutional policing.

Among the conditions, this bill requires notice and an opportunity for public comment prior to the appointment of a monitor, limits an individual to one monitor appointment at a time, sets a five-year term limit for monitors, and requires a public accounting of the fees charged and services provided by the monitor. It also caps fees and explicitly authorizes the use of pro bono services.

In 2021, the Department of Justice began implementing a set of principles and specific recommendations regarding the use of monitors in civil settlement agreements and consent decrees involving state and local governmental entities, including recommendations relating to term limits, capping fees, and public accountability.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-635</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
